<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mariosanchez.org/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power Morning Productivity Bubble</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/mornings</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/mornings</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that the latest fad among self-proclaimed productivity gurus is the concept of &amp;ldquo;power mornings&amp;rdquo;. Just Google &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webhp?hl=en#hl=en&amp;amp;q=morning+rituals&#34;&gt;morning rituals&lt;/a&gt; and you&amp;rsquo;ll see what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, if you don&amp;rsquo;t wake up at 4am, meditate, run a half marathon, speed-read three books, and write a chapter of your soon-to-be-published novel before your coffee is ready, you must be a slacker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But who are these people telling us what to do with our time, our sleep, our exercise and our food? Are they physicians or dietitians? No, they&amp;rsquo;re just personal
development &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo; who have found in the latest productivity fad a way to sell books, seminars and expensive coaching sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, enough of the one-size-fits-all power morning ritual. The bottom line is that &lt;mark&gt;everybody is different because our &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronobiology&#34;&gt;biological rhythms&lt;/a&gt; are different&lt;/mark&gt;. Forget what the &amp;ldquo;gurus&amp;rdquo; say and just do what works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What works for me? I need seven to eight hours of sleep, so waking up at 4am is a no-no. Upon waking up, usually at 6:30am or so, I perform a stretching and strengthening routine for my lower back, abdomen and hamstrings, followed by a healthy breakfast (sometimes blueberry yogurt with muesli, sometimes oatmeal with raisins
and apple, or a sprouted wheat toast with cheddar cheese and a boiled egg, all preceded by a small glass of orange/carrot juice and followed by a large cup of coffee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, do you have a morning ritual?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the topic, check out this &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@InVisionApp/what-s-your-morning-ritual-b3ff2fbcc8e5#.o9qgzlwb9&#34;&gt;Medium article&lt;/a&gt;, where several people share how they get their mornings started. It&amp;rsquo;s worth the 4 minute read (plus, the pictures
are great!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/5/4019/4658619672_819e8d7414_b.jpg&#34; class=&#34;roundcorners&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Doing Now</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/now</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/now</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is how I spend my time these days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I start my day with a 30-45 minute stretching routine followed by a healthy breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I go to work every day, where I develop power tools that make people work faster, easier and more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am constantly simplifying my life and my surroundings, with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/mini&#34;&gt;practical minimalism&lt;/a&gt; frame of mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I monitor and manage my investments, focusing on undervalued stocks and real estate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always &lt;a href=&#34;../reading/&#34;&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt; something. Currently, it&amp;rsquo;s:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008ENA74E/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1&#34;&gt;Why I Left Goldman Sachs&lt;/a&gt;, by Greg Smith.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m learning to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;static site generator&lt;/a&gt; that powers this site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m planning trips for the next few months. Possible destinations: Portland, Raleigh, Peru, Greece, Iceland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I keep in touch and spend time with my family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I rarely miss a game of my favorite soccer team, Argentine side River Plate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page was inspired by the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sivers.org/nowff&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Updated: November 11, 2015&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Best Tools</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/best-tools</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/best-tools</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up in Peru back in the 80&amp;rsquo;s I used to play tennis every weekend. I was never very good at it, but I loved to have the coolest rackets and shoes. Back then that meant either a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.80s-tennis.com/pages/maxply-fort_80-ad.html&#34;&gt;Dunlop Maxply&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;http://racquetmuseum.com/2014/01/23/wilson-jack-kramer-autograph/&#34;&gt;Wilson Jack Kramer&lt;/a&gt; racket, and a pair of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adidas_Stan_Smith&#34;&gt;Adidas Stan Smith&lt;/a&gt; tennis shoes. Needless to say, none of those tools made me be a better player. They were just status symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a right time for buying yourself great tools, but it is usually not when you are just a beginner or a dabbler. At the early stages of every endevour, focused and disciplined practice will get you further than using the latest gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than asking &amp;ldquo;what blogging platform should I use?&amp;rdquo; develop the habit of writing often and see if it is something you want to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than buying a Moleskin notebook to practice drawing mind maps, use any notebook for a while and see if it is something that helps you think more creatively or organize your thoughts better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of buying a Mac Book Pro to try your hand at some basic HTML or CSS, get an old laptop and see if it is something that you want to spend time learning first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve proven your commitment to an activity or craft, by all means get yourself the best tools: you deserve them now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage, the best tools will not only give you an edge but will motivate you to keep improving, and will help you view yourself as what you really are: a professional who takes pride in what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Building Blocks of Success</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/success/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of checklists, and some time ago I developed this list of what I believe are the building blocks of success. They are divided in five big buckets: &lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Self&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Credentials&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Memberships&lt;/strong&gt;. There could be others, but this is a good starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting into the habit of reviewing this list frequently and asking: what are you doing today to nurture and strengthen each of these building blocks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;people:aacdfef422bea8f6180e1d1e68804581&#34;&gt;People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Family&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friends&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Business Contacts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mentors&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heroes/Role Models&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advisors&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clients&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Service Providers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources:aacdfef422bea8f6180e1d1e68804581&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cash&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stocks/Bonds/Mutual Funds&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stock Options&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;401K/IRAs Retirement Accounts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Real Estate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vehicles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tablet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phone&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other Professional Equipment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lines of Credit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Credit Cards&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digital Assets (domain, website, profiles)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Corporations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Processes/Systems&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patents&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Royalties&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brands&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self:aacdfef422bea8f6180e1d1e68804581&#34;&gt;Self&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Values&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Skills&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Education&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Style/Image&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Habits&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Goals and Objectives&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personal Branding&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Management Style&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personality Profile&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;credentials:aacdfef422bea8f6180e1d1e68804581&#34;&gt;Credentials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degrees&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resume&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testimonials&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Letters of Recommendation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Portfolio&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Credit Score&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Business Licenses&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Passports&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Visas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Driver License&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;memberships:aacdfef422bea8f6180e1d1e68804581&#34;&gt;Memberships&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alumni Associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student Associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Political Affiliations&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Religious Organizations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Community Organizations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mastermind Groups&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professional Organizations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boards&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frequent Flyer Programs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clubs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Minimalism</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/mini</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/mini</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk about minimalism these days, and much confusion about what it means. While I&amp;rsquo;m far from being an authority on the subject (I consider myself a minimalist-in-training) I&amp;rsquo;m going to throw in my two cents and explain what minimalism means to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimalism doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we have to turn into some sort of Buddhist monk going through life with six or seven worldly possessions.  Getting rid of stuff is not the goal here, but rather the consequence of choosing to live in a more deliberate way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimalism starts by understanding that everything we surround ourselves with either adds value to our life or is just taking space. Things add value by being useful or by bringing us joy. Everything we let into our lives has to earn it&amp;rsquo;s place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good way to make minimalism a daily practice is to get into the habit of constantly asking ourselves this question: &amp;ldquo;What is this doing here?&amp;rdquo; If it&amp;rsquo;s not adding value or bringing us joy, get rid of it. Throw it away or give it to someone who may need it/like it/want it. Here&amp;rsquo;s the key, though: whatever we decide to do we must decide quickly, or the resistance (laziness, procrastination, the just-in-case syndrome) will take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep it up until this daily practice becomes a habit, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised by how eliminating physical clutter contributes to getting rid of mental clutter too. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that since I&amp;rsquo;m doing this I&amp;rsquo;m able to think more clearly, and have an easier time getting organized and getting things done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Smoking Room</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/smoking-room</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/smoking-room</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m finally back in Shanghai and about to enter my hotel room. I swipe my key card over the sensor, open the door, and immediately sense a strange smell. I walk in a few steps, take a deep breath and think: &amp;ldquo;somebody has been smoking in this room&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s just me&amp;rdquo;, I question myself, as I drop my suitcase and walk toward the opposite side of the room: &amp;ldquo;No&amp;hellip; still cigarette smell&amp;rdquo;, I think. Then I glance at the nightstand and, aha! the proof: an ashtray, and, neatly resting on its edges, a matchbox. They have given me a freaking smoking room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take the elevator downstairs. I spot the guy who checked me in (a tall and slim kid in his twenties, perhaps from South East Asia, but definitely not Chinese), walk toward him and throw my key card on the counter: &amp;ldquo;You gave me a smoking room!&amp;rdquo; I yell. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry sir&amp;rdquo;, he replies, typing furiously as he tries to find me another room, &amp;ldquo;I thought you asked for a smoking room&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;No, I didn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo;, I  answer back. &amp;ldquo;Sorry about that, sir&amp;rdquo; he politely apologizes, as he hands me my new key card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take the elevator, find my new room and open the door. I walk in, take a deep breath and: perfect! no cigarette smell. I close the door behind me and throw open the curtains to reveal a spectacular view of the nearby park and skyline. Seconds later, as I stand by the window taking in the view, I suddenly ask myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When did I turn into such an asshole?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the guy downstairs really did understand that I wanted a smoking room. After all, this is a hotel and employees have to deal with many different types of confusing accents. Or perhaps it was me who didn&amp;rsquo;t understand correctly. But, most importantly, this kid could have been me 25 years ago, new in a foreign country, trying my best to get ahead, having to deal with customers all day from behind a counter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when I decided to go back and apologize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take the elevator back down and stand in line, since the lobby is now packed with people waiting to check in. After a couple of minutes I hear a voice next to me: &amp;ldquo;is your new room OK, sir?&amp;rdquo;. The kid had spotted me standing in line and had come out to check on me. &amp;ldquo;The room? oh, yes, the room, the room is just great&amp;rdquo;, I tell him, still surprised to see him there. &amp;ldquo;Listen&amp;rdquo;, I keep telling him, &amp;ldquo;sorry that I yelled at you before, and thank you for being so diligent in taking care of the problem&amp;rdquo;. Then I shake his hand as he replies: &amp;ldquo;no problem, no problem, I&amp;rsquo;m glad everything turned out OK, sir&amp;rdquo;, before going back to his station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is said that as years go by we get more impatient. I wonder, though, if impatient is the right word, or if what we really become is more selfish and entitled. Could it be possible that years of accumulating possessions and fancy titles can make us forget where we come from, and turn us into insufferable jerks ready to go off when our wine is not at the right temperature, the food we just picked up for dinner messes up our new car smell or a young couple with active young children sits too close to us on a plane?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope not, but even in those cases when it seems it has, we can&amp;rsquo;t change the past just by wishing we had acted differently. What we can do, though, is to remember all those times when those we mistreated reacted with more grace and elegance than us and pay it forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>