<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 11:17:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mariosanchez.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Useful Habits for the Digital Age</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/7newhabits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 11:17:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/7newhabits/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Covey wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1THjXoz&#34;&gt;7 Habits Of Highly Effective People&lt;/a&gt; in 1989. Since then, many authors have expanded the conversation by adding their own seven habits for success, effectiveness, happiness or whatever end goal they may be pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next few paragraphs, I will distill the seven most important habits that, in my opinion, are esential to successfully navigate the waters of the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-know-what-you-want:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;1. Know What You Want&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds easy but, more often than not, people &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t know what they want&lt;/a&gt;. Passion or purpose is not something that hits us in the head while we&amp;rsquo;re sitting down waiting for it. &lt;strong&gt;We need to get out and find it&lt;/strong&gt;. The best way is to try many different things (go wide) until something sticks. It must be something that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind doing even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bring you money. Once you find it, you then need to focus (go deep), learn everything you can, and strive to &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1XHLESW&#34;&gt;become the best&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-be-different:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;2. Be Different&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to find your &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcompany.com/28905/brand-called-you&#34;&gt;personal brand&lt;/a&gt;. Merely being competent or very good is not enough. You need to be different. Find the quality or qualities that make you different than your peers and competitors. You can be the details guy, or the people-person gal, or the guy who is always trying out new things, but by all means find something that makes you stand out. &lt;strong&gt;Approach your craft from an angle that others can&amp;rsquo;t or won&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt;. Narrow your niche as much as you profitably can so that you can claim the top spot.  Seth Godin wrote about this more than a decade ago in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Vpd5ki&#34;&gt;Purple Cow&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, pick it up. It&amp;rsquo;s a short read and well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-spend-less-than-you-make:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;3. Spend Less Than You Make&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing will widen the gap between you and your dreams more than debt. Avoid it like the plague. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, really: &lt;strong&gt;spend less than you make&lt;/strong&gt;. This may seem hard in a society like ours, where we are bombarded every day with &amp;ldquo;buy now, pay later&amp;rdquo; marketing messages, but if you stick to it suddenly it will become a habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-save-a-lot-of-money:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;4. Save a Lot of Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Those who say that money is not important either have too much or don&amp;rsquo;t have any&lt;/strong&gt;. Money gives you flexibility and freedom. Accumulating a big chunk of cash means that you will never have to do &lt;a href=&#34;https://thebillfold.com/a-story-of-a-fuck-off-fund-648401263659#.bhrdyqcf7&#34;&gt;something you don&amp;rsquo;t want to&lt;/a&gt; because you need the money. The car broke down? Want to take that class? Want to go on that trip? Want to splurge on something really important to you? No problem, you&amp;rsquo;ve prepared for it. Just write a check. For more on this I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1TQ0BQt&#34;&gt;Ramit Sethi&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-learn-to-be-uncomfortable:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;5. Learn To Be Uncomfortable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be free you have to &lt;strong&gt;learn to live like a college student&lt;/strong&gt;. Get used to sleeping on couches, drinking tap water, catching the bus, taking cold showers, eating simple meals, using your local library, buying used stuff, etc. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to do all these things all the time, but knowing that you can do them and still be OK will give you an edge: when you know that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a lot to live well and that you can always go somewhere else, well&amp;hellip;&lt;strong&gt;you have the power&lt;/strong&gt;. For more on this I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1XHMBuE&#34;&gt;Mark Cuban&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt;, especially the chapters that describe how he started out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-lighten-your-load:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;6. Lighten Your Load&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being rich in the digital age means something completely different than twenty years ago. Back then, being rich meant owning things: the McMansion, the expensive car, the boat, the fancy jewelery, the corner office, etc. All that is bullshit now. These days &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re considered rich when you have time, freedom, mobility and cool experiences&lt;/strong&gt;. The sharing economy has given us access to practically anything without the burden of ownership. Forget the vacation home: book an Airbnb. Thinking of buying a car? Unless you live in a sprawling city with no public transportation you don&amp;rsquo;t need to: take the train, hail an Uber or ride a bike. Corner office? Please&amp;hellip; just work out of a coffee shop or your local library. Hold on to your money (see #4) and donate/throw away the things you don&amp;rsquo;t use that are weighing you down. The ultimate aim is to fit everything you own in a carry-on bag. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.becomingminimalist.com/millennials/&#34;&gt;Be flexible. Be mobile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-always-be-learning:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;7. Always Be Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think that you&amp;rsquo;re safe because you have a college degree, think again. &lt;strong&gt;Technology and the digital revolution are completely redefining professions&lt;/strong&gt; to the point that they would be unrecognizeable to somebody who has spent the last ten years in a desert island. If you have any doubts, just ask &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@knightfdn/10-basics-today-s-journalists-need-562df8787406#.bzsocpbmk&#34;&gt;journalists&lt;/a&gt;, marketers, customer service representatives, taxi drivers, and other professionals whose lives have been disrupted by technology and globalization. The good news is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/onlineed/&#34;&gt;learning new things online&lt;/a&gt; for free or very little money is now easier than ever. You just need to have drive and curiosity. For older folks, another piece of advice: surround yourself with young people. The future is no longer being shaped by politicians or captains of industry, but by laptop-toting, tech-savvy twenty-somethings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-summary:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know what you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend less than you make&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save a lot of money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to be uncomfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighten your load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always be learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7210/6812971608_30001b913a_h.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;small&#34;&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jodimichelle/6812971608/&#34;&gt;jodimichelle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juxtapose: JavaScript Before-and-After Visual Tool</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/juxtapose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 22:50:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/juxtapose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As content creators in the digital age, writers and journalists need to get familiar with data visualization tools. One of these tools is Juxtapose, created by &lt;a href=&#34;http://knightlab.northwestern.edu/&#34;&gt;Northwestern University Knight Lab&lt;/a&gt; using JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juxtapose lets you highlight the &lt;em&gt;before-and-after&lt;/em&gt; aspect of your stories using a visually compelling slider graphic (you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://juxtapose.knightlab.com/&#34;&gt;make one on the app&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt; and then just cut and embed a snippet of code on your site).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried it myself using two selfies I took during the last World Cup, wearing the jerseys of the two finalists (lame example, I know, but think of the possibilities if you&amp;rsquo;re covering a more serious subject!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;juxtapose&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.knightlab.com/libs/juxtapose/latest/embed/index.html?uid=b440cd8c-1a4a-11e6-a524-0e7075bba956&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to check out the Juxtapose source code it is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NUKnightLab/juxtapose&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: Here is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/06/07/amazing-photos-capture-1910-great-flood-of-paris-v-2016/&#34;&gt;great example of Juxtapose&lt;/a&gt; used in news media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Basic Git Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/gitflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 18:00:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/gitflow/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This quick rundown portrays the basic workflow I go through when using &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of files. It assumes you have some basic knowledge of Git. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are plenty of resources online (&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2&#34;&gt;this is a good starting point&lt;/a&gt;). It also assumes that you are using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; for your remote repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creating-a-repository-from-scratch:a603a77b1f5c5be5405a46ac8ca7dda3&#34;&gt;Creating a repository from scratch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open your Terminal and navigate to a folder you want to start tracking (if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use the Terminal this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-the-command-line&#34;&gt;quick online course&lt;/a&gt; will show you the basics).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type &lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt; to create a new subdirectory, called .git, where your file changes are going to be tracked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a new file, for example one called &lt;em&gt;grocery.txt&lt;/em&gt; (a simple text file listing different grocery stores in your neighborhood) by typing &lt;code&gt;touch grocery.txt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open your favorite text editor, add some grocery store names and save the file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the file to the staging area by doing &lt;code&gt;git add grocery.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commit your changes by doing &lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;ldquo;MESSAGE HERE&amp;rdquo;&lt;/code&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to type your message in between quote marks explaining what you did to the file.  Since this is the first time you commit this file it is OK to just write &amp;ldquo;initial commit&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to push your file to a remote repository, you need to create the remote repository first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Github and create a new project folder where you&amp;rsquo;re going to place and track &lt;em&gt;grocery.txt&lt;/em&gt;. You can call it &lt;em&gt;new-project&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look around the screen for the URL of the project folder you just created. It should be something like &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com/youraccount/new-project.git&#34;&gt;https://www.github.com/youraccount/new-project.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy that URL, go back to your terminal, and type &lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add remote origin &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com/youraccount/new-project.git&#34;&gt;https://www.github.com/youraccount/new-project.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push your file to the remote repository with &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt; (if at any point Github asks you for your username and password type them in).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you are tracking &lt;em&gt;grocery.txt&lt;/em&gt; both in your local repository (your computer) and a remote repository!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s say that the next day you come back to your file and add some more grocery store names. Once you&amp;rsquo;re done, do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save the file&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;code&gt;git add grocery.txt&lt;/code&gt; to add the changes to the staging area, and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;ldquo;add grocery stores&amp;rdquo;&lt;/code&gt; to commit your changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To upload these changes to the remote repository simply type &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt;. Type your username and password when prompted and the changes will be uploaded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloning-a-remote-repository:a603a77b1f5c5be5405a46ac8ca7dda3&#34;&gt;Cloning a remote repository&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloning a remote repository means installing a copy in your local computer. You may want to clone one of your existing remote repositories to do some work on it locally, or you may want to clone a remote repository belonging to somebody else and use it as a template for your own project. In this case, first make sure you have permission from the repository owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what you do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Github and follow the instructions to fork the repository to your profile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to call the repository something else, just rename it as you want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, clone the repository to your local computer by going back to the terminal and typing &lt;code&gt;git clone URL OF THE REPOSITORY&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve cloned the repository and done some work on it, the process is the same as when you update a local repository created from scratch: you work on your files, make some changes, add them to the staging area, commit them, and finally push them back to the remote repository with &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before You Sharpen That Axe</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 21:05:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people don&amp;rsquo;t fail because they don&amp;rsquo;t have enough money or plans, but because they don&amp;rsquo;t know what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what you want is hard, that&amp;rsquo;s why so few people engage in it. It is easier to just start doing things, like answering email or running errands: they keep us busy and give us the illusion of making progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding what we really want, though, is the first step before starting a project, launching a career or designing a life plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with this quote attributed to Abraham Lincoln: &amp;ldquo;give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening my axe&amp;rdquo;. It underscores the importance of preparation before execution. Figuring out what we want comes first, though, so &lt;mark&gt;before you sharpen that axe make sure that chopping down a tree is what you really want to do&lt;/mark&gt;. Perhaps what you really want is to plant a tree instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose first, preparation and execution second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the subject I recommend watching Simon Sinek&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action?language=en&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start With Why&amp;rdquo; Ted talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/tree.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/peter_from_wellington/15701759174/&#34;&gt;Peter Kurdulija&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Ubuntu in an Old Laptop</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 18:00:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the hard drive of my old Toshiba Satellite died suddenly I thought of getting rid of it, but when I learned that you could buy a refurbished hard drive on ebay for very little money (around $35) I ordered one and installed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clean, fresh hard drive with no OS gave me the perfect excuse to install a Linux operating system. I had heard good things about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, with its user-friendly interface and non of the clutter that comes with a traditional Windows installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From another computer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/download/desktop/create-a-usb-stick-on-windows&#34;&gt;create a Ubuntu bootable USB stick&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plug the Ubuntu USB stick in a USB port of the computer where you want to install it, and turn the computer on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;As soon as the first screen comes up press F12 (or Escape or F2 depending on the computer you&amp;rsquo;re using). You will be taken to a menu of options where you will need to change the booting order to boot from the USB drive first (&lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/5991848/how-to-boot-from-a-cd-or-usb-drive-on-any-pc&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; offers a pretty good explanation of how to do it, depending on the computer you&amp;rsquo;re using).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once Ubuntu comes up on the screen, it will give you the option to try it out from the USB port or to install it in your hard drive. You can choose either one. Since I wanted to install it in my clean, empty hard drive I chose the latter. There are other things you can do, like running Ubuntu alonside Windows, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried them. There are plenty of tutorials online explaining alternative installations, though, if you want to do something different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I activated the wifi connection by looking for it in the connections icon at the top right of the main window.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new Ubuntu installation works perfectly. It is fast and efficient, and the interface is intuitive enough that anybody can use it. Ubuntu also comes Firefox already installed, and with LibreOffice, an open source office suite compatible with Microsoft Office. That means you can open and edit files like Word documents, Excel spreadsheets and PowerPoint presentations and share them with other users quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am very happy that my old laptop got a new lease of life, and that installing (and using) the free and open source Ubuntu on it was easy and painless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/../images/ubuntu.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related: &lt;a href=&#34;http://evbogue.com/decentdevcomputer/&#34;&gt;How to Get a Decent Dev Computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology and the Future of Education</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/onlineed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 12:53:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/onlineed/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Following one of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/&#34;&gt;my themes for 2016&lt;/a&gt; I recently started learning Javascript. Rather than using a book I signed up to Treehouse, an online platform that specializes in teaching how to code.  After using the site for a few days I am now able to better understand how technology can help solve the problem of the skyrocketing cost of today&amp;rsquo;s higher education:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-scale:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;1. Scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economies of scale achieved through technology have dramatically reduced the cost of education delivery. While courses in bricks-and-mortar schools can cost thousands of dollars, you can take unlimited classes online for less than $50 a month. Think of the savings this represents over the four years of a typical college education. If colleges and universities are investing in real estate instead of technology they&amp;rsquo;re making a big mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-lesson-delivery:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;2. Lesson Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some people will always prefer face to face lessons, the advantages of video are hard to ignore. For one, cost: why pay somebody to deliver the same lesson over and over again, when you can just capture it on video, once?  Today&amp;rsquo;s educational videos are highly optimized pieces of content where everything, from the instructor&amp;rsquo;s tone of voice, to the words chosen to explain the concepts, to the infographics used as teaching aids, and even the backround decor, have been thoroughly tested to provide the most effective learning experience. A video can also reach millions, not just the number of students that fit in a typical classroom. You can also rewind a video at your leisure, watch it as many times as you want, when you want, wherever you may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-socialization-and-interaction:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;3. Socialization and Interaction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proponents of traditional education may argue that campus life enables students to interact, socialize and make connections.  The same, however, can be achieved through online education. While the interaction may not always be face to face, online tools like forums, social networks, and email let us be in contact with peers, ask questions, and give and get help. Students can also research their local scene for meetups where like-minded people can get together to discuss any topic, exchange ideas, and socialize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-pace-and-rewards:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;4. Pace and Rewards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online schools are pioneers of the &lt;em&gt;gamification&lt;/em&gt; of education. They break down subjects into bite-sized lessons and give out points when a student completes them. Successfully passing a course or track earns them a badge. These achievements are then listed in the student&amp;rsquo;s profile, for bragging rights and motivation. Online teaching platforms are succeeding in making education fun, by providing a learning environment that resonates with digital natives, used to instant gratification and fast feedback loops. Traditional institutions, on the other hand, mostly follow the rigid set of rythms, timelines and processes of the industrial age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-skills-versus-credentials:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;5. Skills versus Credentials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing a credential is one of the few considerations where traditional education may still come out ahead. I believe, however, that as the cost of traditional education gets higher and less people are willing to mortgage their lives in exchange for a diploma, more employers will have to adapt and get with the times. I also envision the talent pool getting bigger and competition stronger, which will devalue credentials in favor of skills and experience. Those who hone their skills working on intersting projects will be more valuable than those who just hide behind a piece of paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I may be overemphasizing the virtues of online education based on my recent (and limited) experience, it is undeniable that traditional education is being &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/news/briefing/21605899-staid-higher-education-business-about-experience-welcome-earthquake-digital&#34;&gt;disrupted&lt;/a&gt;, and that technology and the Internet will become the preferred media for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course&#34;&gt;education delivery in the future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiet</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/quiet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 21:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/quiet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/quiet.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an introvert myself this book really resonated with me. It talks about the current social obsession with extroversion and teamwork, especially in the business world, where being gregarious is seen as an almost indispensable precondition for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With conclusive research data, the author demonstrates that designing an environment that caters to the needs of introverts, by not over stimulating them with group activities, letting them work alone for extended periods of time, or giving them time to recharge, leads to better results, in business and in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial two thirds of the book explain how we arrived to the era of extroversion glorification. Several pages are dedicated to cover Tony Robbins over-the-top seminars and the culture within the Evangelical church. It also deals with the psycological research behind our different personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real meat of the book comes in Chapter 9, where we can find actionable advice. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn about &amp;ldquo;stretching&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Free Trait Agreements&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;restorative niches&amp;rdquo;, powerful techniques that introverts can use to thrive in today&amp;rsquo;s extrovert-driven world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the book I found out that the author had done a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/susan_cain_the_power_of_introverts?language=en&#34;&gt;TED talk&lt;/a&gt; on the subject. While not a substitute for the book it is worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes&#34;&gt;My Highlights and Notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our lives are shaped as profoundly by personality as by gender or race.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yet today we make room for a remarkably narrow range of personality styles. We&amp;rsquo;re told that to be great is to be bold, to be happy is to be sociable. We see ourselves as a nation of extroverts-which means that we&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of who we really are.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So many people pretend to be extroverts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some fool even themselves, until some life event-a layoff, an empty nest, an inheritance that frees them to spend time as they like-jolts them into taking stock of their true natures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introversion-along with its cousins sensitivity, seriousness, and shyness-is now a second-class personality trait.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We make a grave mistake to embrace the Extrovert Ideal so unthinkingly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neither E=mc2 nor Paradise Lost was dashed off by a party animal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Many of the most important institutions of contemporary life are designed for those who enjoy group projects and high levels of stimulation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The vast majority of teachers believe that the ideal student is an extrovert.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As adults, many of us work for organizations that insist we work in teams, in offices without walls, for supervisors who value &amp;ldquo;people skills&amp;rdquo; above all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re expected to promote ourselves unabashedly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re an introvert, you also know that the bias against quiet can cause deep psychic pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come &amp;ldquo;out of your shell&amp;rdquo;-that noxious expression&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now that you&amp;rsquo;re an adult, you might still feel a pang of guilt when you decline a dinner invitation in favor of a good book.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have seen firsthand &lt;mark&gt;how difficult it is for introverts to take stock of their own talents, and how powerful it is when finally they do&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts recharge their batteries by being alone; extroverts need to recharge when they don&amp;rsquo;t socialize enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no all-purpose definition of introversion or extroversion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts and extroverts differ in the level of outside stimulation that they need to function well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts, in contrast, may have strong social skills and enjoy parties and business meetings, but after a while wish they were home in their pajamas. They prefer to devote their social energies to close friends, colleagues, and family. They listen more than they talk, think before they speak, and often feel as if they express themselves better in writing than in conversation. They tend to dislike conflict. Many have a horror of small talk, but enjoy deep discussions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nor are introverts necessarily shy. &lt;mark&gt;Shyness is the fear of social disapproval or humiliation, while introversion is a preference for environments that are not overstimulating&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;America had shifted from what the influential cultural historian Warren Susman called a Culture of Character to a Culture of Personality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The social role demanded of all in the new Culture of Personality was that of a performer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Americans responded to these pressures by trying to become salesmen who could sell not only their company&amp;rsquo;s latest gizmo but also themselves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By 1920, popular self-help guides had changed their focus from inner virtue to outer charm-to know what to say and how to say it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The model employee of the midcentury-even one whose job rarely involved dealing with the public, like a research scientist in a corporate lab-was not a deep thinker but a hearty extrovert with a salesman&amp;rsquo;s personality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Early Americans revered action and were suspicious of intellect, associating the life of the mind with the languid, ineffectual European aristocracy they had left behind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The pressure to entertain, to sell ourselves, and never to be visibly anxious keeps ratcheting up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What if you love knowledge for its own sake, not necessarily as a blueprint to action?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A middle manager at GE once told me that &amp;ldquo;people here don&amp;rsquo;t even want to meet with you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a PowerPoint and a &amp;ldquo;pitch&amp;rdquo; for them&amp;rdquo;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone knows that it&amp;rsquo;s important to be an extrovert and troublesome to be an introvert. So people work real hard at looking like extroverts, whether that&amp;rsquo;s comfortable or not.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If we assume that quiet and loud people have roughly the same number of good (and bad) ideas, then we should worry if the louder and more forceful people always carry the day&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We perceive talkers as smarter than quiet types-even though grade-point averages and SAT and intelligence test scores reveal this perception to be inaccurate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We put too much of a premium on presenting and not enough on substance and critical thinking.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Contrary to the Harvard Business School model of vocal leadership, the ranks of effective CEOs turn out to be filled with introverts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Brigham Young University management professor Bradley Agle studied the CEOs of 128 major companies and found that those considered charismatic by their top executives had bigger salaries but not better corporate performance.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Many of the best-performing companies of the late twentieth century were run by what he calls &amp;ldquo;Level 5 Leaders.&amp;rdquo; These exceptional CEOs were known not for their flash or charisma but for extreme humility coupled with intense professional will.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social media has made new forms of leadership possible for scores of people who don&amp;rsquo;t fit the Harvard Business School mold.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps social media affords us the control we lack in real life socializing: the screen as a barrier between us and the world. The same person who would never raise his hand in a lecture hall of two hundred people might blog to two thousand, or two million, without thinking twice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Introverts prefer to work independently, and solitude can be a catalyst to innovation&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are born and culturally endowed with certain personality traits-introversion, for example-but we can and do act out of character in the service of &amp;ldquo;core personal projects.&amp;rdquo; In other words, introverts are capable of acting like extroverts for the sake of work they consider important, people they love, or anything they value highly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we act out of character by convincing ourselves that our pseudo-self is real, we can eventually burn out without even knowing why.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Behavioral leakage, in which our true selves seep out via unconscious body language.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not always so easy, it turns out, to identify your core personal projects. And it can be especially tough for introverts, who have spent so much of their lives conforming to extroverted norms that by the time they choose a career, or a calling, it feels perfectly normal to ignore their own preferences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are three key steps to identifying your own core personal projects:
* First, think back to what you loved to do when you were a child.
* Second, pay attention to the work you gravitate to.
* Finally, pay attention to what you envy. &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But even if you&amp;rsquo;re stretching yourself in the service of a core personal project, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to act out of character too much, or for too long.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Create as many &lt;mark&gt;&amp;ldquo;restorative niches&amp;rdquo;&lt;/mark&gt; as possible in your daily life. &amp;ldquo;Restorative niche&amp;rdquo; is Professor Little&amp;rsquo;s term for the place you go when you want to return to your true self. It can be a physical place, like the path beside the Richelieu River, or a temporal one, like the quiet breaks you plan between sales calls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Will this job allow me to spend time on in-character activities?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Acting in character most of the time, effectively turns workdays into one giant restorative niche.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Free Trait Agreement acknowledges that we&amp;rsquo;ll each act out of character some of the time-in exchange for being ourselves the rest of the time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The person with whom you can best strike a Free Trait Agreement-after overcoming his or her resistance-is yourself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Double pneumonia and an overscheduled life can happen to anyone, of course, but for Little, it was the result of &lt;mark&gt;acting out of character for too long and without enough restorative niches&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prolonged acting out of character may also increase autonomic nervous system activity, which can, in turn, compromise immune functioning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It can be hard for extroverts to understand how badly introverts need to recharge at the end of a busy day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In sales there&amp;rsquo;s a truism that &amp;ldquo;we have two ears and one mouth&amp;rdquo; and we should use them proportionately.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What makes someone really good at selling or consulting-the number-one thing is they&amp;rsquo;ve got to really listen well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about socializing with everyone. Think quality over quantity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Solve problems, make art, think deeply.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Spend your free time the way you like, not the way you think you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Remember the dangers of the New Groupthink. If it&amp;rsquo;s creativity you&amp;rsquo;re after, ask your employees to solve problems alone before sharing their ideas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t mistake assertiveness or eloquence for good ideas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do We Work?</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/whywork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 16:48:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/whywork/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/whywork.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.swarthmore.edu/SocSci/bschwar1/&#34;&gt;Barry Schwartz&lt;/a&gt; questions the idea that people only work for pay and urges us to design work organizations that give people discretion and autonomy, and the chance to do meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can save yourself reading through pages and pages of empirical evidence and research notes, and go straight to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_the_way_we_think_about_work_is_broken?language=en&#34;&gt;author&amp;rsquo;s TED talk&lt;/a&gt; on the subject if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes&#34;&gt;My highlights and notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Satisfied people do their work because they feel that they are in charge. Their workday offers them a measure of &lt;em&gt;autonomy and discretion&lt;/em&gt;. And they use that autonomy and discretion to achieve a level of mastery or expertise. They learn new things, developing both as workers and as people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gallup found that only 13 percent of workers feel engaged by their jobs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;The four characteristics of good work: challenge, engagement, meaning, and satisfaction. To this I would add &lt;strong&gt;autonomy and discretion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Job crafting is what Wrzesniewski and her colleagues called when we shape our jobs with the central purpose of our employer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To be satisfied with our work, we typically need a belief in the purpose of what we do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is people who see their work as a &amp;ldquo;calling&amp;rdquo; who find it most satisfying.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work &amp;lt; Career &amp;lt; Calling&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Take discretion, engagement, and meaning out of work and people feel less &amp;ldquo;called&amp;rdquo; to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Virtually any job has the potential to offer people satisfaction. It can be made meaningful by connecting them to the welfare of others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Factors that effective organizations have in common&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employment security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-managed teams and decentralized decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They pay more than the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They provide extensive training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t overmeasure employee performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They put great emphasis on the company mission.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In short, you take discretion, engagement, and meaning out of work and people get less satisfaction from doing it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When people are in states of positive emotion, they think expansively and creatively.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Carrots and sticks. What is striking is that, in the analysis that Pfeffer offers, both of these tools have negative effects on employee engagement and work satisfaction.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you create an environment in which workers are respected, they want to be there and they want to work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Carefully crafted incentive schemes, designed to ensure top performance, can often produce the opposite result.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social motives and financial ones compete. No incentives can ever be smart enough to substitute for people who do the right thing because it&amp;rsquo;s the right thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When we lose confidence that people have the will to do the right thing, and we turn to incentives, we find that we get what we pay for.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;watch where they walk, then pave it&amp;rdquo; metaphor argues that the empirical data shape the theories people develop. The &amp;ldquo;if you build it, they will come&amp;rdquo; metaphor argues that theories shape data. [The author] defends the second metaphor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work over which people exercise some discretion and control leads to cognitive flexibility and to an engaged orientation to self and society; in contrast, excessively monitored, oppressively supervised working conditions lead to distress.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People don&amp;rsquo;t think of themselves as primarily motivated by material incentives, but &lt;mark&gt;they think that pretty much everyone else is&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;French emperor Napoleon termed ideologues were so in love with ideas that they ignored empirical evidence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Better data and theories drive out worse ones, and progress is made. Why does this not happen in the case of theories about human nature?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Theories about human nature can actually produce changes in how people behave&lt;/mark&gt;. A theory that is false can become true simply by people believing it&amp;rsquo;s true.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Performance-oriented&lt;/strong&gt; vs. &lt;strong&gt;Mastery-oriented&lt;/strong&gt;: Performance-oriented people want to &lt;em&gt;prove&lt;/em&gt; their ability while mastery-oriented people want to &lt;em&gt;improve&lt;/em&gt; their ability.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So is intelligence fixed? Partly, that depends on whether you believe it&amp;rsquo;s fixed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unless there is a collective effort to combat this ideology, we will all become the lazy, selfish pursuers of self-interest, not just in work but in our lives as a whole, that at least some social scientists have assumed we always were. So the question becomes: What can we do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If we design workplaces that permit people to do work they value, we will be designing a human nature that values work&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The first step to taking responsibility over the structure of our workplace is to start asking questions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are the results of our transactions with customers positive sum, so that both sides leave the transaction better off?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We can demand of ourselves the effort to find the ways in which other people benefit if we do our jobs with enthusiasm rather than indifference.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Industrialization has been a spectacular human achievement. But as it has relieved material poverty, it has done so at the price of poverty of spirit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 3 Words for 2016</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, Chris Brogan started a yearly tradition: choosing the three words that would guide his actions for the next twelve months, and publishing them on his blog (you can read more about it on &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbrogan.com/3-words-2016/&#34;&gt;Chris&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this exercise to be extremely powerful, as it forces us to sit down and think long and hard about our priorities in life and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now sharing my Three Words for 2016: LEARN, EXPERIMENTS, SELF-AWARENESS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Learn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will focus on expanding my competence in new areas of knowledge. It is all too easy to just focus on the day-to-day tasks you&amp;rsquo;ve been performing for years, get complacent and stop learning. That&amp;rsquo;s how you become obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dedicating 2015 to learn the basics of web development and being finally able to deploy a website from scratch, helped me understand how much I missed learning new things and the feeling of accomplishment that comes with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 I will double down on learning. A few things I want to learn: to operate a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_server&#34;&gt;VPS&lt;/a&gt;, improve my Portuguese, and get better at fixing things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experiments:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to gravitate towards the same things over and over again: the same restaurants, the same kind of books, the same passtimes. I like predictablilty and reliability, which probably means that I&amp;rsquo;ve missed out on many good things for not experimenting enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 I will focus on trying new things in the spirit of continuous self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing Tim Ferriss, if you want opportunities to come to you, you must first throw a lot of things against the wall (experiment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guiding word also dovetails nicely with the first one (Learn) as they share many common themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-awareness:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Self-Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage it is crystal clear to me that as important as deciding what to do (or even more important) is to decide what &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By developing my career mostly in large corporations I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my working years living up to other people&amp;rsquo;s expectations: there is always a boss to please, employees to manage, politics to play. A few times I have also been required to play roles that were not in alignment with my core strengths and personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 and beyond I&amp;rsquo;m going to do less of what other people expect of me, and more of the things that allow me to leverage my strengths and get me closer to my overarching life goals. I&amp;rsquo;m going to &amp;ldquo;trust my gut&amp;rdquo;: if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right, I won&amp;rsquo;t do it. No more painting by (other people&amp;rsquo;s) numbers. Life is too short.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ayw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:38:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ayw/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/ayw.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A powerful little book offering valuable uncommon sense advice on how to approach business in alignment with your values and beliefs. In about an hour reading time, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sivers.org&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt; candidly tells us everything he learned from founding, operating and selling CD Baby, the business he stumbled upon when he decided to help fellow musicians sell their work on the Internet in the pre-Paypal, pre-iTunes days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes:395f262b5b83024ba8634078e0030eba&#34;&gt;My Highlights and Notes:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to know your personal philosophy of what makes you happy and what&amp;rsquo;s worth doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business is not about money. It&amp;rsquo;s about making dreams come true for others and for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Success comes from persistently improving and inventing, not from persistently promoting what&amp;rsquo;s not working.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your business plan is moot. You don&amp;rsquo;t know what people really want until you start doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need money to start helping people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make yourself unnecessary to the running of your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real point of doing anything is to be happy, so do only what makes you happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t trying to make a big business. I was just daydreaming about how one little thing would look in a perfect world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you make a business, you get to make a little universe where you control all the laws. This is your utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A business plan should never take more than a few hours of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best plans start simple. A quick glance and common sense should tell you if the numbers will work. The rest are details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revolution&lt;/em&gt; is a term that people use only when you&amp;rsquo;re successful. Before that, you&amp;rsquo;re just a quirky person who does things differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Present each new idea or improvement to the world. If multiple people are saying, &amp;ldquo;Wow! Yes! I need this! I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to pay you to do this!&amp;rdquo; then you should probably do it. But if the response is anything less, don&amp;rsquo;t pursue it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not saying &amp;ldquo;HELL YEAH!&amp;rdquo; about something, say &amp;ldquo;no.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to most things, you leave room in your life to throw yourself completely into that rare thing that makes you say &amp;ldquo;HELL YEAH!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time you think you know what your new business will be doing, remember this quote from Steve Blank: No plan survives first contact with customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By not having any money to waste, you never waste money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely everything you do is for your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make every decision-even decisions about whether to expand the business, raise money, or promote someone-according to what&amp;rsquo;s best for your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of your customers will ask you to turn your attention to expanding. They want you to keep your attention focused on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to grow your business is to focus entirely on your existing customers. Just thrill them, and they&amp;rsquo;ll tell everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an idea to get big big big, it has to be useful. And being useful doesn&amp;rsquo;t need funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be useful, you can always start now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting small puts 100 percent of your energy on actually solving real problems for real people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas are worth nothing unless they are executed. They are just a multiplier. Execution is worth millions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never forget that there are thousands of businesses, like Jim&amp;rsquo;s Fish Bait Shop in a shack on a beach somewhere, that are doing just fine without corporate formalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do land the big client, that organization will practically own you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By trying so hard to please the big client, you will lose touch with what the rest of the world wants. Instead, imagine that you have designed your business to have NO big clients, just lots of little clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you build your business on serving thousands of customers, not dozens, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about any one customer leaving or making special demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to confidently exclude people, and proudly say what you&amp;rsquo;re not. By doing so, you will win the hearts of the people you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a big world. You can loudly leave out 99 percent of it.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have the confidence to know that when your target 1 percent hears you excluding the other 99 percent, the people in that 1 percent will come to you because you&amp;rsquo;ve shown how much you value them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No business goes as planned, so make ten radically different plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t think you need a huge vision. Just stay focused on helping people today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never forget why you&amp;rsquo;re really doing what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. Are you helping people? Are they happy? Are you happy? Are you profitable? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all grade ourselves by different measures: For me, it&amp;rsquo;s how many useful things I create, whether songs, companies, articles, websites, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A business is started to solve a problem. But if the problem was truly solved, that business would no longer be needed! So the business accidentally or unconsciously keeps the problem around so that they can keep solving it for a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any business that&amp;rsquo;s in business to sell you a cure is motivated not to focus on prevention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Care about your customers more than about yourself, and you&amp;rsquo;ll do well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you set up your business like you don&amp;rsquo;t need the money, people are happier to pay you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;When someone&amp;rsquo;s doing something for the money, people can sense it, like a desperate lover. It&amp;rsquo;s a turnoff.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t prevent bad things from happening. Learn to shrug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s often the tiny details that really thrill people enough to make them tell all their friends about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find even the smallest way to make people smile, they&amp;rsquo;ll remember you more for that smile than for all your other fancy business-model stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to tell what someone&amp;rsquo;s going to be like on the job until he&amp;rsquo;s actually on the job for a few weeks. So I&amp;rsquo;d hire lightly and fire lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t try to impress an invisible jury of MBA professors. It&amp;rsquo;s OK to be casual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a benefit to being naive about the norms of the world: deciding from scratch what seems like the right thing to do, instead of just doing what others do.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what business you&amp;rsquo;re in, it&amp;rsquo;s good to prepare for what would happen if business doubled. &amp;ldquo;More of the same&amp;rdquo; is never the answer. You&amp;rsquo;d have to do things in a new way to handle twice as much business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about being, not having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole point of doing anything is because it makes you happy! That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never again promised a customer that I could do something that was beyond my full control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got myself into the delegation mindset. I had to make myself unnecessary to the running of my company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a big difference between being self-employed and being a business owner. Being self-employed feels like freedom until you realize that if you take time off, your business crumbles. To be a true business owner, make sure you
could leave for a year, and when you came back, your business would be doing better than when you left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make your role anything you want it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Anything you hate to do, someone else loves. So find that person and let him do it. &lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge growth means lots of meetings, investors, bankers, media, and answering to others. It&amp;rsquo;s quite far from the real core of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t every business want to be as big as possible? No. Make sure you know what makes you happy, and don&amp;rsquo;t forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust, but verify. Remember it when delegating. You have to do both. &lt;mark&gt;Delegate, but don&amp;rsquo;t abdicate&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s such a thing as over-delegation. I had empowered my employees so much that I gave them all the power. After a complete communication breakdown, it was eight-five people (my employees) against one (me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned an important word: abdicate. To abdicate means to surrender or relinquish power or responsibility; this word is usually used when a king abdicates the throne or crown. Lesson learned too late: Delegate, but don&amp;rsquo;t abdicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that the bigger learning and growing challenge for me was letting go, not staying on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I let two companies bid, and ended up choosing the one that bid the lowest but understood my clients better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The less I own, the happier I am. The lack of stuff gives me the priceless freedom to live anywhere anytime. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m altruistic. I&amp;rsquo;m sacrificing nothing. I&amp;rsquo;ve just learned what makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You make your perfect world. Business is as creative as the fine arts. You can be as unconventional, unique, and quirky as you want. A business is a reflection of the creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter which goal you choose, there will be lots of people telling you you&amp;rsquo;re wrong. Just pay close attention to what excites you and what drains you. Pay close attention to when you&amp;rsquo;re being the real you and when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to
impress an invisible jury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it makes you happy, that&amp;rsquo;s OK. It&amp;rsquo;s your choice to remain small.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My $100 Office</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/100office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 10:34:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/100office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed a quiet space at home where I could sit down and tweak the code of my site, and otherwise tinker with some web development tools I want to learn. Since my second bedroom had some empty space and a window with a nice view of the garden, it was the perfect place to try to fit a small workstation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of money but I still wanted my new writing setup to look good, so my logical first stop was Ikea&amp;rsquo;s website. I found a $35 desk and a $15 chair that I liked and perfectly fit the space available, so I drove to the nearest store and picked them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to give the space some character, so I selected twelve pictures I had taken on my &lt;a href=&#34;../photos/&#34;&gt;trips&lt;/a&gt; and ordered 8x10 prints (I got them for less than $20 in Snapfish).  I also got some cheap but stylish frames from Walmart ($11 for a set of six, so $22 total).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I added a recycled lamp I got for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I installed everything and this is how it now looks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/images/workstation.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am extremely happy with this new setup. I now have a place to write and code comfortably, that looks good and cost me less than $100.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Create a Minimal Hugo Site</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/minimalhugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/minimalhugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;These are the instructions to create a minimal, functional Hugo site. For more information read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/introduction/&#34;&gt;Hugo Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;download-hugo&#34;&gt;Download Hugo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download Hugo for many different platforms from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;copy-hugo-exe-on-a-working-folder&#34;&gt;Copy hugo.exe on a working folder&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a folder (you can name it /projects/) under your root, and then navigate to that folder by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd projects&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-a-new-hugo-site-in-a-subfolder-of-projects-called-projecthugo&#34;&gt;Create a new Hugo site in a subfolder of /projects called /projecthugo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site ~/projects/projecthugo/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;go-to-your-hugo-site-folder&#34;&gt;Go to your Hugo site folder&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd projecthugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;list-the-contents-of-the-projecthugo-folder&#34;&gt;List the contents of the /projecthugo folder&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should now see a skeleton with the basic structure of a Hugo site but no content or any of the folders or files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;archetypes  config.toml content layouts static data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;install-hugo-in-your-path&#34;&gt;Install Hugo in your path.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy the hugo.exe into your /projecthugo folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;again and you should now see the hugo executable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;archetypes  config.toml content layouts static data hugo.exe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-some-posts&#34;&gt;Create some posts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new post/post1.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open post1.md with your favorite text editor and you will see three fields already pre-written in the top section of the file, called &amp;ldquo;front matter&amp;rdquo; (between the +++ marks). By default, Hugo includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add more parameters later (like Categories or Tags).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo will match the title of your post with your post file name, so if you want to call it something different just replace the text between quotes in the Title field in the front matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can write some content below the second +++ line (leave one or two lines blank at the beginning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want your post to go live remember to change &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;draft = true&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;draft = false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you keep it as draft your post will not show on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create another post called post2.md following a similar process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;create-a-couple-of-pages-that-are-not-posts&#34;&gt;Create a couple of pages that are not posts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These would be pages like &lt;strong&gt;about&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;contact&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new about.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new contact.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open your favorite text editor and create some content for about.md and contact.md&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-default-templates&#34;&gt;Create _default templates&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will create four templates and place them in a folder called /layouts/_default:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;single.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;summary.html&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;li.html&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Single is for your individual content (e.g. posts or pages)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;List is for a list of posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Summary and li are views that will be used in your list template, depending if you just want a list of posts titles or a summary of each post in addition to the title.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hugo documentation provides instructions on what code to use in each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create section specific templates if your site is larger but for now _default templates are all we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-partial-templates&#34;&gt;Create partial templates&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are good for the common areas of your site. Go ahead and create:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;header.html (must include a link to the style sheet and the site&amp;rsquo;s navigation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;footer.html (for copyright or similar info)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place these templates in a folder called /layouts/partials/. These partial templates can be called from any other template (for example from single.hmtl or list.html) by simply using the following code within those templates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ partial &#34;header.html&#34; . }}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ partial &#34;footer.html&#34; . }}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-an-index-html-template&#34;&gt;Create an index.html template&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This template is only used for the home page. Create it however you want your home page to look and place it in the root of the /layouts folder.  You can also choose to use a list of posts as your index page. In that case just save the list template as index.html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-a-static-css-folder-and-upload-a-style-sheet&#34;&gt;Create a /static/css folder and upload a style sheet.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to link to the style sheet from the header.html partial template:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34; href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/css/style.css&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to include the above code between &amp;lt;&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-a-static-images-folder-and-upload-some-images&#34;&gt;Create a /static/images folder and upload some images.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self explanatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;update-your-config-toml-file&#34;&gt;Update your config.toml file&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just add the URL of your site and your site&amp;rsquo;s description. That&amp;rsquo;s all you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to start. You can add more parameters later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;try-out-your-site&#34;&gt;Try out your site&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have created content and templates it&amp;rsquo;s time to view your site. Type the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server -w&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything went well Hugo will generate your website and you will be able to see it at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34;&gt;http://localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;get-your-site-ready-to-upload&#34;&gt;Get your site ready to upload&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied with the way your site looks, run the hugo command by itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to upload or git push your site to your web hosting service. Your site files will be in a folder called /public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to start from scratch, I have created a Minimal Hugo Site and git pushed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mariobox/MinimalHugoSite&#34;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; to Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can simply clone the repository by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/mariobox/MinimalHugoSite.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Good They Can&#39;t Ignore You</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/sgtci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/sgtci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/sgtci.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The career advice I wish I had received when I was 18 years old. This book exposes the &amp;ldquo;follow your passion&amp;rdquo; myth and argues that the best way to be successful and happy at work is to become extremely good at what we do. Read it before embarking on any significant career change or if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to get more satisfaction out of your current job or career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are my notes and highlights from the book:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do some people end up loving what they do, while so many others fail at this goal? My question was clear: How do people end up loving what they do? And I needed an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conventional wisdom on career successfollow your passionis seriously flawed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be good at something before you can expect a good job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dont follow your passion; rather, let it follow you in your quest to become, in the words of my favorite Steve Martin quote, so good that they cant ignore you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus away from finding the right work and toward working right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes time to get good at anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key thing is to force yourself through the work, force the skills to come; thats the hardest phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compelling careers often have complex origins that reject the simple idea that all you have to do is follow your passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many complex reasons for workplace satisfaction, but the reductive notion of matching your job to a pre-existing passion is not among them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less than 4% percent of the total identified passions had any relation to work or education, with the remaining  percent describing hobby-style interests such as sports and art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a distinction between a job, a career, and a calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more experience [one has], the more likely [one is] to love his/her work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The happiest, most passionate employees are not those who followed their passion into a position, but instead those who have been around long enough to become good at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passion Is a Side Effect of Mastery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three traits of a great job or career: Autonomy, Competence, Relatedness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autonomy: the feeling that you have control over your day, and that your actions are important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competence: the feeling that you are good at what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relatedness: the feeling of connection to other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telling someone to follow their passion is not just an act of innocent optimism, but potentially the foundation for a career riddled with confusion and angst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The craftsman mindset, a focus on what value youre producing in your job, and the passion mindset, a focus on what value your job offers you [are opposites]. The craftsman mindset is the foundation for creating work you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Eventually] you are so experienced [that] theres a confidence that comes out, Steve Martin explained. I think its something the audience smells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An obsessive focus on the quality of what you produce is the rule in professional music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The craftsman mindset is crucial for building a career you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when you focus only on what your work offers you, it makes you hyperaware of what you dont like about it, leading to chronic unhappiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deep questions driving the passion mindsetWho am I? and What do I truly love?are essentially impossible to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two different ways people think about their working life. The first is the craftsman mindset, which focuses on what you can offer the world. The second is the passion mindset, which instead focuses on what the world can offer you. The craftsman mindset offers clarity, while the passion mindset offers a swamp of ambiguous and unanswerable questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shouldnt just envy the craftsman mindset, you should emulate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how you feel about your job right now, adopting the craftsman mindset will be the foundation on which youll build a compelling career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopt the craftsman mindset first and then the passion follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic economic theory tells us that if you want something thats both rare and valuable, you need something rare and valuable to offer in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It follows that if you want a great job, you need something of great value to offer in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three traits of great carrers: creativity, impact, and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the rare and valuable skills you can offer as your career capital. The craftsman mindset, with its relentless focus on becoming so good they cant ignore you, is a strategy well suited for acquiring career capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downside of the passion mindset is that it strips away merit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great work doesnt just require great courage, but also skills of great (and real) value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DISQUALIFIERS FOR APPLYING THE CRAFTSMAN MINDSET The job presents few opportunities to distinguish yourself by developing relevant skills that are rare and valuable. The job focuses on something you think is useless or perhaps even actively bad for the world. The job forces you to work with people you really dislike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carefully and persistently gather career capital. Valuable skills will translate into valuable opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on difficult activities, carefully chosen to stretch your abilities where they most need stretching and that provide immediate feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deliberate practice is activity designed, typically by a teacher, for the sole purpose of effectively improving specific aspects of an individuals performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to understand the source of professional athletes talent, for example, look to their practice schedules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When experts exhibit their superior performance in public their behavior looks so effortless and natural that we are tempted to attribute it to special talents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can figure out how to integrate deliberate practice into your own life, you have the possibility of blowing past your peers in your value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning is not done in isolation: You need to be constantly soliciting feedback from colleagues and professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of these markets: winner-take-all and auction. Step 1: Decide What Capital Market Youre In. Step 2: Identify Your Capital Type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seek open gatesopportunities to build capital that are already open to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about skill acquisition like a freight train: Getting it started requires a huge application of effort, but changing its track once its moving is easy. In other words, its hard to start from scratch in a new field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3: Define good. Deliberate practice requires good goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 4: Stretch and Destroy. Doing things we know how to do well is enjoyable, and thats exactly the opposite of what deliberate practice demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deliberate practice is often the opposite of enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term stretch describes what deliberate practice feels like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If youre not uncomfortable, then youre probably stuck at an acceptable level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embracing honest feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 5: Be Patient. Deliberate practice, an approach to work where you deliberately stretch your abilities beyond where youre comfortable and then receive ruthless feedback on your performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Control over what you do, and how you do it, is one of the most powerful traits you can acquire when creating work you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;theory on how people end up loving what they do. I argued in Rule #1 that follow your passion is bad advice, as the vast majority of people dont have pre-existing passions waiting to be discovered and matched to a job. In Rule #2, I then countered that people with compelling careers instead start by getting good at something rare and valuablebuilding what I called career capitaland then cashing in this capital for the traits that make great work great. In this understanding, finding the right work pales in importance to working right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving people more control over what they do and how they do it increases their happiness, engagement, and sense of fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to love what you do, your first step is to acquire career capital. Your next step is to invest this capital in the traits that define great work. Control is one of the most important targets you can choose for this investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Control thats acquired without career capital is not sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enthusiasm alone is not rare and valuable and is therefore not worth much in terms of career capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have enough career capital to acquire more control in your working life, you have become valuable enough to your employer that they will fight your efforts to gain more autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When no one cares what you do with your working life, you probably dont have enough career capital to do anything interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key, it seems, is to know when the time is right to become courageous in your career decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should only pursue a bid for more control if you have evidence that its something that people are willing to pay you for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what people are willing to pay for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to decisions affecting your core career, money remains an effective judge of value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When deciding whether to follow an appealing pursuit that will introduce more control into your work life, seek evidence of whether people are willing to pay for it. If you find this evidence, continue. If not, move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A unifying mission to your working life can be a source of great satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have a mission is to have a unifying focus for your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Missions are powerful because they focus your energy toward a useful goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systematically experiment with different proto-missions to seek out a direction worth pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mission chosen before you have relevant career capital is not likely to be sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next big ideas in any field are found right beyond the current cutting edge, in the adjacent space that contains the possible new combinations of existing ideas.&lt;br /&gt;
We like to think of innovation as striking us in a stunning eureka moment, where you all at once change the way people see the world, leaping far ahead of our current understanding. Im arguing that in reality, innovation is more systematic. We grind away to expand the cutting edge, opening up new problems in the adjacent possible to tackle and therefore expand the cutting edge some more, opening up more new problems, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good career mission is similar to a scientific breakthroughits an innovation waiting to be discovered in the adjacent possible of your field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to identify a mission for your working life, therefore, you must first get to the cutting edgethe only place where these missions become visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First master a promising nichea task that may take yearsand only then turning her attention to seeking a mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people who love their work got where they are by first building up career capital and then cashing it in for the types of traits that define great work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a mission, you need to first acquire capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advancing to the cutting edge in a field is an act of small thinking, requiring you to focus on a narrow collection of subjects for a potentially long time. Once you get to the cutting edge, however, and discover a mission in the adjacent possible, you must go after it with zeal: a big action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great missions are transformed into great successes as the result of using small and achievable projectslittle betsto explore the concrete possibilities surrounding a compelling idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you dont have a trusted strategy for making this leap from idea to execution, then like me and so many others, youll probably avoid the leap altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than believing they have to start with a big idea or plan out a whole project in advance, [successful people] make a methodical series of little bets about what might be a good direction, learning critical information from lots of little failures and from small but significant wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great missions are transformed into great successes as the result of finding projects that satisfy the law of remarkability, which requires that an idea inspires people to remark about it, and is launched in a venue where such remarking is made easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a mission-driven project to succeed, it should be remarkable in two different ways. First, it must compel people who encounter it to remark about it to others. Second, it must be launched in a venue that supports such remarking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other People&#39;s Money</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/opm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/opm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/opm.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent journalistic work about the biggest real estate deal ever made. If follows the saga of Stuyvesant Town, the largest residential project in New York City, from it&amp;rsquo;s humble beginnings as a middle class bastion in the late 1940s, to object of desire of financiers and speculators in the cusp of the real estate bubble of the early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goes deep into the details of the deal itself and the personalities and egoes of the people involved. You will find this book thoroughly enjoyable if you are into real estate investing or politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 6S Discipline</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/6s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/6s/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, the company moved us to a new office. When we walked into our shiny, new cubicles we found a single sheet of paper laid out on top of our recently installed, empty desks describing something called &amp;ldquo;The 6S Discipline&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a concise list of 6 bullet points that summarized a process to keep our work stations clean and organized. I later found out that the 6S concept comes from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_manufacturing&#34;&gt;Lean Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt; philosophy, the principles of which can also be applied to an office setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I have always liked to keep my workplace neatly organized and keep around only the things I need at one particular moment, the 6S concept strongly resonated with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about the 6S philosophy, you can read this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vitalentusa.com/learn/An_Introduction_to_6S.pdf&#34;&gt;comprehensive 6S overview&lt;/a&gt; I found searching online. On the other hand, if you just want to grasp the gist of it, here are the 6S principles in short form, just like in the page I found on my desk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sort:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Sort&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sort out necessary and unnecessary items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep only items necessary to perform the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove and discard the items not required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-in-order:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Set In Order&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organize the essential materials in the workplace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find &amp;ldquo;a place for everything and keep everything in its place&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shine:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Shine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep the area clean at all times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;standardize:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Standardize&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain the Sort, Set In Order, and Shine Steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sustain:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Sustain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain the gain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for ways to continuously improve your work area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;safety-first:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Safety First&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an accident-free workplace. Eliminate hazards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, 6S is about &lt;mark&gt;eliminating waste and maximizing value-adding activities&lt;/mark&gt;, by creating and maintaining an organized, clean, safe and efficient work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/4/3548/3389551970_a24a14b9ba_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/cocokelley/3389551970&#34;&gt;Cassandra Lavalle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>