<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mariosanchez.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Talk Like Ted</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/talkliketed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/talkliketed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/ted.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was rehearsing a presentation, and one of my co-workers recorded it on video. What an eye opener! I was terrible&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting some honest feedback and a few tips, and going through the presentation for five or six more times, my delivery got better, to the point that I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t have to cringe when I watched it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if fate had it, a few days later I was at a Fedex store and saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17910144-talk-like-ted&#34;&gt;Talk Like Ted&lt;/a&gt;, by Carmine Gallo, sitting on the shelves. I went to my local library and picked it up. Here are my most important takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good presentation is:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional (touch the heart)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Novel (teach something new)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memorable (you&amp;rsquo;ll never forget)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Stories are &amp;ldquo;data with a soul&amp;rdquo;&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warm up your audience with stories, before you throw around statistics. &lt;strong&gt;Start with a story they can relate to&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;three types of stories&lt;/strong&gt;:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About other people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About brand success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;story arch&lt;/strong&gt; goes like this: at the beginning everything is fine; then something bad happens; then the bad is overcome and victory ensues. Every good story follows more or less that trajectory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three things to do &lt;strong&gt;before a good presentation&lt;/strong&gt;:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get brutal feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reherase, rehearse, rehearse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;four elements&lt;/strong&gt; that you must incorporate into your verbal delivery:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inflections, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pauses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ideal speaking speed when you deliver a presentation is &lt;strong&gt;190 words/minute&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you present, try to &lt;strong&gt;act and look like a leader&lt;/strong&gt;: looks, poise, confidence, matter almost as much as your content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gestures are important. Hand movements are necessary, but for maximum effectiveness you need to use them sparingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your hand movements within your &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;power sphere&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;: the arch between your eyes, your extended arms and your waist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other &lt;strong&gt;Do&amp;rsquo;s and Dont&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt;:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t juggle, tap or jingle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t stand still. &lt;strong&gt;Move!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t put both hands in your pocket&lt;/strong&gt;. One hand is OK, provided that the other one is moving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Dopamine is your brain&amp;rsquo;s SAVE button&lt;/mark&gt;. When the brain releases dopamine, people remember more. You need to help your audience release dopamine with compelling stories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To get more story ideas submit yourself to &lt;strong&gt;new experiences&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. travel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must have &lt;strong&gt;ONE key message&lt;/strong&gt;: there must be one key point you want to make, and you need to be able to express it in a &amp;ldquo;Twitter headline&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;(140 characters or less)&lt;/strong&gt;. If you can&amp;rsquo;t, keep refining your idea. Being able to articulate your point briefly and concisely will help your audience to better process your content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create &lt;strong&gt;jaw-dropping moments&lt;/strong&gt;: present the information in a way nobody has done it before (remember &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/bill_gates_unplugged&#34;&gt;Bill Gates releasing mosquitoes&lt;/a&gt; to the audience before his talk about malaria?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find &lt;strong&gt;tangible comparisons to hard to understand numbers&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re talking about BP&amp;rsquo;s oil spill, talk in terms of how many olympic size pools of oil were leaked, as oppossed to gallons. Steve Jobs did this brilliantly when he launched the ipod, talking about 1,000 songs in your pocket, instead of Megabytes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End on a high note, and &lt;strong&gt;leave the audience wanting to know more&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;using humor&lt;/strong&gt;, try to use:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal anecdotes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analogies and metaphors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Videos and photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;18 Minute Rule&lt;/strong&gt;: there is a reason why TED talks are 18 minutes long. It is the optimal length if you want the audience to be engaged and remember what you said.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longer presentations require a break or a change of pace (perhaps incorporating a video in between your talk) &lt;strong&gt;every 10 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember the &lt;strong&gt;Rule of Three&lt;/strong&gt;: people remember and make sense of blocks of three concepts at a time. Throw in more and they won&amp;rsquo;t process them as well. Some examples of the Rule of Three are: &amp;ldquo;Good, Better, Best&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Life, Liberty and the Pursuit of Happiness&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Eat, Pray, Love&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Small, Medium, Large&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Three Story Structure&lt;/strong&gt;: this is a very effective technique, used by the best presenters. You have &lt;strong&gt;ONE key point&lt;/strong&gt; supported by &lt;strong&gt;three key messages&lt;/strong&gt;, and each of those three key messages is supported by &lt;strong&gt;stories, statistics and examples&lt;/strong&gt;. Watch &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.stanford.edu/2005/06/14/jobs-061505/&#34;&gt;Steve&amp;rsquo;s Job commencement address&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford and see if you can figure out his main point and key messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a &lt;strong&gt;multi-sensory experience&lt;/strong&gt;: try to incorporate props and visual aids into your presentation. Remember: pictures are better than bullet points, videos are better than pictures, and things/people are better than videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay in your lane: Basically, &lt;strong&gt;be authentic&lt;/strong&gt; and don&amp;rsquo;t bullshit. Know what you&amp;rsquo;re talking about. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know, don&amp;rsquo;t give that talk, or keep practicing. Don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;fake it &amp;lsquo;til you make it&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;fake it &amp;lsquo;til you become it&lt;/mark&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to the Good Life</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ayw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ayw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/stoic.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally got to read &amp;ldquo;A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy&amp;rdquo; by William B. Irvine. The book came highly recommended by Derek Sivers, an artist and writer that I respect and identify with due to our almost identical world views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had only a vague idea of what stoicism was prior to reading the book, but based on my little knowledge I suspected that I have been practicing, albeit unknowingly, many of the tenets of this philosophy. Reading the book confirmed my theory, and introduced me to some new tools and techniques to improve the way I live. Here are &lt;strong&gt;10 key ideas&lt;/strong&gt; of the book that I highlighted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The objective of Stoicism is to enable you to live a good life by pursuing &lt;strong&gt;tranquility&lt;/strong&gt; (defined as the absence of negative emotions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism teaches us to use our &lt;strong&gt;reasoning ability&lt;/strong&gt; to banish negative emotions like anger, grief, and envy. Rational people will find Stoicism easier to practice than overly emotional people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism recommends the practice of &amp;ldquo;negative visualization&amp;rdquo;, basically to imagine how would life be if we lose the things or people we value. By engaging in negative visualization we diminish the anguish and grief of loss in two ways: first, because whatever happens we will be expecting it, and second, because it teaches us to be grateful for the things we still have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to master the &amp;ldquo;trichotomy of control&amp;rdquo;, by recognizing the three categories of things: 1) Things over which we have complete control, 2) Things over which we have no control at all, and 3) Things over which we have some but not complete control. We should only concern ourselves with things over which we have complete control, or some level of control. It is useless to worry about things over which we don&amp;rsquo;t have control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Along those lines, Stoicism teaches us to choose &amp;ldquo;internal goals&amp;rdquo; as opposed to &amp;ldquo;external goals&amp;rdquo;. For example, if we&amp;rsquo;re playing a game of tennis, our goal should be to play our best tennis possible, and not to win the game. By internalizing his goals, the Stoic is able to preserve his tranquility while dealing with things over which he has only partial control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism teaches us that the key to being wealthy is not to have a lot but to &lt;strong&gt;need very little&lt;/strong&gt;. Stoics don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily reject material wealth. They enjoy it but they don&amp;rsquo;t cling to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics prepare to lose their wealth by regularly practicing &amp;ldquo;voluntary discomfort&amp;rdquo;. The most likely result of practicing this technique is that we will soon notice how little do we really need to live a happy, productive life. Some things we can practice on a regular basis are to eat simply prioritizing nutrition over pleasure, get rid of non-essential possesions and practice minimalism, take public transportation instead of our car, sleep in couches, take cold showers, etc. These are minor things that we will get used to and learn to enjoy with time. Because they have learned to enjoy things that are easily obtainable or that can’t be taken from them, Stoics will find much in life to enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics recognize that our anger about something is usually worse and lasts longer than the damage done to us, therefore we should &lt;strong&gt;avoid getting angry&lt;/strong&gt;. To get rid of anger we should practice putting things in their right perspective. For example, we can ask ourselves: &amp;ldquo;will this really matter in 100 years?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics value their &lt;strong&gt;freedom&lt;/strong&gt;, and they are therefore reluctant to do anything that will give others power over them. If we seek social status, we give other people power over us. That is why as Stoics we must become indifferent to other people’s opinions of us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We must train ourselves to not hold grudges or condider ourselves a victim. If we consider ourselves victims, we are not going to have a good life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this book I recommend checking out &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/book/StoicJoy&#34;&gt;Derek Siver&amp;rsquo;s book notes&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0195374614?tag=sivers-20&#34;&gt;reading the whole book&lt;/a&gt; (it&amp;rsquo;s worth it!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: A Guide to the Good Life</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/stoic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/stoic.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally managed to read &amp;ldquo;A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy&amp;rdquo; by William B. Irvine. The book came highly recommended by Derek Sivers, an artist and writer that I respect and identify with due to our almost identical world views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had only a vague idea of what stoicism was prior to reading the book, but based on my little knowledge I suspected that I have been practicing, albeit unknowingly, many of the tenets of this philosophy. Reading the book confirmed my theory, and introduced me to some new tools and techniques to improve the way I live. Here are &lt;strong&gt;10 key ideas&lt;/strong&gt; of the book that I highlighted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The objective of Stoicism is to enable you to live a good life by pursuing &lt;strong&gt;tranquility&lt;/strong&gt; (defined as the absence of negative emotions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism teaches us to use our &lt;strong&gt;reasoning ability&lt;/strong&gt; to banish negative emotions like anger, grief, and envy. Rational people will find Stoicism easier to practice than overly emotional people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism recommends the practice of &amp;ldquo;negative visualization&amp;rdquo;, basically to imagine how would life be if we lose the things or people we value. By engaging in negative visualization we diminish the anguish and grief of loss in two ways: first, because whatever happens we will be expecting it, and second, because it teaches us to be grateful for the things we still have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to master the &amp;ldquo;trichotomy of control&amp;rdquo;, by recognizing the three categories of things: 1) Things over which we have complete control, 2) Things over which we have no control at all, and 3) Things over which we have some but not complete control. We should only concern ourselves with things over which we have complete control, or some level of control. It is useless to worry about things over which we don&amp;rsquo;t have control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Along those lines, Stoicism teaches us to choose &amp;ldquo;internal goals&amp;rdquo; as opposed to &amp;ldquo;external goals&amp;rdquo;. For example, if we&amp;rsquo;re playing a game of tennis, our goal should be to play our best tennis possible, and not to win the game. By internalizing his goals, the Stoic is able to preserve his tranquility while dealing with things over which he has only partial control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism teaches us that the key to being wealthy is not to have a lot but to &lt;strong&gt;need very little&lt;/strong&gt;. Stoics don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily reject material wealth. They enjoy it but they don&amp;rsquo;t cling to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics prepare to lose their wealth by regularly practicing &amp;ldquo;voluntary discomfort&amp;rdquo;. The most likely result of practicing this technique is that we will soon notice how little do we really need to live a happy, productive life. Some things we can practice on a regular basis are to eat simply prioritizing nutrition over pleasure, get rid of non-essential possessions and practice minimalism, take public transportation instead of our car, sleep in couches, take cold showers, etc. These are minor things that we will get used to and learn to enjoy with time. Because they have learned to enjoy things that are easily obtainable or that can’t be taken from them, Stoics will find much in life to enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics recognize that our anger about something is usually worse and lasts longer than the damage done to us, therefore we should &lt;strong&gt;avoid getting angry&lt;/strong&gt;. To get rid of anger we should practice putting things in their right perspective. For example, we can ask ourselves: &amp;ldquo;will this really matter in 100 years?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics value their &lt;strong&gt;freedom&lt;/strong&gt;, and they are therefore reluctant to do anything that will give others power over them. If we seek social status, we give other people power over us. That is why as Stoics we must become indifferent to other people’s opinions of us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We must train ourselves to not hold grudges or consider ourselves a victim. If we consider ourselves victims, we are not going to have a good life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this book I recommend checking out &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/book/StoicJoy&#34;&gt;Derek Siver&amp;rsquo;s book notes&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0195374614?tag=sivers-20&#34;&gt;reading the whole book&lt;/a&gt; (it&amp;rsquo;s worth it!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallery</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/gallery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Places I&amp;rsquo;ve been. Things that caught my eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://66.media.tumblr.com/3a9fce7081e44f1fbafab7adc6051f10/tumblr_ofv7d2aqfP1qz7ur9o3_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Visual Storytelling Summit @ The Idea Center&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/5b1ff46184c72d8eb99ce41e13953bc1/tumblr_ofv7d2aqfP1qz7ur9o2_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Capitol, Annapolis, MD&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/6cee5295e83e548ece49d8408c31e99f/tumblr_ofv7d2aqfP1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Harbor, Annapolis, MD&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://67.media.tumblr.com/e6ff9ef974df18f3a113f66e47712e78/tumblr_oglmtiCMFC1qz7ur9o3_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Victoria Harbour, Cape Town, S.A.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://67.media.tumblr.com/45f36847571c0eb162aec8feddffebf3/tumblr_oglmtiCMFC1qz7ur9o2_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A View from Cable Mountain, Cape Town, S.A.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://67.media.tumblr.com/d0271e19ddb02135a8f57f383816b994/tumblr_oglmtiCMFC1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Kirstenbosch National Botanical Garden, Cape Town, S.A.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/bb52a98d00fc300a5d011cfaa7d1cf14/tumblr_ocy7coAtdY1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Landing in Panama City&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/84c510905100c38d2d5b28b5a5332ea0/tumblr_occ8msLjaF1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Sanibel, FL&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://66.media.tumblr.com/048db88744dcc7f30127ae3ccae3ce66/tumblr_obzbaq5C0Z1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Google Analytics IQ class&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://67.media.tumblr.com/8647cda79e25754c8e47d01a8cfd4d97/tumblr_obzannm7fP1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Monumental de River&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://66.media.tumblr.com/3453ff27919cf46b7955e28f71c254c4/tumblr_obza4vDzSq1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Port of Miami at dusk&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/4a096d78507ad9616c947ff35e449b17/tumblr_obza4vDzSq1qz7ur9o2_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Working at home&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/56efe0813e644376afa7802807d3b24e/tumblr_nx1zvtPaxq1qz7ur9o3_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Dried fish at Monterosso al Mare&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/aba0b27f9be305fdfa0a772d0f7eb397/tumblr_nx1xselzwl1qz7ur9o9_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Manarola, Cinque Terre&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/102fee3542e5ff746f7adf20b37d3dca/tumblr_nsgn7woPjG1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Brooklyn townhouse&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/b3d3fff1a1857c1b03b3f6eec6ceb325/tumblr_nsgmwt1apO1qz7ur9o8_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Downtown NYC&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/09784396750c3cdfab2cb0d5379f2160/tumblr_nogpcm9V3V1qz7ur9o7_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Italian icons&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://66.media.tumblr.com/9439de5a70d9c47640a63d76f335eb98/tumblr_nplc2hPYSe1qz7ur9o3_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;La Rosa Nautica restaurant, Lima, Peru&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/775dcedf9a0785b9374ab8d5c3e4706e/tumblr_nplc2hPYSe1qz7ur9o4_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Lima, Peru&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://65.media.tumblr.com/9245d7420ec6e64cc74bfa89e38e9b46/tumblr_nmnn7lm1sF1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Bogota from Monserrate&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://66.media.tumblr.com/e02e25a8b1e9d05a6eb062bede48ed93/tumblr_nmap6sWgT21qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Dune safari, Dubai&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/828a74b77b6cbb1fa7ba1b81f01a76a8/tumblr_njsc54cAVW1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Caviar, smoked salmon and vodka&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://65.media.tumblr.com/bb7fe01f3c9f38009ac143a31714ffd4/tumblr_njsbfyVTKX1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Matchbox&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;picbox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://66.media.tumblr.com/6d87d638dd85e5becce7b7b1634479cd/tumblr_njsbemErgw1qz7ur9o1_540.jpg&#34; class=&#34;frame&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Church of The Spilled Blood, St. Petersburg&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a SPA with Angular.js</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/angularspa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/angularspa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/angularjs.png&#34; class=&#34;profile&#34;&gt;A few weeks ago I came across the concept of SPA, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single-page_application&#34;&gt;Single Page Application&lt;/a&gt;, and learned that they can be created with &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;Angular.js&lt;/a&gt;, a JavaScript library supported by Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most definitions of SPA you can find online are very technical and full of jargon, so perhaps the best way a newbie web developer like me can understand it is with an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have an &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; web page with three different sections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The header (where the navigation menu is)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The content area, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The footer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The header and the footer remain the same all over the website, so the only thing that really changes when you go from the &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; page to, say, the &lt;code&gt;about.html&lt;/code&gt; page is the actual page content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a SPA does is to allow the header and the footer to stay right where they are, while it calls only the actual content of the &lt;code&gt;about.html&lt;/code&gt; page and sticks it right between the header and the footer. No new page is loaded (that&amp;rsquo;s where the &amp;ldquo;Single Page&amp;rdquo; part of Single Page Application comes from).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The switch between the content of your &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; and your &lt;code&gt;about.html&lt;/code&gt; page is done on the fly by the browser of the person viewing your site, by following the &lt;strong&gt;Angular.js&lt;/strong&gt; directives embedded in the page code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to test building a SPA by creating a barebones, basic brochure site, using &lt;strong&gt;Angular.js&lt;/strong&gt; to generate four page views: Home, About, Contact and Resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airpair.com/angularjs/building-angularjs-app-tutorial&#34;&gt;excellent tutorial&lt;/a&gt; online. After reading it carefully several times I started by creating the index template, which contains the Angular directives to make the site work, and which acts as a template for the whole site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then created bare-bones html files for the other three pages of the site: About, Contact and Resume (nothing fancy, just a couple of &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags and a paragraph).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I tweaked the &lt;strong&gt;main.js&lt;/strong&gt; file to refer to my four pages: &lt;code&gt;/home&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;/contact&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;/about&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;/resume&lt;/code&gt;, instead of all the different pages listed in the tutorial (which uses a bloated website template that I decided not to follow, for simplicity&amp;rsquo;s sake. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t use the Bootstrap style sheets suggested by the author, opting instead for a much simpler style sheet based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://getskeleton.com&#34;&gt;Skeleton&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;main.js&lt;/strong&gt; file is where the real magic happens: it contains the Routes, which are basically the instructions that &lt;strong&gt;Angular.js&lt;/strong&gt; gives the browser: &amp;ldquo;if user clicks on &lt;code&gt;/about&lt;/code&gt; do this; if user clicks on &lt;code&gt;/contact&lt;/code&gt; do that&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to try it yourself I recommend that you read and follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airpair.com/angularjs/building-angularjs-app-tutorial&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. The author is obviously a very capable programmer and can explain things much better than I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also clone the site I created. Here is the Github repo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/mariobox/angulartestsite/&#34;&gt;http://github.com/mariobox/angulartestsite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also created a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mariobox.github.io/angulartestsite&#34;&gt;Live Demo&lt;/a&gt; so you can try it out on your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 9 Principles</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 21:10:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/principles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this slide in a meeting room at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theideacenter.co&#34;&gt;The Idea Center&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://67.media.tumblr.com/2310dd5921f5742e43873efe4187ac86/tumblr_oac1a49Eqv1qz7ur9o1_1280.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principles, succinctly listed on the page, resonated immediately so I took a picture of the slide. Later, when I got home, I Googled them and found the source: Joi Ito, director of MIT&amp;rsquo;s Media Lab &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.media.mit.edu/about/principles&#34;&gt;wrote them in 2012&lt;/a&gt; as he distilled the mental models required to succeed in the new world of work brought upon us by technology and the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inktalks.com/discover/287/joichi-ito-mit-media-lab-from-a-container-to-a-network&#34;&gt;watch Ito&amp;rsquo;s presentation&lt;/a&gt; where he explains in more detail each one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just going to list them here as a note-to-self for future reference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience Over Strength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems Over Objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disobedience Over Compliance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull Over Push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compasses Over Maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emergence Over Authority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk Over Safety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice Over Theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning Over Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Useful Habits for the Digital Age</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/7newhabits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 11:17:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/7newhabits/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Covey wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1THjXoz&#34;&gt;7 Habits Of Highly Effective People&lt;/a&gt; in 1989. Since then, many authors have expanded the conversation by adding their own seven habits for success, effectiveness, happiness or whatever end goal they may be pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next few paragraphs, I will distill the seven most important habits that, in my opinion, are esential to successfully navigate the waters of the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-know-what-you-want:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;1. Know What You Want&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds easy but, more often than not, people &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t know what they want&lt;/a&gt;. Passion or purpose is not something that hits us in the head while we&amp;rsquo;re sitting down waiting for it. &lt;strong&gt;We need to get out and find it&lt;/strong&gt;. The best way is to try many different things (go wide) until something sticks. It must be something that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind doing even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bring you money. Once you find it, you then need to focus (go deep), learn everything you can, and strive to &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1XHLESW&#34;&gt;become the best&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-be-different:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;2. Be Different&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to find your &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcompany.com/28905/brand-called-you&#34;&gt;personal brand&lt;/a&gt;. Merely being competent or very good is not enough. You need to be different. Find the quality or qualities that make you different than your peers and competitors. You can be the details guy, or the people-person gal, or the guy who is always trying out new things, but by all means find something that makes you stand out. &lt;strong&gt;Approach your craft from an angle that others can&amp;rsquo;t or won&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt;. Narrow your niche as much as you profitably can so that you can claim the top spot.  Seth Godin wrote about this more than a decade ago in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Vpd5ki&#34;&gt;Purple Cow&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, pick it up. It&amp;rsquo;s a short read and well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-spend-less-than-you-make:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;3. Spend Less Than You Make&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing will widen the gap between you and your dreams more than debt. Avoid it like the plague. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, really: &lt;strong&gt;spend less than you make&lt;/strong&gt;. This may seem hard in a society like ours, where we are bombarded every day with &amp;ldquo;buy now, pay later&amp;rdquo; marketing messages, but if you stick to it suddenly it will become a habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-save-a-lot-of-money:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;4. Save a Lot of Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Those who say that money is not important either have too much or don&amp;rsquo;t have any&lt;/strong&gt;. Money gives you flexibility and freedom. Accumulating a big chunk of cash means that you will never have to do &lt;a href=&#34;https://thebillfold.com/a-story-of-a-fuck-off-fund-648401263659#.bhrdyqcf7&#34;&gt;something you don&amp;rsquo;t want to&lt;/a&gt; because you need the money. The car broke down? Want to take that class? Want to go on that trip? Want to splurge on something really important to you? No problem, you&amp;rsquo;ve prepared for it. Just write a check. For more on this I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1TQ0BQt&#34;&gt;Ramit Sethi&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-learn-to-be-uncomfortable:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;5. Learn To Be Uncomfortable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be free you have to &lt;strong&gt;learn to live like a college student&lt;/strong&gt;. Get used to sleeping on couches, drinking tap water, catching the bus, taking cold showers, eating simple meals, using your local library, buying used stuff, etc. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to do all these things all the time, but knowing that you can do them and still be OK will give you an edge: when you know that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a lot to live well and that you can always go somewhere else, well&amp;hellip;&lt;strong&gt;you have the power&lt;/strong&gt;. For more on this I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1XHMBuE&#34;&gt;Mark Cuban&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt;, especially the chapters that describe how he started out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-lighten-your-load:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;6. Lighten Your Load&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being rich in the digital age means something completely different than twenty years ago. Back then, being rich meant owning things: the McMansion, the expensive car, the boat, the fancy jewelery, the corner office, etc. All that is bullshit now. These days &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re considered rich when you have time, freedom, mobility and cool experiences&lt;/strong&gt;. The sharing economy has given us access to practically anything without the burden of ownership. Forget the vacation home: book an Airbnb. Thinking of buying a car? Unless you live in a sprawling city with no public transportation you don&amp;rsquo;t need to: take the train, hail an Uber or ride a bike. Corner office? Please&amp;hellip; just work out of a coffee shop or your local library. Hold on to your money (see #4) and donate/throw away the things you don&amp;rsquo;t use that are weighing you down. The ultimate aim is to fit everything you own in a carry-on bag. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.becomingminimalist.com/millennials/&#34;&gt;Be flexible. Be mobile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-always-be-learning:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;7. Always Be Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think that you&amp;rsquo;re safe because you have a college degree, think again. &lt;strong&gt;Technology and the digital revolution are completely redefining professions&lt;/strong&gt; to the point that they would be unrecognizeable to somebody who has spent the last ten years in a desert island. If you have any doubts, just ask &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@knightfdn/10-basics-today-s-journalists-need-562df8787406#.bzsocpbmk&#34;&gt;journalists&lt;/a&gt;, marketers, customer service representatives, taxi drivers, and other professionals whose lives have been disrupted by technology and globalization. The good news is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/onlineed/&#34;&gt;learning new things online&lt;/a&gt; for free or very little money is now easier than ever. You just need to have drive and curiosity. For older folks, another piece of advice: surround yourself with young people. The future is no longer being shaped by politicians or captains of industry, but by laptop-toting, tech-savvy twenty-somethings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-summary:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know what you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend less than you make&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save a lot of money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to be uncomfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighten your load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always be learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7210/6812971608_30001b913a_h.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;small&#34;&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jodimichelle/6812971608/&#34;&gt;jodimichelle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juxtapose: JavaScript Before-and-After Visual Tool</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/juxtapose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 22:50:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/juxtapose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As content creators in the digital age, writers and journalists need to get familiar with data visualization tools. One of these tools is Juxtapose, created by &lt;a href=&#34;http://knightlab.northwestern.edu/&#34;&gt;Northwestern University Knight Lab&lt;/a&gt; using JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juxtapose lets you highlight the &lt;em&gt;before-and-after&lt;/em&gt; aspect of your stories using a visually compelling slider graphic (you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://juxtapose.knightlab.com/&#34;&gt;make one on the app&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt; and then just cut and embed a snippet of code on your site).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried it myself using two selfies I took during the last World Cup, wearing the jerseys of the two finalists (lame example, I know, but think of the possibilities if you&amp;rsquo;re covering a more serious subject!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;juxtapose&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.knightlab.com/libs/juxtapose/latest/embed/index.html?uid=b440cd8c-1a4a-11e6-a524-0e7075bba956&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to check out the Juxtapose source code it is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NUKnightLab/juxtapose&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: Here is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/06/07/amazing-photos-capture-1910-great-flood-of-paris-v-2016/&#34;&gt;great example of Juxtapose&lt;/a&gt; used in news media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Basic Git Workflow</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/gitflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 18:00:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/gitflow/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This quick rundown portrays the basic workflow I go through when using &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of files. It assumes you have some basic knowledge of Git. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are plenty of resources online (&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2&#34;&gt;this is a good starting point&lt;/a&gt;). It also assumes that you are using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; for your remote repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creating-a-repository-from-scratch:a603a77b1f5c5be5405a46ac8ca7dda3&#34;&gt;Creating a repository from scratch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open your Terminal and navigate to a folder you want to start tracking (if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use the Terminal this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-the-command-line&#34;&gt;quick online course&lt;/a&gt; will show you the basics).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type &lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt; to create a new subdirectory, called .git, where your file changes are going to be tracked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a new file, for example one called &lt;em&gt;grocery.txt&lt;/em&gt; (a simple text file listing different grocery stores in your neighborhood) by typing &lt;code&gt;touch grocery.txt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open your favorite text editor, add some grocery store names and save the file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the file to the staging area by doing &lt;code&gt;git add grocery.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commit your changes by doing &lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;ldquo;MESSAGE HERE&amp;rdquo;&lt;/code&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to type your message in between quote marks explaining what you did to the file.  Since this is the first time you commit this file it is OK to just write &amp;ldquo;initial commit&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to push your file to a remote repository, you need to create the remote repository first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Github and create a new project folder where you&amp;rsquo;re going to place and track &lt;em&gt;grocery.txt&lt;/em&gt;. You can call it &lt;em&gt;new-project&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look around the screen for the URL of the project folder you just created. It should be something like &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com/youraccount/new-project.git&#34;&gt;https://www.github.com/youraccount/new-project.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy that URL, go back to your terminal, and type &lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add remote origin &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com/youraccount/new-project.git&#34;&gt;https://www.github.com/youraccount/new-project.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push your file to the remote repository with &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt; (if at any point Github asks you for your username and password type them in).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you are tracking &lt;em&gt;grocery.txt&lt;/em&gt; both in your local repository (your computer) and a remote repository!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s say that the next day you come back to your file and add some more grocery store names. Once you&amp;rsquo;re done, do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save the file&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;code&gt;git add grocery.txt&lt;/code&gt; to add the changes to the staging area, and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;ldquo;add grocery stores&amp;rdquo;&lt;/code&gt; to commit your changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To upload these changes to the remote repository simply type &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt;. Type your username and password when prompted and the changes will be uploaded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloning-a-remote-repository:a603a77b1f5c5be5405a46ac8ca7dda3&#34;&gt;Cloning a remote repository&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloning a remote repository means installing a copy in your local computer. You may want to clone one of your existing remote repositories to do some work on it locally, or you may want to clone a remote repository belonging to somebody else and use it as a template for your own project. In this case, first make sure you have permission from the repository owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what you do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Github and follow the instructions to fork the repository to your profile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to call the repository something else, just rename it as you want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, clone the repository to your local computer by going back to the terminal and typing &lt;code&gt;git clone URL OF THE REPOSITORY&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve cloned the repository and done some work on it, the process is the same as when you update a local repository created from scratch: you work on your files, make some changes, add them to the staging area, commit them, and finally push them back to the remote repository with &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before You Sharpen That Axe</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 21:05:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people don&amp;rsquo;t fail because they don&amp;rsquo;t have enough money or plans, but because they don&amp;rsquo;t know what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what you want is hard, that&amp;rsquo;s why so few people engage in it. It is easier to just start doing things, like answering email or running errands: they keep us busy and give us the illusion of making progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding what we really want, though, is the first step before starting a project, launching a career or designing a life plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with this quote attributed to Abraham Lincoln: &amp;ldquo;give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening my axe&amp;rdquo;. It underscores the importance of preparation before execution. Figuring out what we want comes first, though, so &lt;mark&gt;before you sharpen that axe make sure that chopping down a tree is what you really want to do&lt;/mark&gt;. Perhaps what you really want is to plant a tree instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose first, preparation and execution second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the subject I recommend watching Simon Sinek&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action?language=en&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start With Why&amp;rdquo; Ted talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/tree.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/peter_from_wellington/15701759174/&#34;&gt;Peter Kurdulija&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Ubuntu in an Old Laptop</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 18:00:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the hard drive of my old Toshiba Satellite died suddenly I thought of getting rid of it, but when I learned that you could buy a refurbished hard drive on ebay for very little money (around $35) I ordered one and installed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clean, fresh hard drive with no OS gave me the perfect excuse to install a Linux operating system. I had heard good things about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, with its user-friendly interface and none of the clutter that comes with a traditional Windows installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From another computer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/download/desktop/create-a-usb-stick-on-windows&#34;&gt;create a Ubuntu bootable USB stick&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plug the Ubuntu USB stick in a USB port of the computer where you want to install it, and turn the computer on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;As soon as the first screen comes up press F12 (or Escape or F2 depending on the computer you&amp;rsquo;re using). You will be taken to a menu of options where you will need to change the booting order to boot from the USB drive first (&lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/5991848/how-to-boot-from-a-cd-or-usb-drive-on-any-pc&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; offers a pretty good explanation of how to do it, depending on the computer you&amp;rsquo;re using).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once Ubuntu comes up on the screen, it will give you the option to try it out from the USB port or to install it in your hard drive. You can choose either one. Since I wanted to install it in my clean, empty hard drive I chose the latter. There are other things you can do, like running Ubuntu alongside Windows, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried them. There are plenty of tutorials online explaining alternative installations, though, if you want to do something different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I activated the wifi connection by looking for it in the connections icon at the top right of the main window.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new Ubuntu installation works perfectly. It is fast and efficient, and the interface is intuitive enough that anybody can use it. Ubuntu also comes Firefox already installed, and with LibreOffice, an open source office suite compatible with Microsoft Office. That means you can open and edit files like Word documents, Excel spreadsheets and PowerPoint presentations and share them with other users quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am very happy that my old laptop got a new lease of life, and that installing (and using) the free and open source Ubuntu on it was easy and painless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/../images/ubuntu.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related: &lt;a href=&#34;http://evbogue.com/decentdevcomputer/&#34;&gt;How to Get a Decent Dev Computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology and the Future of Education</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/onlineed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 12:53:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/onlineed/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Following one of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/&#34;&gt;my themes for 2016&lt;/a&gt; I recently started learning Javascript. Rather than using a book I signed up to Treehouse, an online platform that specializes in teaching how to code.  After using the site for a few days I am now able to better understand how technology can help solve the problem of the skyrocketing cost of today&amp;rsquo;s higher education:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-scale:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;1. Scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economies of scale achieved through technology have dramatically reduced the cost of education delivery. While courses in bricks-and-mortar schools can cost thousands of dollars, you can take unlimited classes online for less than $50 a month. Think of the savings this represents over the four years of a typical college education. If colleges and universities are investing in real estate instead of technology they&amp;rsquo;re making a big mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-lesson-delivery:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;2. Lesson Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some people will always prefer face to face lessons, the advantages of video are hard to ignore. For one, cost: why pay somebody to deliver the same lesson over and over again, when you can just capture it on video, once?  Today&amp;rsquo;s educational videos are highly optimized pieces of content where everything, from the instructor&amp;rsquo;s tone of voice, to the words chosen to explain the concepts, to the infographics used as teaching aids, and even the backround decor, have been thoroughly tested to provide the most effective learning experience. A video can also reach millions, not just the number of students that fit in a typical classroom. You can also rewind a video at your leisure, watch it as many times as you want, when you want, wherever you may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-socialization-and-interaction:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;3. Socialization and Interaction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proponents of traditional education may argue that campus life enables students to interact, socialize and make connections.  The same, however, can be achieved through online education. While the interaction may not always be face to face, online tools like forums, social networks, and email let us be in contact with peers, ask questions, and give and get help. Students can also research their local scene for meetups where like-minded people can get together to discuss any topic, exchange ideas, and socialize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-pace-and-rewards:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;4. Pace and Rewards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online schools are pioneers of the &lt;em&gt;gamification&lt;/em&gt; of education. They break down subjects into bite-sized lessons and give out points when a student completes them. Successfully passing a course or track earns them a badge. These achievements are then listed in the student&amp;rsquo;s profile, for bragging rights and motivation. Online teaching platforms are succeeding in making education fun, by providing a learning environment that resonates with digital natives, used to instant gratification and fast feedback loops. Traditional institutions, on the other hand, mostly follow the rigid set of rythms, timelines and processes of the industrial age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-skills-versus-credentials:a1d805a8a8ab61b425677631aabd1cb0&#34;&gt;5. Skills versus Credentials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing a credential is one of the few considerations where traditional education may still come out ahead. I believe, however, that as the cost of traditional education gets higher and less people are willing to mortgage their lives in exchange for a diploma, more employers will have to adapt and get with the times. I also envision the talent pool getting bigger and competition stronger, which will devalue credentials in favor of skills and experience. Those who hone their skills working on intersting projects will be more valuable than those who just hide behind a piece of paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I may be overemphasizing the virtues of online education based on my recent (and limited) experience, it is undeniable that traditional education is being &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/news/briefing/21605899-staid-higher-education-business-about-experience-welcome-earthquake-digital&#34;&gt;disrupted&lt;/a&gt;, and that technology and the Internet will become the preferred media for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course&#34;&gt;education delivery in the future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiet</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/quiet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 21:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/quiet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/quiet.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an introvert myself this book really resonated with me. It talks about the current social obsession with extroversion and teamwork, especially in the business world, where being gregarious is seen as an almost indispensable precondition for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With conclusive research data, the author demonstrates that designing an environment that caters to the needs of introverts, by not over stimulating them with group activities, letting them work alone for extended periods of time, or giving them time to recharge, leads to better results, in business and in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial two thirds of the book explain how we arrived to the era of extroversion glorification. Several pages are dedicated to cover Tony Robbins over-the-top seminars and the culture within the Evangelical church. It also deals with the psycological research behind our different personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real meat of the book comes in Chapter 9, where we can find actionable advice. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn about &amp;ldquo;stretching&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Free Trait Agreements&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;restorative niches&amp;rdquo;, powerful techniques that introverts can use to thrive in today&amp;rsquo;s extrovert-driven world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the book I found out that the author had done a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/susan_cain_the_power_of_introverts?language=en&#34;&gt;TED talk&lt;/a&gt; on the subject. While not a substitute for the book it is worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes:413acb98b45f59b87e6a91c1fc93570d&#34;&gt;My Highlights and Notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our lives are shaped as profoundly by personality as by gender or race.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yet today we make room for a remarkably narrow range of personality styles. We&amp;rsquo;re told that to be great is to be bold, to be happy is to be sociable. We see ourselves as a nation of extroverts-which means that we&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of who we really are.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So many people pretend to be extroverts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some fool even themselves, until some life event-a layoff, an empty nest, an inheritance that frees them to spend time as they like-jolts them into taking stock of their true natures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introversion-along with its cousins sensitivity, seriousness, and shyness-is now a second-class personality trait.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We make a grave mistake to embrace the Extrovert Ideal so unthinkingly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neither E=mc2 nor Paradise Lost was dashed off by a party animal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Many of the most important institutions of contemporary life are designed for those who enjoy group projects and high levels of stimulation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The vast majority of teachers believe that the ideal student is an extrovert.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As adults, many of us work for organizations that insist we work in teams, in offices without walls, for supervisors who value &amp;ldquo;people skills&amp;rdquo; above all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re expected to promote ourselves unabashedly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re an introvert, you also know that the bias against quiet can cause deep psychic pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come &amp;ldquo;out of your shell&amp;rdquo;-that noxious expression&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now that you&amp;rsquo;re an adult, you might still feel a pang of guilt when you decline a dinner invitation in favor of a good book.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have seen firsthand &lt;mark&gt;how difficult it is for introverts to take stock of their own talents, and how powerful it is when finally they do&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts recharge their batteries by being alone; extroverts need to recharge when they don&amp;rsquo;t socialize enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no all-purpose definition of introversion or extroversion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts and extroverts differ in the level of outside stimulation that they need to function well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts, in contrast, may have strong social skills and enjoy parties and business meetings, but after a while wish they were home in their pajamas. They prefer to devote their social energies to close friends, colleagues, and family. They listen more than they talk, think before they speak, and often feel as if they express themselves better in writing than in conversation. They tend to dislike conflict. Many have a horror of small talk, but enjoy deep discussions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nor are introverts necessarily shy. &lt;mark&gt;Shyness is the fear of social disapproval or humiliation, while introversion is a preference for environments that are not overstimulating&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;America had shifted from what the influential cultural historian Warren Susman called a Culture of Character to a Culture of Personality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The social role demanded of all in the new Culture of Personality was that of a performer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Americans responded to these pressures by trying to become salesmen who could sell not only their company&amp;rsquo;s latest gizmo but also themselves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By 1920, popular self-help guides had changed their focus from inner virtue to outer charm-to know what to say and how to say it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The model employee of the midcentury-even one whose job rarely involved dealing with the public, like a research scientist in a corporate lab-was not a deep thinker but a hearty extrovert with a salesman&amp;rsquo;s personality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Early Americans revered action and were suspicious of intellect, associating the life of the mind with the languid, ineffectual European aristocracy they had left behind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The pressure to entertain, to sell ourselves, and never to be visibly anxious keeps ratcheting up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What if you love knowledge for its own sake, not necessarily as a blueprint to action?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A middle manager at GE once told me that &amp;ldquo;people here don&amp;rsquo;t even want to meet with you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a PowerPoint and a &amp;ldquo;pitch&amp;rdquo; for them&amp;rdquo;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone knows that it&amp;rsquo;s important to be an extrovert and troublesome to be an introvert. So people work real hard at looking like extroverts, whether that&amp;rsquo;s comfortable or not.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If we assume that quiet and loud people have roughly the same number of good (and bad) ideas, then we should worry if the louder and more forceful people always carry the day&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We perceive talkers as smarter than quiet types-even though grade-point averages and SAT and intelligence test scores reveal this perception to be inaccurate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We put too much of a premium on presenting and not enough on substance and critical thinking.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Contrary to the Harvard Business School model of vocal leadership, the ranks of effective CEOs turn out to be filled with introverts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Brigham Young University management professor Bradley Agle studied the CEOs of 128 major companies and found that those considered charismatic by their top executives had bigger salaries but not better corporate performance.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Many of the best-performing companies of the late twentieth century were run by what he calls &amp;ldquo;Level 5 Leaders.&amp;rdquo; These exceptional CEOs were known not for their flash or charisma but for extreme humility coupled with intense professional will.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social media has made new forms of leadership possible for scores of people who don&amp;rsquo;t fit the Harvard Business School mold.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps social media affords us the control we lack in real life socializing: the screen as a barrier between us and the world. The same person who would never raise his hand in a lecture hall of two hundred people might blog to two thousand, or two million, without thinking twice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Introverts prefer to work independently, and solitude can be a catalyst to innovation&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are born and culturally endowed with certain personality traits-introversion, for example-but we can and do act out of character in the service of &amp;ldquo;core personal projects.&amp;rdquo; In other words, introverts are capable of acting like extroverts for the sake of work they consider important, people they love, or anything they value highly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we act out of character by convincing ourselves that our pseudo-self is real, we can eventually burn out without even knowing why.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Behavioral leakage, in which our true selves seep out via unconscious body language.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not always so easy, it turns out, to identify your core personal projects. And it can be especially tough for introverts, who have spent so much of their lives conforming to extroverted norms that by the time they choose a career, or a calling, it feels perfectly normal to ignore their own preferences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are three key steps to identifying your own core personal projects:
* First, think back to what you loved to do when you were a child.
* Second, pay attention to the work you gravitate to.
* Finally, pay attention to what you envy. &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But even if you&amp;rsquo;re stretching yourself in the service of a core personal project, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to act out of character too much, or for too long.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Create as many &lt;mark&gt;&amp;ldquo;restorative niches&amp;rdquo;&lt;/mark&gt; as possible in your daily life. &amp;ldquo;Restorative niche&amp;rdquo; is Professor Little&amp;rsquo;s term for the place you go when you want to return to your true self. It can be a physical place, like the path beside the Richelieu River, or a temporal one, like the quiet breaks you plan between sales calls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Will this job allow me to spend time on in-character activities?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Acting in character most of the time, effectively turns workdays into one giant restorative niche.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Free Trait Agreement acknowledges that we&amp;rsquo;ll each act out of character some of the time-in exchange for being ourselves the rest of the time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The person with whom you can best strike a Free Trait Agreement-after overcoming his or her resistance-is yourself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Double pneumonia and an overscheduled life can happen to anyone, of course, but for Little, it was the result of &lt;mark&gt;acting out of character for too long and without enough restorative niches&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prolonged acting out of character may also increase autonomic nervous system activity, which can, in turn, compromise immune functioning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It can be hard for extroverts to understand how badly introverts need to recharge at the end of a busy day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In sales there&amp;rsquo;s a truism that &amp;ldquo;we have two ears and one mouth&amp;rdquo; and we should use them proportionately.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What makes someone really good at selling or consulting-the number-one thing is they&amp;rsquo;ve got to really listen well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about socializing with everyone. Think quality over quantity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Solve problems, make art, think deeply.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Spend your free time the way you like, not the way you think you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Remember the dangers of the New Groupthink. If it&amp;rsquo;s creativity you&amp;rsquo;re after, ask your employees to solve problems alone before sharing their ideas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t mistake assertiveness or eloquence for good ideas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do We Work?</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/whywork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 16:48:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/whywork/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/whywork.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.swarthmore.edu/SocSci/bschwar1/&#34;&gt;Barry Schwartz&lt;/a&gt; questions the idea that people only work for pay and urges us to design work organizations that give people discretion and autonomy, and the chance to do meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can save yourself reading through pages and pages of empirical evidence and research notes, and go straight to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_the_way_we_think_about_work_is_broken?language=en&#34;&gt;author&amp;rsquo;s TED talk&lt;/a&gt; on the subject if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes:938663226f49485894bf15c3c52c2d69&#34;&gt;My highlights and notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Satisfied people do their work because they feel that they are in charge. Their workday offers them a measure of &lt;em&gt;autonomy and discretion&lt;/em&gt;. And they use that autonomy and discretion to achieve a level of mastery or expertise. They learn new things, developing both as workers and as people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gallup found that only 13 percent of workers feel engaged by their jobs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;The four characteristics of good work: challenge, engagement, meaning, and satisfaction. To this I would add &lt;strong&gt;autonomy and discretion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Job crafting is what Wrzesniewski and her colleagues called when we shape our jobs with the central purpose of our employer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To be satisfied with our work, we typically need a belief in the purpose of what we do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is people who see their work as a &amp;ldquo;calling&amp;rdquo; who find it most satisfying.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work &amp;lt; Career &amp;lt; Calling&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Take discretion, engagement, and meaning out of work and people feel less &amp;ldquo;called&amp;rdquo; to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Virtually any job has the potential to offer people satisfaction. It can be made meaningful by connecting them to the welfare of others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Factors that effective organizations have in common&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employment security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-managed teams and decentralized decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They pay more than the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They provide extensive training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t overmeasure employee performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They put great emphasis on the company mission.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In short, you take discretion, engagement, and meaning out of work and people get less satisfaction from doing it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When people are in states of positive emotion, they think expansively and creatively.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Carrots and sticks. What is striking is that, in the analysis that Pfeffer offers, both of these tools have negative effects on employee engagement and work satisfaction.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you create an environment in which workers are respected, they want to be there and they want to work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Carefully crafted incentive schemes, designed to ensure top performance, can often produce the opposite result.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social motives and financial ones compete. No incentives can ever be smart enough to substitute for people who do the right thing because it&amp;rsquo;s the right thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When we lose confidence that people have the will to do the right thing, and we turn to incentives, we find that we get what we pay for.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;watch where they walk, then pave it&amp;rdquo; metaphor argues that the empirical data shape the theories people develop. The &amp;ldquo;if you build it, they will come&amp;rdquo; metaphor argues that theories shape data. [The author] defends the second metaphor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work over which people exercise some discretion and control leads to cognitive flexibility and to an engaged orientation to self and society; in contrast, excessively monitored, oppressively supervised working conditions lead to distress.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People don&amp;rsquo;t think of themselves as primarily motivated by material incentives, but &lt;mark&gt;they think that pretty much everyone else is&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;French emperor Napoleon termed ideologues were so in love with ideas that they ignored empirical evidence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Better data and theories drive out worse ones, and progress is made. Why does this not happen in the case of theories about human nature?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Theories about human nature can actually produce changes in how people behave&lt;/mark&gt;. A theory that is false can become true simply by people believing it&amp;rsquo;s true.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Performance-oriented&lt;/strong&gt; vs. &lt;strong&gt;Mastery-oriented&lt;/strong&gt;: Performance-oriented people want to &lt;em&gt;prove&lt;/em&gt; their ability while mastery-oriented people want to &lt;em&gt;improve&lt;/em&gt; their ability.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So is intelligence fixed? Partly, that depends on whether you believe it&amp;rsquo;s fixed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unless there is a collective effort to combat this ideology, we will all become the lazy, selfish pursuers of self-interest, not just in work but in our lives as a whole, that at least some social scientists have assumed we always were. So the question becomes: What can we do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If we design workplaces that permit people to do work they value, we will be designing a human nature that values work&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The first step to taking responsibility over the structure of our workplace is to start asking questions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are the results of our transactions with customers positive sum, so that both sides leave the transaction better off?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We can demand of ourselves the effort to find the ways in which other people benefit if we do our jobs with enthusiasm rather than indifference.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Industrialization has been a spectacular human achievement. But as it has relieved material poverty, it has done so at the price of poverty of spirit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 3 Words for 2016</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, Chris Brogan started a yearly tradition: choosing the three words that would guide his actions for the next twelve months, and publishing them on his blog (you can read more about it on &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbrogan.com/3-words-2016/&#34;&gt;Chris&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this exercise to be extremely powerful, as it forces us to sit down and think long and hard about our priorities in life and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now sharing my Three Words for 2016: LEARN, EXPERIMENTS, SELF-AWARENESS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn&#34;&gt;Learn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will focus on expanding my competence in new areas of knowledge. It is all too easy to just focus on the day-to-day tasks you&amp;rsquo;ve been performing for years, get complacent and stop learning. That&amp;rsquo;s how you become obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dedicating 2015 to learn the basics of web development and being finally able to deploy a website from scratch, helped me understand how much I missed learning new things and the feeling of accomplishment that comes with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 I will double down on learning. A few things I want to learn: to operate a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_server&#34;&gt;VPS&lt;/a&gt;, improve my Portuguese, and get better at fixing things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experiments&#34;&gt;Experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to gravitate towards the same things over and over again: the same restaurants, the same kind of books, the same passtimes. I like predictablilty and reliability, which probably means that I&amp;rsquo;ve missed out on many good things for not experimenting enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 I will focus on trying new things in the spirit of continuous self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing Tim Ferriss, if you want opportunities to come to you, you must first throw a lot of things against the wall (experiment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guiding word also dovetails nicely with the first one (Learn) as they share many common themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-awareness&#34;&gt;Self-Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage it is crystal clear to me that as important as deciding what to do (or even more important) is to decide what &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By developing my career mostly in large corporations I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my working years living up to other people&amp;rsquo;s expectations: there is always a boss to please, employees to manage, politics to play. A few times I have also been required to play roles that were not in alignment with my core strengths and personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 and beyond I&amp;rsquo;m going to do less of what other people expect of me, and more of the things that allow me to leverage my strengths and get me closer to my overarching life goals. I&amp;rsquo;m going to &amp;ldquo;trust my gut&amp;rdquo;: if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right, I won&amp;rsquo;t do it. No more painting by (other people&amp;rsquo;s) numbers. Life is too short.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>