<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 11:17:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mariosanchez.org/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Useful Habits for the Digital Age</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/7newhabits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 11:17:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/7newhabits/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Covey wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1THjXoz&#34;&gt;7 Habits Of Highly Effective People&lt;/a&gt; in 1989. Since then, many authors have expanded the conversation by adding their own seven habits for success, effectiveness, happiness or whatever end goal they may be pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next few paragraphs, I will distill the seven most important habits that, in my opinion, are esential to successfully navigate the waters of the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-know-what-you-want:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;1. Know What You Want&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds easy but, more often than not, people &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t know what they want&lt;/a&gt;. Passion or purpose is not something that hits us in the head while we&amp;rsquo;re sitting down waiting for it. &lt;strong&gt;We need to get out and find it&lt;/strong&gt;. The best way is to try many different things (go wide) until something sticks. It must be something that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind doing even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bring you money. Once you find it, you then need to focus (go deep), learn everything you can, and strive to &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1XHLESW&#34;&gt;become the best&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-be-different:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;2. Be Different&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to find your &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcompany.com/28905/brand-called-you&#34;&gt;personal brand&lt;/a&gt;. Merely being competent or very good is not enough. You need to be different. Find the quality or qualities that make you different than your peers and competitors. You can be the details guy, or the people-person gal, or the guy who is always trying out new things, but by all means find something that makes you stand out. &lt;strong&gt;Approach your craft from an angle that others can&amp;rsquo;t or won&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt;. Narrow your niche as much as you profitably can so that you can claim the top spot.  Seth Godin wrote about this more than a decade ago in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Vpd5ki&#34;&gt;Purple Cow&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, pick it up. It&amp;rsquo;s a short read and well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-spend-less-than-you-make:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;3. Spend Less Than You Make&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing will widen the gap between you and your dreams more than debt. Avoid it like the plague. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, really: &lt;strong&gt;spend less than you make&lt;/strong&gt;. This may seem hard in a society like ours, where we are bombarded every day with &amp;ldquo;buy now, pay later&amp;rdquo; marketing messages, but if you stick to it suddenly it will become a habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-save-a-lot-of-money:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;4. Save a Lot of Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Those who say that money is not important either have too much or don&amp;rsquo;t have any&lt;/strong&gt;. Money gives you flexibility and freedom. Accumulating a big chunk of cash means that you will never have to do &lt;a href=&#34;https://thebillfold.com/a-story-of-a-fuck-off-fund-648401263659#.bhrdyqcf7&#34;&gt;something you don&amp;rsquo;t want to&lt;/a&gt; because you need the money. The car broke down? Want to take that class? Want to go on that trip? Want to splurge on something really important to you? No problem, you&amp;rsquo;ve prepared for it. Just write a check. For more on this I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1TQ0BQt&#34;&gt;Ramit Sethi&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-learn-to-be-uncomfortable:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;5. Learn To Be Uncomfortable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be free you have to &lt;strong&gt;learn to live like a college student&lt;/strong&gt;. Get used to sleeping on couches, drinking tap water, catching the bus, taking cold showers, eating simple meals, using your local library, buying used stuff, etc. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to do all these things all the time, but knowing that you can do them and still be OK will give you an edge: when you know that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a lot to live well and that you can always go somewhere else, well&amp;hellip;&lt;strong&gt;you have the power&lt;/strong&gt;. For more on this I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1XHMBuE&#34;&gt;Mark Cuban&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt;, especially the chapters that describe how he started out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-lighten-your-load:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;6. Lighten Your Load&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being rich in the digital age means something completely different than twenty years ago. Back then, being rich meant owning things: the McMansion, the expensive car, the boat, the fancy jewelery, the corner office, etc. All that is bullshit now. These days &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re considered rich when you have time, freedom, mobility and cool experiences&lt;/strong&gt;. The sharing economy has given us access to practically anything without the burden of ownership. Forget the vacation home: book an Airbnb. Thinking of buying a car? Unless you live in a sprawling city with no public transportation you don&amp;rsquo;t need to: take the train, hail an Uber or ride a bike. Corner office? Please&amp;hellip; just work out of a coffee shop or your local library. Hold on to your money (see #4) and donate/throw away the things you don&amp;rsquo;t use that are weighing you down. The ultimate aim is to fit everything you own in a carry-on bag. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.becomingminimalist.com/millennials/&#34;&gt;Be flexible. Be mobile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-always-be-learning:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;7. Always Be Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think that you&amp;rsquo;re safe because you have a college degree, think again. &lt;strong&gt;Technology and the digital revolution are completely redefining professions&lt;/strong&gt; to the point that they would be unrecognizeable to somebody who has spent the last ten years in a desert island. If you have any doubts, just ask &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@knightfdn/10-basics-today-s-journalists-need-562df8787406#.bzsocpbmk&#34;&gt;journalists&lt;/a&gt;, marketers, customer service representatives, taxi drivers, and other professionals whose lives have been disrupted by technology and globalization. The good news is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/onlineed/&#34;&gt;learning new things online&lt;/a&gt; for free or very little money is now easier than ever. You just need to have drive and curiosity. For older folks, another piece of advice: surround yourself with young people. The future is no longer being shaped by politicians or captains of industry, but by laptop-toting, tech-savvy twenty-somethings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-summary:b6c7a23b65051c4e5f37e9bb19ff35d1&#34;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know what you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend less than you make&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save a lot of money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to be uncomfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighten your load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always be learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7210/6812971608_30001b913a_h.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;small&#34;&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jodimichelle/6812971608/&#34;&gt;jodimichelle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before You Sharpen That Axe</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 21:05:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/axe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people don&amp;rsquo;t fail because they don&amp;rsquo;t have enough money or plans, but because they don&amp;rsquo;t know what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what you want is hard, that&amp;rsquo;s why so few people engage in it. It is easier to just start doing things, like answering email or running errands: they keep us busy and give us the illusion of making progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding what we really want, though, is the first step before starting a project, launching a career or designing a life plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with this quote attributed to Abraham Lincoln: &amp;ldquo;give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening my axe&amp;rdquo;. It underscores the importance of preparation before execution. Figuring out what we want comes first, though, so &lt;mark&gt;before you sharpen that axe make sure that chopping down a tree is what you really want to do&lt;/mark&gt;. Perhaps what you really want is to plant a tree instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose first, preparation and execution second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the subject I recommend watching Simon Sinek&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action?language=en&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start With Why&amp;rdquo; Ted talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/tree.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/peter_from_wellington/15701759174/&#34;&gt;Peter Kurdulija&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 3 Words for 2016</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, Chris Brogan started a yearly tradition: choosing the three words that would guide his actions for the next twelve months, and publishing them on his blog (you can read more about it on &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbrogan.com/3-words-2016/&#34;&gt;Chris&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this exercise to be extremely powerful, as it forces us to sit down and think long and hard about our priorities in life and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now sharing my Three Words for 2016: LEARN, EXPERIMENTS, SELF-AWARENESS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Learn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will focus on expanding my competence in new areas of knowledge. It is all too easy to just focus on the day-to-day tasks you&amp;rsquo;ve been performing for years, get complacent and stop learning. That&amp;rsquo;s how you become obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dedicating 2015 to learn the basics of web development and being finally able to deploy a website from scratch, helped me understand how much I missed learning new things and the feeling of accomplishment that comes with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 I will double down on learning. A few things I want to learn: to operate a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_server&#34;&gt;VPS&lt;/a&gt;, improve my Portuguese, and get better at fixing things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experiments:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to gravitate towards the same things over and over again: the same restaurants, the same kind of books, the same passtimes. I like predictablilty and reliability, which probably means that I&amp;rsquo;ve missed out on many good things for not experimenting enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 I will focus on trying new things in the spirit of continuous self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing Tim Ferriss, if you want opportunities to come to you, you must first throw a lot of things against the wall (experiment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guiding word also dovetails nicely with the first one (Learn) as they share many common themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-awareness:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Self-Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage it is crystal clear to me that as important as deciding what to do (or even more important) is to decide what &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By developing my career mostly in large corporations I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my working years living up to other people&amp;rsquo;s expectations: there is always a boss to please, employees to manage, politics to play. A few times I have also been required to play roles that were not in alignment with my core strengths and personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 and beyond I&amp;rsquo;m going to do less of what other people expect of me, and more of the things that allow me to leverage my strengths and get me closer to my overarching life goals. I&amp;rsquo;m going to &amp;ldquo;trust my gut&amp;rdquo;: if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right, I won&amp;rsquo;t do it. No more painting by (other people&amp;rsquo;s) numbers. Life is too short.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 6S Discipline</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/6s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/6s/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, the company moved us to a new office. When we walked into our shiny, new cubicles we found a single sheet of paper laid out on top of our recently installed, empty desks describing something called &amp;ldquo;The 6S Discipline&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a concise list of 6 bullet points that summarized a process to keep our work stations clean and organized. I later found out that the 6S concept comes from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_manufacturing&#34;&gt;Lean Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt; philosophy, the principles of which can also be applied to an office setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I have always liked to keep my workplace neatly organized and keep around only the things I need at one particular moment, the 6S concept strongly resonated with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about the 6S philosophy, you can read this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vitalentusa.com/learn/An_Introduction_to_6S.pdf&#34;&gt;comprehensive 6S overview&lt;/a&gt; I found searching online. On the other hand, if you just want to grasp the gist of it, here are the 6S principles in short form, just like in the page I found on my desk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sort:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Sort&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sort out necessary and unnecessary items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep only items necessary to perform the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove and discard the items not required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-in-order:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Set In Order&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organize the essential materials in the workplace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find &amp;ldquo;a place for everything and keep everything in its place&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shine:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Shine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep the area clean at all times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;standardize:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Standardize&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain the Sort, Set In Order, and Shine Steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sustain:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Sustain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain the gain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for ways to continuously improve your work area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;safety-first:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Safety First&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an accident-free workplace. Eliminate hazards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, 6S is about &lt;mark&gt;eliminating waste and maximizing value-adding activities&lt;/mark&gt;, by creating and maintaining an organized, clean, safe and efficient work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/4/3548/3389551970_a24a14b9ba_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/cocokelley/3389551970&#34;&gt;Cassandra Lavalle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Building Blocks of Success</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/success/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of checklists, and some time ago I developed this list of what I believe are the building blocks of success. They are divided in five big buckets: &lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Self&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Credentials&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Memberships&lt;/strong&gt;. There could be others, but this is a good starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting into the habit of reviewing this list frequently and asking: what are you doing today to nurture and strengthen each of these building blocks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Family&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heroes/Role Models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advisors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service Providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stocks/Bonds/Mutual Funds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stock Options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;401K/IRAs Retirement Accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real Estate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tablet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Professional Equipment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lines of Credit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credit Cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Assets (domain, website, profiles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corporations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processes/Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Royalties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self&#34;&gt;Self&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style/Image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Habits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals and Objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Branding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management Style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personality Profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;credentials&#34;&gt;Credentials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Degrees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testimonials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Letters of Recommendation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credit Score&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Licenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Driver License&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;memberships&#34;&gt;Memberships&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alumni Associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student Associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Political Affiliations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religious Organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community Organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastermind Groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional Organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequent Flyer Programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clubs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Build a Brand</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/brand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/brand/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the paragraphs below I am outlining a basic roadmap you can follow to build your small business brand. You will still have to put out a lot of work, but it will help you clarify the process and ask better questions along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-a-brand-do:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;What Does a Brand Do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are as many definitions of brand as there are branding experts. However, there is probably just one thing you need to remember: a brand helps us say something about ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, people who drive Toyota Prius. What do you think they&amp;rsquo;re trying to communicate? Would it be, perhaps, that they care about the environment? The role of the brand (Prius) is to help them tell that story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crave association with brands that help us tell the story we want to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-product:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Your Product&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, your product needs to be something you need or use. This will give you the ability to see things from your customers&amp;rsquo; perspective. It is no coincidence that so many entrepreneurs find success after creating a product they themselves need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t actively use or need the product you sell, then make sure that at least you&amp;rsquo;re deeply interested in it, so that you won&amp;rsquo;t mind researching, learning and doing what it takes to become an expert as you go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-target-market:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Your Target Market&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to find customers who need the product you&amp;rsquo;re offering. You do this by segmenting the market. In the end, you should be able to pinpoint a market niche that you can serve and dominate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to segment the market: by geography, by demographics, by psychographics, by behavior, etc. Without getting too technical, we will just list as many ways to segment the market as we can think of, so you can select the combination that best works for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place of residence (country, state, region, city, neighbourhood, postal code)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Age&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occupation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethnicity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nationality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marital status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Household size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life cycle stage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Political Affiliation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religious preference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entertainment preferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interests/hobbies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opinions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attitudes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purchasing habits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price sensitivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purchase likelihood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usage frequency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purchase process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you may decide to target young dads, between 30 and 40 years old, making between $80K and $150K a year, who have a graduate degree, live in South Florida, play tennis over the weekend, don&amp;rsquo;t have much discretionary time and want to take their game to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an exercise, can you break down the categories above even further?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-competition:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Your Competition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far you have a product and a target customer. Things are definitely moving in the right direction, but there&amp;rsquo;s one more thing you need to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if somebody is already in that space?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competition is not necessarily a bad thing: it means there is a market for what you want to sell. At the same time it means that you need to find a way to differentiate yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you bring to the table that your competitors can&amp;rsquo;t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three ways you can differentiate yourself: offer more than your competition, offer less, and have a point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at these three options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;differentiator-1-offering-more:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Differentiator #1: Offering More&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Availability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun Factor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convenience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After Sale Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just some of the areas you can analyze. Can you think of others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;differentiator-2-offering-less:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Differentiator #2: Offering Less&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default approach to differentiation is usually to pile up more features to outdo the competition. However, more features don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean a better product. Introducing features to one-up the competition can lead to feature creep. Products become confusing and brands lose their identity in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers like clarity. Just focus on a few important features and don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to eliminate the rest. Simplicity can be the most powerful competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep iterating until you&amp;rsquo;ve found your unique point of differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;differentiator-3-your-pov-point-of-view:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Differentiator #3: Your POV (Point of View)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features and benefits don&amp;rsquo;t create powerful USPs (unique selling propositions) any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What differentiates a brand in today&amp;rsquo;s competitive environment is its &lt;strong&gt;Point of View&lt;/strong&gt;. This is clearly explained in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action.html&#34;&gt;Simon Sinek&amp;rsquo;s Golden Circles theory&lt;/a&gt;, which he introduced in one of the most viewed TED talks of all time. The gist of his presentation is this: &lt;strong&gt;People don&amp;rsquo;t buy what you do: they buy WHY you do it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WHY is your Point of View.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-it-profitable:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Is it Profitable?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now you should already have a clearly differentiated position, but since to get there you may have had to further narrow your target market, you need to determine if that market is still big enough to make a profit. To know for sure you may need to run some market tests and pilot runs. If they show promise then you have found your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, testing a market is now easier than ever thanks to Internet platforms like eBay, Amazon, Craigslist, Etsy, eLance, to name some of the most well known ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed reading so far, building a brand is not easy. It is not a linear process. There is no exact sequence of steps: most of the time you will need to work on different variables (your product, your competition, your customers) at the same time, and make frequent reassessments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why the process requires more than just sitting in front of a computer. You may need to lay down charts, note cards or props on a large table, stick color Post-It notes on a wall or make heavy use of a whiteboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also want to involve other people: business associates, suppliers, potential customers, consultants and mentors (people who can give you feedback).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building your brand remember the words of Abraham Lincoln: &amp;lsquo;Give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening the axe.&amp;rsquo; It is better to spend more time getting your brand right before you launch than attempt to change course when your brand is already out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;communicating-your-brand:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Communicating Your Brand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have already defined your brand. Now you need to communicate what your brand is all about. To do so, you need to develop and articulate a few important concepts that we&amp;rsquo;ll explain in the next few paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vision:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Vision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vision is where you want to take your brand. It is your chief aim. It is an ideal place in the future where you would like your brand to be. It is the way you ultimately want your brand to be perceived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mission is what you do every day. It is your brand&amp;rsquo;s purpose besides making money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An effective mission statement has to be customer-centric. Words like &amp;lsquo;maximize shareholder value&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;constant profitable growth&amp;rsquo; don&amp;rsquo;t belong on a mission statement. They are financial objectives. They are important, certainly, but they should come as a &lt;em&gt;consequence&lt;/em&gt; of having (and executing on) a customer-centered mission .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your mission needs to be articulated as simply and as clearly as possible, so that &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt; can understand it. Paraphrasing Albert Einstein, if you can&amp;rsquo;t explain it to a six year old it is not clear enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good example of a clear mission statement is Walmart&amp;rsquo;s: &amp;lsquo;To save you money so you can live better.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slogan:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Slogan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A slogan is a short sentence that distills either your mission or you brand&amp;rsquo;s most important differentiation point. Since your slogan will be used in your marketing and promotional campaigns it has to be worded in terms that your target customer will understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;name:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brand name is your most important brand signal. Choose a name that communicates something about your brand and shows some personality (and by all means, stay away from acronyms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the HVLP Fan Company, a Kentucky-based fan manufacturer, saw sales and brand awareness soar after they changed their name to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bigassfans.com&#34;&gt;Big Ass Fans&lt;/a&gt;, a nod to customers who kept referring to the company&amp;rsquo;s large industrial units as &amp;lsquo;big ass&amp;rsquo; fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you don&amp;rsquo;t have to get that quirky, but being original certainly helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;logo:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Logo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A logo does not &amp;lsquo;make&amp;rsquo; your brand. A logo is a symbol that represents your brand. A good logo takes something that customers associate with your brand and distills it in the simplest graphic form possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of a good logo is National Geograhic&amp;rsquo;s. It is just a simple yellow rectangle that evoques the yellow frame around the printed magazine&amp;rsquo;s impactful cover images (one of the most remembered and loved features of the National Geographic brand.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you design your logo aim for that same degree of simplicity. Think about how can your logo make a meaningful connection to your brand, and how you can make it as simple as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important consideration, too: the simpler the logo, the better it will render in different surfaces and materials. This is especially important in marketing and promotional vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;packaging:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Packaging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have a limited marketing budget, you may want to leverage your packaging to double up as marketing material. If you have a physical product, invest in the best, most professional package you can afford. A good package can make all the difference at the point of sale, where customers ultimately make their buying decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;price:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Price&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price is a proxy for value. Bear in mind that not everybody has time for lengthy features and benefits comparisons, so price will be used as good indicator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When setting your price it is better to aim higher, while at the same time making sure that your brand delivers much more value than the premium you&amp;rsquo;re charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing is a complex subject so you may want to read up more about it (I find &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seobook.com/getting-your-pricing-right&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; to be an excellent introduction to the subject of pricing, in case you want to dig deeper).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;domain-name:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Domain Name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your domain name (also referred to as your web address or URL) needs to be chosen at the same time as your brand name. This is important because most good domains are taken and your brand name &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be part of your domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, register a domain with a .com extension. If your company is a non-profit you can use a .org extension. If you don&amp;rsquo;t find a good domain with those extensions there are other ones that have become popular like .co and .io (however, they might be more expensive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you with search engines you may also want to include in your domain name the kind of product or service you offer (for example: CollinsPlumbing.com instead of just Collins.com). A word of caution, though: you need to think long term because if you plan to introduce other products or services in the future you don&amp;rsquo;t want to limit yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your aim should be to find a domain name that includes your brand name, is descriptive enough, and not too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;website:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you needed to choose one, and only one marketing vehicle for your small business brand it would be a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good website can accomplish many things for you: it can be an information hub, a customer service vehicle, a marketing tool, a way to engage in conversations with your customers, a starting point to building a mailing list, and even a distribution channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that your site renders correctly in different browsers and resolutions (especially in tablets and mobile phones, since every day more people use them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make your site display correctly in any device it needs to be built using a technique called &lt;em&gt;responsive web design&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, sites that are built with responsive web design automatically recognize what kind of device is being used to access them, and display the site version that best fits the resolution of that particular device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that the person who designs your website knows about responsive web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blog:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding a blog to your site is a good way to show your expertise and build trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to host your blog in your own domain or sub-domain. Otherwise, you will be at the mercy of whoever owns the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than setting your blog at the root of your domain &lt;em&gt;yoursite.com&lt;/em&gt; it is good practice to deploy it in a sub-domain, like &lt;em&gt;blog.yourdomain.com&lt;/em&gt; or a folder, like &lt;em&gt;yourdomain.com/blog&lt;/em&gt;. The reason why a blog shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be deployed at the root is because the root must be reserved for the main page of your site, which should give a comprehensive view of your brand, your company, your products and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good blogging platform option is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordpress.org&#34;&gt;Wordpress.org&lt;/a&gt;, since it lets you use your own domain AND host the software with the web host of your choice (you can find a good tutorial on how to install a Wordpress blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theminimalists.com/how-to-set-up-a-wordpress-blog/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other popular platforms, like Tumblr for example, will let you use your own domain, but your blog will be hosted at Tumblr&amp;rsquo;s web servers, not your web host, which is not an ideal set-up for a serious business blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A word of caution, though. Don&amp;rsquo;t expect your blog to be a sales tool. Although it will help you sell more, a blog is primarily a trust-building mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;email-newsletter:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Email Newsletter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A regular email newsletter, sent to readers who have opted in and want to receive it, is one of the most powerful marketing tools you can use. After all, most people read their email every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike social media, email is still very personal. When somebody opts into your mailing list and gives you their email address it&amp;rsquo;s like you&amp;rsquo;re being invited to that person&amp;rsquo;s home. You must correspond to that trust by delivering extremely high quality content and making your readers feel like they&amp;rsquo;re part of an exclusive club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create and manage a newsletter through services like &lt;a href=&#34;http://mailchimp.com&#34;&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;, or if you prefer a more simple, minimalistic option you can use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tinyletter.com&#34;&gt;Tinyletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leveraging-your-brand:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Leveraging Your Brand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brand must mean something extremely clear to a very targeted group of people before you can consider taking it to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you need to resist the temptation of doing too many things with your brand too soon, like defining your target market too broadly under the misled assumption that not doing so may cause you to &amp;lsquo;lose business&amp;rsquo;. More often than not, the opposite is true: if you aim at everything and everybody you won&amp;rsquo;t mean anything to anybody, and you will dilute or even destroy your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with something very targeted and then, once you have consolidated your position, think about what else you can offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-products-for-your-customers:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Creating Products for Your Customers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your best customers for your new offerings will be your existing customers. Once you become successful with your brand you will have the privilege of finding products for your customers instead of having to find customers for your products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;line-extensions:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Line Extensions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a good idea to create different products at different price levels, since not everybody will be able to afford your best, most expensive products. You may want to start new customers off with a relatively low cost option so that they can get familiar with your brand, and then move them up to more sophisticated products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend focusing on three different price levels: Good, Better, and Best. By limiting choice to a few, well differentiated options, you eliminate confusion and make the purchasing decision easier. Think of how Spanish wine makers market their wine: they adhere to just three standard denominations based on the quality of the grapes and the timeframe of the aging process: Crianza (Good), Reserva (Better) and Gran Reserva (Best). Simple, and it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;brand-partnerships:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Brand Partnerships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partnerships are a great brand building technique especially when your brand is new. By associating your brand to another one in a non-competitive sector you will essentially leverage that brand&amp;rsquo;s attributes in your favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think how car manufacturers partner with luxury brands to create premium versions of their models. Recently, for example, Fiat partnered with Italian luxury goods brand Gucci to offer a version of its successful Fiat 500 in Gucci trim, making it easier to tie their car to the concept of Italian style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;brand-extensions:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Brand Extensions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brand extensions happen when you take your brand into new product categories. For brand extensions to be successful there must be some kind of synergy between the core category and the new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, it&amp;rsquo;s not much of a stretch for a brand like BMW to go from cars to motorcycles. That brand extension feels natural and credible. Another good brand extension could be a brand of pasta that branches out into pasta sauces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;licensing:09d8fdd3fac986096e1c7cce196b77af&#34;&gt;Licensing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Licensing is probably the most powerful way to leverage your brand. It occurs when you aim your brand at entirely new businesses and distribution channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a clothing manufacturer with good penetration in department stores may license a brand like Jeep to develop a line of rugged outdoor clothes. Jeep, in exchange, will receive a royalty and access to a completely different distribution channel, without essentially doing anything and with very low risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Licensing will only work, though, when your brand is already well established in the marketplace, and when what it stands for is already widely and easily understood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam&#39;s Rules for Building a Business</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/sams-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/sams-rules/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, during a trip to Bentonville, Arkansas, I had the chance to visit Walmart&amp;#8217;s first store (originally called Walton&amp;#8217;s 5-10), and picked up a leaflet containing Sam Walton&amp;#8217;s 10 rules for building a successful business. Pearls of wisdom, straight from the man who built the world&amp;#8217;s most successful retailer out of nothing. Since I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find a link to it on the Internet, I am transcribing them below (all of them are great, but I especially like #7, #9 and #10):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-1-commit-to-your-business:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 1: Commit to your business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe in it more than anybody else. I think I overcame every single one of my personal shortcomings by the sheer passion I brought to my work. I don&amp;#8217;t know if you&amp;#8217;re born with this kind of passion, or if you can learn it. But I do know you need it. If you love your work, you&amp;#8217;ll be out there every day trying to do it the best you possibly can, and pretty soon everybody around will catch the passion from you &amp;mdash; like a fever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-2-share-your-profits-with-all-your-associates-and-treat-them-as-partners:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 2: Share your profits with all your associates, and treat them as partners&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In turn, they will treat you as a partner, and together you will all perform beyond your wildest expectations. Remain a corporation and retain control if you like, but behave as a servant leader in your partnership. Encourage your associates to hold a stake in the company. Offer discounted stock, and grant them stock for their retirement. It&amp;#8217;s the single best thing we ever did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-3-motivate-your-partners:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 3: Motivate your partners&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money and ownership alone aren&amp;#8217;t enough. Constantly, day by day, think of new and more interesting ways to motivate and challenge your partners. Set high goals, encourage competition, and then keep score. Make bets with outrageous payoffs. If things get stale, cross-pollinate; have managers switch jobs with one another to stay challenged. Keep everybody guessing as to what your next trick is going to be. Don&amp;#8217;t become too predictable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-4-communicate-everything-you-possibly-can-to-your-partners:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 4: Communicate everything you possibly can to your partners&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more they know, the more they&amp;#8217;ll understand. The more they understand, the more they&amp;#8217;ll care. Once they care, there&amp;#8217;s no stopping them. If you don&amp;#8217;t trust your associates to know what&amp;#8217;s going on, they&amp;#8217;ll know you really don&amp;#8217;t consider them partners. Information is power, and the gain you get from empowering your associates more than offsets the risk of informing your competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-5-appreciate-everything-your-associates-do-for-the-business:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 5: Appreciate everything your associates do for the business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A paycheck and a stock option will buy one kind of loyalty. But all of us like to be told how much somebody appreciates what we do for them. We like to hear it often, and especially when we have done something we&amp;#8217;re really proud of. Nothing else can quite substitute for a few well-chosen, well-timed, sincere words of praise. They&amp;#8217;re absolutely free &amp;mdash; and worth a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-6-celebrate-your-success:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 6: Celebrate your success&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find some humor in your failures. Don&amp;#8217;t take yourself so seriously. Loosen up, and everybody around you will loosen up. Have fun. Show enthusiasm &amp;mdash; always. When all else fails, put on a costume and sing a silly song. Then make everybody else sing with you. Don&amp;#8217;t do a hula on Wall Street. It&amp;#8217;s been done. Think up your own stunt. All of this is more important, and more fun, than you think, and it really fools competition. &amp;#8220;Why should we take those cornballs at Wal-Mart seriously?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-7-listen-to-everyone-in-your-company-and-figure-out-ways-to-get-them-talking:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 7: Listen to everyone in your company and figure out ways to get them talking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The folks on the front lines &amp;mdash; the ones who actually talk to the customer &amp;mdash; are the only ones who really know what&amp;#8217;s going on out there. You&amp;#8217;d better find out what they know. This really is what total quality is all about. To push responsibility down in your organization, and to force good ideas to bubble up within it, you must listen to what your associates are trying to tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-8-exceed-your-customer-8217-s-expectations:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 8: Exceed your customer&amp;#8217;s expectations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do, they&amp;#8217;ll come back over and over. Give them what they want &amp;mdash; and a little more. Let them know you appreciate them. Make good on all your mistakes, and don&amp;#8217;t make excuses &amp;mdash; apologize. Stand behind everything you do. The two most important words I ever wrote were on that first Wal-Mart sign: &amp;#8220;Satisfaction Guaranteed.&amp;#8221; They&amp;#8217;re still up there, and they have made all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-9-control-your-expenses-better-than-your-competition:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 9: Control your expenses better than your competition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where you can always find the competitive advantage. For twenty-five years running &amp;mdash; long before Wal-Mart was known as the nation&amp;#8217;s largest retailer &amp;mdash; we&amp;#8217;ve ranked No. 1 in our industry for the lowest ratio of expenses to sales. You can make a lot of different mistakes and still recover if you run an efficient operation. Or you can be brilliant and still go out of business if you&amp;#8217;re too inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rule-10-swim-upstream:5cd272a68276fbd4f74ed5050ec995e5&#34;&gt;Rule 10: Swim upstream&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go the other way. Ignore the conventional wisdom. If everybody else is doing it one way, there&amp;#8217;s a good chance you can find your niche by going in exactly the opposite direction. But be prepared for a lot of folks to wave you down and tell you you&amp;#8217;re headed the wrong way. I guess in all my years, what I heard more often than anything was: a town of less than 50,000 population cannot support a discount store for very long.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tu Marca Personal</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/marca-personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/marca-personal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mucho se ha escrito sobre el concepto de marca personal. A juzgar por gran parte del material que se puede encontrar en Internet, podr&amp;iacute;a pensarse que se trata de un concepto superficial y fr&amp;iacute;volo. Por ello, en los p&amp;aacute;rrafos que siguen intentare plasmar mi opini&amp;oacute;n sobre el tema y explicar por que es importante.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-poco-de-historia:1e5203f9d6f3f6af0248e56ec6ce10e8&#34;&gt;Un Poco de Historia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El concepto de &lt;strong&gt;branding personal&lt;/strong&gt; no es nuevo. Existi&amp;oacute; siempre, aunque muchas veces confundido entre conceptos parecidos, como reputaci&amp;oacute;n, experiencia y personalidad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fue el autor norteamericano Tom Peters en su ya cl&amp;aacute;sico art&amp;iacute;culo &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcompany.com%2Fmagazine%2F10%2Fbrandyou.html&#34;&gt;The Brand Called You&lt;/a&gt; (aparecido en la revista Fast Company en Agosto de 1997) el primero en definirlo formalmente.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En su art&amp;iacute;culo, Peters afirma que la &amp;uacute;nica manera de lograr diferenciarnos como profesionales en un mundo cada vez m&amp;aacute;s competitivo es manejando nuestra carrera como las grandes empresas manejan las marcas de sus productos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;qu-es-el-branding-personal:1e5203f9d6f3f6af0248e56ec6ce10e8&#34;&gt;&amp;iquest;Qu&amp;eacute; es el Branding Personal?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branding personal es el &lt;strong&gt;proceso de definir con precisi&amp;oacute;n qu&amp;eacute; nos hace diferentes, de especificar como esa diferencia se traduce en un beneficio relevante para nuestra clientela o audiencia, y de comunicar ese beneficio de manera clara, concisa y efectiva.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El branding personal nos permite romper el paradigma tradicional de tener que adaptarnos a las diferentes oportunidades que se nos presentan (ll&amp;aacute;mese un empleo o un proyecto), y nos da la pauta para saber si esas oportunidades son realmente compatibles con nosotros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Un proceso de branding personal bien ejecutado har&amp;aacute; que las oportunidades correctas &lt;strong&gt;vengan a nosotros&lt;/strong&gt; en lugar de nosotros tener que perseguirlas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El branding personal implica tambi&amp;eacute;n actuar con una visi&amp;oacute;n a largo plazo. No podemos reinventarnos todos los d&amp;iacute;as. Cada una de nuestras acciones contribuye a que acumulemos (o perdamos) brand equity, y sus consecuencias se dejar&amp;aacute;n sentir por mucho tiempo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;en-favor-del-branding-personal:1e5203f9d6f3f6af0248e56ec6ce10e8&#34;&gt;En Favor del Branding Personal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hay quienes dicen que el branding personal es un enfoque simplista que ignora la complejidad de nuestra condici&amp;oacute;n humana y nos reduce a la categor&amp;iacute;a de objetos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nada podr&amp;iacute;a estar m&amp;aacute;s lejos de la realidad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esa complejidad, mezcla &amp;uacute;nica de nuestros &lt;strong&gt;talentos, valores, relaciones, experiencias y preferencias personales&lt;/strong&gt; es precisamente lo que nos hace diferentes. No se trata entonces de ignorar nuestra complejidad, sino de definirla de tal manera que nos ayude a comunicar el valor que solamente nosotros podemos ofrecer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No asumir la responsabilidad de construir nuestra marca personal es dejar que se nos defina a trav&amp;eacute;s de descripciones de trabajo gen&amp;eacute;ricas e impersonales, y que nos convirtamos en &lt;em&gt;commodities&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comunicando-tu-marca-personal:1e5203f9d6f3f6af0248e56ec6ce10e8&#34;&gt;Comunicando Tu Marca Personal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Las mejores marcas personales son capaces de comunicar lo que representan en muy pocas palabras. Un ejemplo es el candidato (y hoy presidente de los Estados Unidos) Barack Obama quien logr&amp;oacute; definirse con una sola palabra: Cambio (Change).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una manera efectiva de comunicar tu marca personal es a trav&amp;eacute;s de una &lt;strong&gt;declaraci&amp;oacute;n de misi&amp;oacute;n&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrariamente a lo que ocurre en el mundo corporativo, donde la declaraci&amp;oacute;n de misi&amp;oacute;n es por lo general una insulsa colecci&amp;oacute;n de cliches acu&amp;ntilde;ados por alg&amp;uacute;n gur&amp;uacute; de moda, la declaraci&amp;oacute;n de misi&amp;oacute;n puede ser una herramienta muy &amp;uacute;til si se redacta con pocas palabras simples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Por ejemplo &#34;lograr que de cada dos alumnos uno vaya a la universidad&#34; es una declaraci&amp;oacute;n de misi&amp;oacute;n mucho m&amp;aacute;s poderosa que &#34;sinergizar esfuerzos para que mediante el uso de tecnolog&amp;iacute;a de punta maximicemos el potencial intr&amp;iacute;nseco del educando&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otra herramienta muy &amp;uacute;til es la llamada &lt;strong&gt;frase de elevador&lt;/strong&gt;, una especie de comercial para tu marca personal que debes poder exponer en alrededor de 15 segundos. Con esta corta frase debes poder presentarte (dar tu nombre); explicar a que te dedicas; cual es el valor de lo que ofreces o que te hace especial y diferente; y sugerir un pr&amp;oacute;ximo paso (que podr&amp;iacute;a ser simplemente la manera de comunicarse contigo).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es &amp;uacute;til tambi&amp;eacute;n confeccionar una lista de tres a cinco adjetivos que te definan. &amp;iquest;Qu&amp;eacute; palabras quisieras que vengan autom&amp;aacute;ticamente a la mente de todos aquellos que escuchan tu nombre? Piensa en adjetivos con connotaciones positivas y que establezcan una diferencia importante.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;m-s-all-del-curriculum-vitae:1e5203f9d6f3f6af0248e56ec6ce10e8&#34;&gt;M&amp;aacute;s All&amp;aacute; del Curriculum Vitae&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si bien todav&amp;iacute;a es necesario, el curriculum vitae ya no es suficiente. En estas &amp;eacute;pocas, una estrategia de branding personal que no aproveche las poderosas herramientas que nos brinda la Internet est&amp;aacute; condenada al fracaso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoy, si no est&amp;aacute;s en Google no existes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;65% de los usuarios de Internet conf&amp;iacute;an en un &lt;strong&gt;motor de b&amp;uacute;squeda&lt;/strong&gt; para conseguir la informaci&amp;oacute;n deseada: &amp;iquest;Qu&amp;eacute; encontrar&amp;aacute;n cuando escriban tu nombre? &amp;iquest;Qu&amp;eacute; encontrar&amp;aacute;n cuando escriban tu especialidad y tu ciudad? &amp;iquest;Te encontrar&amp;aacute;n, o encontrar&amp;aacute;n a tus competidores?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si bien hay muchas maneras de influenciar &amp;eacute;ticamente los resultados de un motor de b&amp;uacute;squeda, una de las m&amp;aacute;s comunes es registrar tu dominio y crear una crear una p&amp;aacute;gina web sencilla. Tambi&amp;eacute;n es muy efectivo llenar perfiles en las principales redes sociales, y llenar un perfil en Google. Estos perfiles tienden a ser muy bien catalogados por los motores de b&amp;uacute;squeda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;el-poder-de-los-blogs-y-las-redes-sociales:1e5203f9d6f3f6af0248e56ec6ce10e8&#34;&gt;El Poder de los Blogs y las Redes Sociales&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Los blogs y las redes sociales (los llamados social media) han roto las barreras de entrada que nos separaban de nuestro mercado objetivo. Estas herramientas (muchas de ellas gratuitas o de bajo costo) han permitido que quienes &amp;eacute;ramos antes simples espectadores ahora podamos tomar control del escenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Los medios tradicionales como los diarios, la televisi&amp;oacute;n y la radio ya no son la &amp;uacute;nica manera en que podemos consumir y diseminar informaci&amp;oacute;n.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La publicidad tradicional atraviesa por una grave crisis de credibilidad, y con justa raz&amp;oacute;n. Nada m&amp;aacute;s cabe plantearse la pregunta: Qu&amp;eacute; tiene m&amp;aacute;s peso: lo que t&amp;uacute; digas de t&amp;iacute; mismo, o lo que otros digan de ti?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La respuesta es obvia, y explica por que cada vez menos gente depende de la publicidad para tomar una decisi&amp;oacute;n de compra y cada vez m&amp;aacute;s en recomendaciones de amigos, potenciadas de exponencialmente por las redes sociales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gracias a los &lt;strong&gt;blogs&lt;/strong&gt; ahora contamos con una plataforma de alcance global e instant&amp;aacute;neo para expresar y difundir nuestras ideas, as&amp;iacute; como tambi&amp;eacute;n interactuar con quienes nos visitan. Un blog es quiz&amp;aacute;s la mejor herramienta disponible para comunicar nuestra marca personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redes como LinkedIn permiten relacionarnos con otros profesionales y construir nuestra red de contactos de una manera f&amp;aacute;cil y r&amp;aacute;pida. Por medio de LinkedIn podemos acceder a oportunidades que de otra manera no se nos hubiesen presentado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trav&amp;eacute;s de YouTube podemos tener un canal propio para difundir nuestras ideas, presentaciones, entrevistas y comentarios.  Slideshare nos permite compartir nuestras presentaciones con nuestra audiencia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otras herramientas importantes para comunicar tu marca personal son Twitter, para compartir enlaces y opiniones breves, y Facebook, para compartir comentarios, fotograf&amp;iacute;as, videos y aplicaciones, o para construir una p&amp;aacute;gina para nuestra empresa, producto o servicio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Las posibilidades que nos brinda la Internet para construir y comunicar nuestra marca personal est&amp;aacute;n limitadas s&amp;oacute;lo por nuestra imaginaci&amp;oacute;n y por el tiempo y esfuerzo que deseemos invertirle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tu-personalidad-la-cereza-de-la-torta:1e5203f9d6f3f6af0248e56ec6ce10e8&#34;&gt;Tu Personalidad: La Cereza de la Torta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una de las primeras preguntas que surge cuando uno resalta la importancia de crear nuestra marca personal y participar activamente en las redes sociales es: &amp;iquest;Para qu&amp;eacute;? &amp;iquest;A qui&amp;eacute;n le importa mi opini&amp;oacute;n, lo que me gusta, o lo que estoy haciendo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pues, a todos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vivimos en una &amp;eacute;poca en que &lt;strong&gt;los atributos t&amp;eacute;cnicos, si bien siguen siendo importantes, ya no son suficientes para diferenciarnos&lt;/strong&gt;. Probablemente hayan, s&amp;oacute;lo en tu ciudad, miles de profesionales (dentistas, abogados, contadores, etc.) t&amp;eacute;cnicamente capacitados para hacer su trabajo bien.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esta abundancia de opciones nos da la prerrogativa de trabajar s&amp;oacute;lo con personas que compartan nuestros valores, nuestras aficiones, nuestras prioridades y nuestra manera de ver las cosas (personas que, como se dice comunmente, &#34;nos caigan bien&#34;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nuestra personalidad y nuestras experiencias personales son la saz&amp;oacute;n que le da al plato de nuestra marca personal su sabor &amp;uacute;nico y caracter&amp;iacute;stico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El exceso de formalidad, y la separaci&amp;oacute;n de la vida profesional de la personal son cosa del pasado. Lo que la gente quiere saber para trabajar contigo es quien eres realmente, y cuales son tus historias.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>