<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mariosanchez.org/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My 3 Words for 2016</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/3words16/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, Chris Brogan started a yearly tradition: choosing the three words that would guide his actions for the next twelve months, and publishing them on his blog (you can read more about it on &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbrogan.com/3-words-2016/&#34;&gt;Chris&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this exercise to be extremely powerful, as it forces us to sit down and think long and hard about our priorities in life and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now sharing my Three Words for 2016: LEARN, EXPERIMENTS, SELF-AWARENESS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Learn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will focus on expanding my competence in new areas of knowledge. It is all too easy to just focus on the day-to-day tasks you&amp;rsquo;ve been performing for years, get complacent and stop learning. That&amp;rsquo;s how you become obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dedicating 2015 to learn the basics of web development and being finally able to deploy a website from scratch, helped me understand how much I missed learning new things and the feeling of accomplishment that comes with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 I will double down on learning. A few things I want to learn: to operate a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_server&#34;&gt;VPS&lt;/a&gt;, improve my Portuguese, and get better at fixing things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experiments:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to gravitate towards the same things over and over again: the same restaurants, the same kind of books, the same passtimes. I like predictablilty and reliability, which probably means that I&amp;rsquo;ve missed out on many good things for not experimenting enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 I will focus on trying new things in the spirit of continuous self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing Tim Ferriss, if you want opportunities to come to you, you must first throw a lot of things against the wall (experiment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guiding word also dovetails nicely with the first one (Learn) as they share many common themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-awareness:0a431635f918607bc30d2e73d05f468d&#34;&gt;Self-Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage it is crystal clear to me that as important as deciding what to do (or even more important) is to decide what &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By developing my career mostly in large corporations I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my working years living up to other people&amp;rsquo;s expectations: there is always a boss to please, employees to manage, politics to play. A few times I have also been required to play roles that were not in alignment with my core strengths and personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2016 and beyond I&amp;rsquo;m going to do less of what other people expect of me, and more of the things that allow me to leverage my strengths and get me closer to my overarching life goals. I&amp;rsquo;m going to &amp;ldquo;trust my gut&amp;rdquo;: if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right, I won&amp;rsquo;t do it. No more painting by (other people&amp;rsquo;s) numbers. Life is too short.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My $100 Office</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/100office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 10:34:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/100office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed a quiet space at home where I could sit down and tweak the code of my site, and otherwise tinker with some web development tools I want to learn. Since my second bedroom had some empty space and a window with a nice view of the garden, it was the perfect place to try to fit a small workstation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of money but I still wanted my new writing setup to look good, so my logical first stop was Ikea&amp;rsquo;s website. I found a $35 desk and a $15 chair that I liked and perfectly fit the space available, so I drove to the nearest store and picked them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to give the space some character, so I selected twelve pictures I had taken on my &lt;a href=&#34;../photos/&#34;&gt;trips&lt;/a&gt; and ordered 8x10 prints (I got them for less than $20 in Snapfish).  I also got some cheap but stylish frames from Walmart ($11 for a set of six, so $22 total).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I added a recycled lamp I got for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I installed everything and this is how it now looks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/images/workstation.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am extremely happy with this new setup. I now have a place to write and code comfortably, that looks good and cost me less than $100.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 6S Discipline</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/6s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/6s/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, the company moved us to a new office. When we walked into our shiny, new cubicles we found a single sheet of paper laid out on top of our recently installed, empty desks describing something called &amp;ldquo;The 6S Discipline&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a concise list of 6 bullet points that summarized a process to keep our work stations clean and organized. I later found out that the 6S concept comes from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_manufacturing&#34;&gt;Lean Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt; philosophy, the principles of which can also be applied to an office setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I have always liked to keep my workplace neatly organized and keep around only the things I need at one particular moment, the 6S concept strongly resonated with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about the 6S philosophy, you can read this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vitalentusa.com/learn/An_Introduction_to_6S.pdf&#34;&gt;comprehensive 6S overview&lt;/a&gt; I found searching online. On the other hand, if you just want to grasp the gist of it, here are the 6S principles in short form, just like in the page I found on my desk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sort:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Sort&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sort out necessary and unnecessary items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep only items necessary to perform the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove and discard the items not required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-in-order:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Set In Order&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organize the essential materials in the workplace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find &amp;ldquo;a place for everything and keep everything in its place&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shine:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Shine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep the area clean at all times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;standardize:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Standardize&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain the Sort, Set In Order, and Shine Steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sustain:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Sustain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain the gain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for ways to continuously improve your work area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;safety-first:42441621e042de90c292d1ae34891e18&#34;&gt;Safety First&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an accident-free workplace. Eliminate hazards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, 6S is about &lt;mark&gt;eliminating waste and maximizing value-adding activities&lt;/mark&gt;, by creating and maintaining an organized, clean, safe and efficient work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/4/3548/3389551970_a24a14b9ba_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credits: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/cocokelley/3389551970&#34;&gt;Cassandra Lavalle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power Morning Productivity Bubble</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/mornings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/mornings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that the latest fad among self-proclaimed productivity gurus is the concept of &amp;ldquo;power mornings&amp;rdquo;. Just Google &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webhp?hl=en#hl=en&amp;amp;q=morning+rituals&#34;&gt;morning rituals&lt;/a&gt; and you&amp;rsquo;ll see what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, if you don&amp;rsquo;t wake up at 4am, meditate, run a half marathon, speed-read three books, and write a chapter of your soon-to-be-published novel before your coffee is ready, you must be a slacker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But who are these people telling us what to do with our time, our sleep, our exercise and our food? Are they physicians or dietitians? No, they&amp;rsquo;re just personal
development &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo; who have found in the latest productivity fad a way to sell books, seminars and expensive coaching sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, enough of the one-size-fits-all power morning ritual. The bottom line is that &lt;mark&gt;everybody is different because our &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronobiology&#34;&gt;biological rhythms&lt;/a&gt; are different&lt;/mark&gt;. Forget what the &amp;ldquo;gurus&amp;rdquo; say and just do what works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What works for me? I need seven to eight hours of sleep, so waking up at 4am is a no-no. Upon waking up, usually at 6:30am or so, I perform a stretching and strengthening routine for my lower back, abdomen and hamstrings, followed by a healthy breakfast (sometimes blueberry yogurt with muesli, sometimes oatmeal with raisins
and apple, or a sprouted wheat toast with cheddar cheese and a boiled egg, all preceded by a small glass of orange/carrot juice and followed by a large cup of coffee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, do you have a morning ritual?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the topic, check out this &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@InVisionApp/what-s-your-morning-ritual-b3ff2fbcc8e5#.o9qgzlwb9&#34;&gt;Medium article&lt;/a&gt;, where several people share how they get their mornings started. It&amp;rsquo;s worth the 4 minute read (plus, the pictures
are great!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/5/4019/4658619672_819e8d7414_b.jpg&#34; class=&#34;roundcorners&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Best Tools</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/best-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/best-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up in Peru back in the 80&amp;rsquo;s I used to play tennis every weekend. I was never very good at it, but I loved to have the coolest rackets and shoes. Back then that meant either a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.80s-tennis.com/pages/maxply-fort_80-ad.html&#34;&gt;Dunlop Maxply&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;http://racquetmuseum.com/2014/01/23/wilson-jack-kramer-autograph/&#34;&gt;Wilson Jack Kramer&lt;/a&gt; racket, and a pair of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adidas_Stan_Smith&#34;&gt;Adidas Stan Smith&lt;/a&gt; tennis shoes. Needless to say, none of those tools made me be a better player. They were just status symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a right time for buying yourself great tools, but it is usually not when you are just a beginner or a dabbler. &lt;mark&gt;At the early stages of any endevour, focused and disciplined practice will get you further than using the latest gadgets&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than asking &amp;ldquo;what blogging platform should I use?&amp;rdquo; develop the habit of writing often and see if it is something you want to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than buying a Moleskin notebook to practice drawing mind maps, use any notebook for a while and see if it is something that helps you think more creatively or organize your thoughts better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of buying a Mac Book Pro to try your hand at some basic HTML or CSS, get an old laptop and see if it is something that you want to spend time learning first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve proven your commitment to an activity or craft, by all means get yourself the best tools: you deserve them now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage, the best tools will not only give you an edge but will motivate you to keep improving, and will help you view yourself as what you really are: a professional who takes pride in what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Minimalism</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/post/mini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk about minimalism these days, and much confusion about what it means. While I&amp;rsquo;m far from being an authority on the subject (I consider myself a minimalist-in-training) I&amp;rsquo;m going to throw in my two cents and explain what minimalism means to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimalism doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we have to turn into some sort of Buddhist monk going through life with six or seven worldly possessions.  &lt;mark&gt;Getting rid of stuff is not the goal here, but rather the consequence of choosing to live in a more deliberate way&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimalism starts by understanding that everything we surround ourselves with either adds value to our life or is just taking space. Things add value by being useful or by bringing us joy. Everything we let into our lives has to earn it&amp;rsquo;s place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good way to make minimalism a daily practice is to get into the habit of constantly asking ourselves this question: &amp;ldquo;What is this doing here?&amp;rdquo; If it&amp;rsquo;s not adding value or bringing us joy, get rid of it. Throw it away or give it to someone who may need it/like it/want it. Here&amp;rsquo;s the key, though: whatever we decide to do we must decide quickly, or the resistance (laziness, procrastination, the just-in-case syndrome) will take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep it up until this daily practice becomes a habit, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised by how eliminating physical clutter contributes to getting rid of mental clutter too. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that since I&amp;rsquo;m doing this I&amp;rsquo;m able to think more clearly, and have an easier time getting organized and getting things done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>