<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to the Good Life</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ayw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ayw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/stoic.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally got to read &amp;ldquo;A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy&amp;rdquo; by William B. Irvine. The book came highly recommended by Derek Sivers, an artist and writer that I respect and identify with due to our almost identical world views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had only a vague idea of what stoicism was prior to reading the book, but based on my little knowledge I suspected that I have been practicing, albeit unknowingly, many of the tenets of this philosophy. Reading the book confirmed my theory, and introduced me to some new tools and techniques to improve the way I live. Here are &lt;strong&gt;10 key ideas&lt;/strong&gt; of the book that I highlighted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The objective of Stoicism is to enable you to live a good life by pursuing &lt;strong&gt;tranquility&lt;/strong&gt; (defined as the absence of negative emotions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism teaches us to use our &lt;strong&gt;reasoning ability&lt;/strong&gt; to banish negative emotions like anger, grief, and envy. Rational people will find Stoicism easier to practice than overly emotional people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism recommends the practice of &amp;ldquo;negative visualization&amp;rdquo;, basically to imagine how would life be if we lose the things or people we value. By engaging in negative visualization we diminish the anguish and grief of loss in two ways: first, because whatever happens we will be expecting it, and second, because it teaches us to be grateful for the things we still have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to master the &amp;ldquo;trichotomy of control&amp;rdquo;, by recognizing the three categories of things: 1) Things over which we have complete control, 2) Things over which we have no control at all, and 3) Things over which we have some but not complete control. We should only concern ourselves with things over which we have complete control, or some level of control. It is useless to worry about things over which we don&amp;rsquo;t have control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Along those lines, Stoicism teaches us to choose &amp;ldquo;internal goals&amp;rdquo; as opposed to &amp;ldquo;external goals&amp;rdquo;. For example, if we&amp;rsquo;re playing a game of tennis, our goal should be to play our best tennis possible, and not to win the game. By internalizing his goals, the Stoic is able to preserve his tranquility while dealing with things over which he has only partial control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoicism teaches us that the key to being wealthy is not to have a lot but to &lt;strong&gt;need very little&lt;/strong&gt;. Stoics don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily reject material wealth. They enjoy it but they don&amp;rsquo;t cling to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics prepare to lose their wealth by regularly practicing &amp;ldquo;voluntary discomfort&amp;rdquo;. The most likely result of practicing this technique is that we will soon notice how little do we really need to live a happy, productive life. Some things we can practice on a regular basis are to eat simply prioritizing nutrition over pleasure, get rid of non-essential possesions and practice minimalism, take public transportation instead of our car, sleep in couches, take cold showers, etc. These are minor things that we will get used to and learn to enjoy with time. Because they have learned to enjoy things that are easily obtainable or that can’t be taken from them, Stoics will find much in life to enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics recognize that our anger about something is usually worse and lasts longer than the damage done to us, therefore we should &lt;strong&gt;avoid getting angry&lt;/strong&gt;. To get rid of anger we should practice putting things in their right perspective. For example, we can ask ourselves: &amp;ldquo;will this really matter in 100 years?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics value their &lt;strong&gt;freedom&lt;/strong&gt;, and they are therefore reluctant to do anything that will give others power over them. If we seek social status, we give other people power over us. That is why as Stoics we must become indifferent to other people’s opinions of us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We must train ourselves to not hold grudges or condider ourselves a victim. If we consider ourselves victims, we are not going to have a good life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this book I recommend checking out &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/book/StoicJoy&#34;&gt;Derek Siver&amp;rsquo;s book notes&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0195374614?tag=sivers-20&#34;&gt;reading the whole book&lt;/a&gt; (it&amp;rsquo;s worth it!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiet</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/quiet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 21:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/quiet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/quiet.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an introvert myself this book really resonated with me. It talks about the current social obsession with extroversion and teamwork, especially in the business world, where being gregarious is seen as an almost indispensable precondition for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With conclusive research data, the author demonstrates that designing an environment that caters to the needs of introverts, by not over stimulating them with group activities, letting them work alone for extended periods of time, or giving them time to recharge, leads to better results, in business and in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial two thirds of the book explain how we arrived to the era of extroversion glorification. Several pages are dedicated to cover Tony Robbins over-the-top seminars and the culture within the Evangelical church. It also deals with the psycological research behind our different personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real meat of the book comes in Chapter 9, where we can find actionable advice. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn about &amp;ldquo;stretching&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Free Trait Agreements&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;restorative niches&amp;rdquo;, powerful techniques that introverts can use to thrive in today&amp;rsquo;s extrovert-driven world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the book I found out that the author had done a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/susan_cain_the_power_of_introverts?language=en&#34;&gt;TED talk&lt;/a&gt; on the subject. While not a substitute for the book it is worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes:413acb98b45f59b87e6a91c1fc93570d&#34;&gt;My Highlights and Notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our lives are shaped as profoundly by personality as by gender or race.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yet today we make room for a remarkably narrow range of personality styles. We&amp;rsquo;re told that to be great is to be bold, to be happy is to be sociable. We see ourselves as a nation of extroverts-which means that we&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of who we really are.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So many people pretend to be extroverts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some fool even themselves, until some life event-a layoff, an empty nest, an inheritance that frees them to spend time as they like-jolts them into taking stock of their true natures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introversion-along with its cousins sensitivity, seriousness, and shyness-is now a second-class personality trait.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We make a grave mistake to embrace the Extrovert Ideal so unthinkingly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neither E=mc2 nor Paradise Lost was dashed off by a party animal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Many of the most important institutions of contemporary life are designed for those who enjoy group projects and high levels of stimulation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The vast majority of teachers believe that the ideal student is an extrovert.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As adults, many of us work for organizations that insist we work in teams, in offices without walls, for supervisors who value &amp;ldquo;people skills&amp;rdquo; above all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re expected to promote ourselves unabashedly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re an introvert, you also know that the bias against quiet can cause deep psychic pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come &amp;ldquo;out of your shell&amp;rdquo;-that noxious expression&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now that you&amp;rsquo;re an adult, you might still feel a pang of guilt when you decline a dinner invitation in favor of a good book.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have seen firsthand &lt;mark&gt;how difficult it is for introverts to take stock of their own talents, and how powerful it is when finally they do&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts recharge their batteries by being alone; extroverts need to recharge when they don&amp;rsquo;t socialize enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no all-purpose definition of introversion or extroversion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts and extroverts differ in the level of outside stimulation that they need to function well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introverts, in contrast, may have strong social skills and enjoy parties and business meetings, but after a while wish they were home in their pajamas. They prefer to devote their social energies to close friends, colleagues, and family. They listen more than they talk, think before they speak, and often feel as if they express themselves better in writing than in conversation. They tend to dislike conflict. Many have a horror of small talk, but enjoy deep discussions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nor are introverts necessarily shy. &lt;mark&gt;Shyness is the fear of social disapproval or humiliation, while introversion is a preference for environments that are not overstimulating&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;America had shifted from what the influential cultural historian Warren Susman called a Culture of Character to a Culture of Personality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The social role demanded of all in the new Culture of Personality was that of a performer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Americans responded to these pressures by trying to become salesmen who could sell not only their company&amp;rsquo;s latest gizmo but also themselves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By 1920, popular self-help guides had changed their focus from inner virtue to outer charm-to know what to say and how to say it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The model employee of the midcentury-even one whose job rarely involved dealing with the public, like a research scientist in a corporate lab-was not a deep thinker but a hearty extrovert with a salesman&amp;rsquo;s personality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Early Americans revered action and were suspicious of intellect, associating the life of the mind with the languid, ineffectual European aristocracy they had left behind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The pressure to entertain, to sell ourselves, and never to be visibly anxious keeps ratcheting up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What if you love knowledge for its own sake, not necessarily as a blueprint to action?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A middle manager at GE once told me that &amp;ldquo;people here don&amp;rsquo;t even want to meet with you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a PowerPoint and a &amp;ldquo;pitch&amp;rdquo; for them&amp;rdquo;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone knows that it&amp;rsquo;s important to be an extrovert and troublesome to be an introvert. So people work real hard at looking like extroverts, whether that&amp;rsquo;s comfortable or not.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If we assume that quiet and loud people have roughly the same number of good (and bad) ideas, then we should worry if the louder and more forceful people always carry the day&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We perceive talkers as smarter than quiet types-even though grade-point averages and SAT and intelligence test scores reveal this perception to be inaccurate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We put too much of a premium on presenting and not enough on substance and critical thinking.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Contrary to the Harvard Business School model of vocal leadership, the ranks of effective CEOs turn out to be filled with introverts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Brigham Young University management professor Bradley Agle studied the CEOs of 128 major companies and found that those considered charismatic by their top executives had bigger salaries but not better corporate performance.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Many of the best-performing companies of the late twentieth century were run by what he calls &amp;ldquo;Level 5 Leaders.&amp;rdquo; These exceptional CEOs were known not for their flash or charisma but for extreme humility coupled with intense professional will.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social media has made new forms of leadership possible for scores of people who don&amp;rsquo;t fit the Harvard Business School mold.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps social media affords us the control we lack in real life socializing: the screen as a barrier between us and the world. The same person who would never raise his hand in a lecture hall of two hundred people might blog to two thousand, or two million, without thinking twice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Introverts prefer to work independently, and solitude can be a catalyst to innovation&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are born and culturally endowed with certain personality traits-introversion, for example-but we can and do act out of character in the service of &amp;ldquo;core personal projects.&amp;rdquo; In other words, introverts are capable of acting like extroverts for the sake of work they consider important, people they love, or anything they value highly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we act out of character by convincing ourselves that our pseudo-self is real, we can eventually burn out without even knowing why.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Behavioral leakage, in which our true selves seep out via unconscious body language.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not always so easy, it turns out, to identify your core personal projects. And it can be especially tough for introverts, who have spent so much of their lives conforming to extroverted norms that by the time they choose a career, or a calling, it feels perfectly normal to ignore their own preferences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are three key steps to identifying your own core personal projects:
* First, think back to what you loved to do when you were a child.
* Second, pay attention to the work you gravitate to.
* Finally, pay attention to what you envy. &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But even if you&amp;rsquo;re stretching yourself in the service of a core personal project, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to act out of character too much, or for too long.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Create as many &lt;mark&gt;&amp;ldquo;restorative niches&amp;rdquo;&lt;/mark&gt; as possible in your daily life. &amp;ldquo;Restorative niche&amp;rdquo; is Professor Little&amp;rsquo;s term for the place you go when you want to return to your true self. It can be a physical place, like the path beside the Richelieu River, or a temporal one, like the quiet breaks you plan between sales calls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Will this job allow me to spend time on in-character activities?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Acting in character most of the time, effectively turns workdays into one giant restorative niche.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Free Trait Agreement acknowledges that we&amp;rsquo;ll each act out of character some of the time-in exchange for being ourselves the rest of the time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The person with whom you can best strike a Free Trait Agreement-after overcoming his or her resistance-is yourself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Double pneumonia and an overscheduled life can happen to anyone, of course, but for Little, it was the result of &lt;mark&gt;acting out of character for too long and without enough restorative niches&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prolonged acting out of character may also increase autonomic nervous system activity, which can, in turn, compromise immune functioning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It can be hard for extroverts to understand how badly introverts need to recharge at the end of a busy day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In sales there&amp;rsquo;s a truism that &amp;ldquo;we have two ears and one mouth&amp;rdquo; and we should use them proportionately.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What makes someone really good at selling or consulting-the number-one thing is they&amp;rsquo;ve got to really listen well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about socializing with everyone. Think quality over quantity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Solve problems, make art, think deeply.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Spend your free time the way you like, not the way you think you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Remember the dangers of the New Groupthink. If it&amp;rsquo;s creativity you&amp;rsquo;re after, ask your employees to solve problems alone before sharing their ideas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t mistake assertiveness or eloquence for good ideas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do We Work?</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/whywork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 16:48:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/whywork/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/whywork.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.swarthmore.edu/SocSci/bschwar1/&#34;&gt;Barry Schwartz&lt;/a&gt; questions the idea that people only work for pay and urges us to design work organizations that give people discretion and autonomy, and the chance to do meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can save yourself reading through pages and pages of empirical evidence and research notes, and go straight to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_the_way_we_think_about_work_is_broken?language=en&#34;&gt;author&amp;rsquo;s TED talk&lt;/a&gt; on the subject if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes:938663226f49485894bf15c3c52c2d69&#34;&gt;My highlights and notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Satisfied people do their work because they feel that they are in charge. Their workday offers them a measure of &lt;em&gt;autonomy and discretion&lt;/em&gt;. And they use that autonomy and discretion to achieve a level of mastery or expertise. They learn new things, developing both as workers and as people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gallup found that only 13 percent of workers feel engaged by their jobs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;The four characteristics of good work: challenge, engagement, meaning, and satisfaction. To this I would add &lt;strong&gt;autonomy and discretion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Job crafting is what Wrzesniewski and her colleagues called when we shape our jobs with the central purpose of our employer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To be satisfied with our work, we typically need a belief in the purpose of what we do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is people who see their work as a &amp;ldquo;calling&amp;rdquo; who find it most satisfying.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work &amp;lt; Career &amp;lt; Calling&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Take discretion, engagement, and meaning out of work and people feel less &amp;ldquo;called&amp;rdquo; to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Virtually any job has the potential to offer people satisfaction. It can be made meaningful by connecting them to the welfare of others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Factors that effective organizations have in common&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employment security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-managed teams and decentralized decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They pay more than the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They provide extensive training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t overmeasure employee performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They put great emphasis on the company mission.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In short, you take discretion, engagement, and meaning out of work and people get less satisfaction from doing it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When people are in states of positive emotion, they think expansively and creatively.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Carrots and sticks. What is striking is that, in the analysis that Pfeffer offers, both of these tools have negative effects on employee engagement and work satisfaction.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you create an environment in which workers are respected, they want to be there and they want to work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Carefully crafted incentive schemes, designed to ensure top performance, can often produce the opposite result.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social motives and financial ones compete. No incentives can ever be smart enough to substitute for people who do the right thing because it&amp;rsquo;s the right thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When we lose confidence that people have the will to do the right thing, and we turn to incentives, we find that we get what we pay for.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;watch where they walk, then pave it&amp;rdquo; metaphor argues that the empirical data shape the theories people develop. The &amp;ldquo;if you build it, they will come&amp;rdquo; metaphor argues that theories shape data. [The author] defends the second metaphor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Work over which people exercise some discretion and control leads to cognitive flexibility and to an engaged orientation to self and society; in contrast, excessively monitored, oppressively supervised working conditions lead to distress.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People don&amp;rsquo;t think of themselves as primarily motivated by material incentives, but &lt;mark&gt;they think that pretty much everyone else is&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;French emperor Napoleon termed ideologues were so in love with ideas that they ignored empirical evidence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Better data and theories drive out worse ones, and progress is made. Why does this not happen in the case of theories about human nature?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Theories about human nature can actually produce changes in how people behave&lt;/mark&gt;. A theory that is false can become true simply by people believing it&amp;rsquo;s true.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Performance-oriented&lt;/strong&gt; vs. &lt;strong&gt;Mastery-oriented&lt;/strong&gt;: Performance-oriented people want to &lt;em&gt;prove&lt;/em&gt; their ability while mastery-oriented people want to &lt;em&gt;improve&lt;/em&gt; their ability.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So is intelligence fixed? Partly, that depends on whether you believe it&amp;rsquo;s fixed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unless there is a collective effort to combat this ideology, we will all become the lazy, selfish pursuers of self-interest, not just in work but in our lives as a whole, that at least some social scientists have assumed we always were. So the question becomes: What can we do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If we design workplaces that permit people to do work they value, we will be designing a human nature that values work&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The first step to taking responsibility over the structure of our workplace is to start asking questions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are the results of our transactions with customers positive sum, so that both sides leave the transaction better off?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We can demand of ourselves the effort to find the ways in which other people benefit if we do our jobs with enthusiasm rather than indifference.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Industrialization has been a spectacular human achievement. But as it has relieved material poverty, it has done so at the price of poverty of spirit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ayw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:38:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ayw/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/ayw.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A powerful little book offering valuable uncommon sense advice on how to approach business in alignment with your values and beliefs. In about an hour reading time, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sivers.org&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt; candidly tells us everything he learned from founding, operating and selling CD Baby, the business he stumbled upon when he decided to help fellow musicians sell their work on the Internet in the pre-Paypal, pre-iTunes days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes&#34;&gt;My Highlights and Notes:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to know your personal philosophy of what makes you happy and what&amp;rsquo;s worth doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business is not about money. It&amp;rsquo;s about making dreams come true for others and for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Success comes from persistently improving and inventing, not from persistently promoting what&amp;rsquo;s not working.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your business plan is moot. You don&amp;rsquo;t know what people really want until you start doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need money to start helping people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make yourself unnecessary to the running of your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real point of doing anything is to be happy, so do only what makes you happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t trying to make a big business. I was just daydreaming about how one little thing would look in a perfect world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you make a business, you get to make a little universe where you control all the laws. This is your utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A business plan should never take more than a few hours of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best plans start simple. A quick glance and common sense should tell you if the numbers will work. The rest are details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revolution&lt;/em&gt; is a term that people use only when you&amp;rsquo;re successful. Before that, you&amp;rsquo;re just a quirky person who does things differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Present each new idea or improvement to the world. If multiple people are saying, &amp;ldquo;Wow! Yes! I need this! I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to pay you to do this!&amp;rdquo; then you should probably do it. But if the response is anything less, don&amp;rsquo;t pursue it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not saying &amp;ldquo;HELL YEAH!&amp;rdquo; about something, say &amp;ldquo;no.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to most things, you leave room in your life to throw yourself completely into that rare thing that makes you say &amp;ldquo;HELL YEAH!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time you think you know what your new business will be doing, remember this quote from Steve Blank: No plan survives first contact with customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By not having any money to waste, you never waste money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely everything you do is for your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make every decision-even decisions about whether to expand the business, raise money, or promote someone-according to what&amp;rsquo;s best for your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of your customers will ask you to turn your attention to expanding. They want you to keep your attention focused on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to grow your business is to focus entirely on your existing customers. Just thrill them, and they&amp;rsquo;ll tell everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an idea to get big big big, it has to be useful. And being useful doesn&amp;rsquo;t need funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be useful, you can always start now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting small puts 100 percent of your energy on actually solving real problems for real people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas are worth nothing unless they are executed. They are just a multiplier. Execution is worth millions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never forget that there are thousands of businesses, like Jim&amp;rsquo;s Fish Bait Shop in a shack on a beach somewhere, that are doing just fine without corporate formalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do land the big client, that organization will practically own you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By trying so hard to please the big client, you will lose touch with what the rest of the world wants. Instead, imagine that you have designed your business to have NO big clients, just lots of little clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you build your business on serving thousands of customers, not dozens, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about any one customer leaving or making special demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to confidently exclude people, and proudly say what you&amp;rsquo;re not. By doing so, you will win the hearts of the people you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a big world. You can loudly leave out 99 percent of it.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have the confidence to know that when your target 1 percent hears you excluding the other 99 percent, the people in that 1 percent will come to you because you&amp;rsquo;ve shown how much you value them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No business goes as planned, so make ten radically different plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t think you need a huge vision. Just stay focused on helping people today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never forget why you&amp;rsquo;re really doing what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. Are you helping people? Are they happy? Are you happy? Are you profitable? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all grade ourselves by different measures: For me, it&amp;rsquo;s how many useful things I create, whether songs, companies, articles, websites, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A business is started to solve a problem. But if the problem was truly solved, that business would no longer be needed! So the business accidentally or unconsciously keeps the problem around so that they can keep solving it for a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any business that&amp;rsquo;s in business to sell you a cure is motivated not to focus on prevention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Care about your customers more than about yourself, and you&amp;rsquo;ll do well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you set up your business like you don&amp;rsquo;t need the money, people are happier to pay you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;When someone&amp;rsquo;s doing something for the money, people can sense it, like a desperate lover. It&amp;rsquo;s a turnoff.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t prevent bad things from happening. Learn to shrug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s often the tiny details that really thrill people enough to make them tell all their friends about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find even the smallest way to make people smile, they&amp;rsquo;ll remember you more for that smile than for all your other fancy business-model stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to tell what someone&amp;rsquo;s going to be like on the job until he&amp;rsquo;s actually on the job for a few weeks. So I&amp;rsquo;d hire lightly and fire lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t try to impress an invisible jury of MBA professors. It&amp;rsquo;s OK to be casual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a benefit to being naive about the norms of the world: deciding from scratch what seems like the right thing to do, instead of just doing what others do.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what business you&amp;rsquo;re in, it&amp;rsquo;s good to prepare for what would happen if business doubled. &amp;ldquo;More of the same&amp;rdquo; is never the answer. You&amp;rsquo;d have to do things in a new way to handle twice as much business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about being, not having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole point of doing anything is because it makes you happy! That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never again promised a customer that I could do something that was beyond my full control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got myself into the delegation mindset. I had to make myself unnecessary to the running of my company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a big difference between being self-employed and being a business owner. Being self-employed feels like freedom until you realize that if you take time off, your business crumbles. To be a true business owner, make sure you
could leave for a year, and when you came back, your business would be doing better than when you left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make your role anything you want it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Anything you hate to do, someone else loves. So find that person and let him do it. &lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge growth means lots of meetings, investors, bankers, media, and answering to others. It&amp;rsquo;s quite far from the real core of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t every business want to be as big as possible? No. Make sure you know what makes you happy, and don&amp;rsquo;t forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust, but verify. Remember it when delegating. You have to do both. &lt;mark&gt;Delegate, but don&amp;rsquo;t abdicate&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s such a thing as over-delegation. I had empowered my employees so much that I gave them all the power. After a complete communication breakdown, it was eight-five people (my employees) against one (me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned an important word: abdicate. To abdicate means to surrender or relinquish power or responsibility; this word is usually used when a king abdicates the throne or crown. Lesson learned too late: Delegate, but don&amp;rsquo;t abdicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that the bigger learning and growing challenge for me was letting go, not staying on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I let two companies bid, and ended up choosing the one that bid the lowest but understood my clients better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The less I own, the happier I am. The lack of stuff gives me the priceless freedom to live anywhere anytime. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m altruistic. I&amp;rsquo;m sacrificing nothing. I&amp;rsquo;ve just learned what makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You make your perfect world. Business is as creative as the fine arts. You can be as unconventional, unique, and quirky as you want. A business is a reflection of the creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter which goal you choose, there will be lots of people telling you you&amp;rsquo;re wrong. Just pay close attention to what excites you and what drains you. Pay close attention to when you&amp;rsquo;re being the real you and when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to
impress an invisible jury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it makes you happy, that&amp;rsquo;s OK. It&amp;rsquo;s your choice to remain small.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Good They Can&#39;t Ignore You</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/sgtci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/sgtci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/sgtci.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The career advice I wish I had received when I was 18 years old. This book exposes the &amp;ldquo;follow your passion&amp;rdquo; myth and argues that the best way to be successful and happy at work is to become extremely good at what we do. Read it before embarking on any significant career change or if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to get more satisfaction out of your current job or career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are my notes and highlights from the book:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do some people end up loving what they do, while so many others fail at this goal? My question was clear: How do people end up loving what they do? And I needed an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conventional wisdom on career success—follow your passion—is seriously flawed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be good at something before you can expect a good job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t follow your passion; rather, let it follow you in your quest to become, in the words of my favorite Steve Martin quote, “so good that they can’t ignore you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus away from finding the right work and toward working right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes time to get good at anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key thing is to force yourself through the work, force the skills to come; that’s the hardest phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compelling careers often have complex origins that reject the simple idea that all you have to do is follow your passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many complex reasons for workplace satisfaction, but the reductive notion of matching your job to a pre-existing passion is not among them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less than 4% percent of the total identified passions had any relation to work or education, with the remaining  percent describing hobby-style interests such as sports and art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a distinction between a job, a career, and a calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more experience [one has], the more likely [one is] to love his/her work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The happiest, most passionate employees are not those who followed their passion into a position, but instead those who have been around long enough to become good at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passion Is a Side Effect of Mastery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three traits of a great job or career: Autonomy, Competence, Relatedness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autonomy: the feeling that you have control over your day, and that your actions are important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competence: the feeling that you are good at what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relatedness: the feeling of connection to other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telling someone to “follow their passion” is not just an act of innocent optimism, but potentially the foundation for a career riddled with confusion and angst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The craftsman mindset, a focus on what value you’re producing in your job, and the passion mindset, a focus on what value your job offers you [are opposites]. The craftsman mindset is the foundation for creating work you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Eventually] you are so experienced [that] there’s a confidence that comes out,” Steve Martin explained. “I think it’s something the audience smells.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An obsessive focus on the quality of what you produce is the rule in professional music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The craftsman mindset is crucial for building a career you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when you focus only on what your work offers you, it makes you hyperaware of what you don’t like about it, leading to chronic unhappiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deep questions driving the passion mindset—“Who am I?” and “What do I truly love?”—are essentially impossible to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two different ways people think about their working life. The first is the craftsman mindset, which focuses on what you can offer the world. The second is the passion mindset, which instead focuses on what the world can offer you. The craftsman mindset offers clarity, while the passion mindset offers a swamp of ambiguous and unanswerable questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shouldn’t just envy the craftsman mindset, you should emulate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how you feel about your job right now, adopting the craftsman mindset will be the foundation on which you’ll build a compelling career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopt the craftsman mindset first and then the passion follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic economic theory tells us that if you want something that’s both rare and valuable, you need something rare and valuable to offer in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It follows that if you want a great job, you need something of great value to offer in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three traits of great carrers: creativity, impact, and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the rare and valuable skills you can offer as your career capital. The craftsman mindset, with its relentless focus on becoming “so good they can’t ignore you,” is a strategy well suited for acquiring career capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downside of the passion mindset is that it strips away merit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great work doesn’t just require great courage, but also skills of great (and real) value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DISQUALIFIERS FOR APPLYING THE CRAFTSMAN MINDSET The job presents few opportunities to distinguish yourself by developing relevant skills that are rare and valuable. The job focuses on something you think is useless or perhaps even actively bad for the world. The job forces you to work with people you really dislike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carefully and persistently gather career capital. Valuable skills will translate into valuable opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on difficult activities, carefully chosen to stretch your abilities where they most need stretching and that provide immediate feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Deliberate practice” is activity designed, typically by a teacher, for the sole purpose of effectively improving specific aspects of an individual’s performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to understand the source of professional athletes’ talent, for example, look to their practice schedules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When experts exhibit their superior performance in public their behavior looks so effortless and natural that we are tempted to attribute it to special talents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can figure out how to integrate deliberate practice into your own life, you have the possibility of blowing past your peers in your value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning is not done in isolation: You need to be constantly soliciting feedback from colleagues and professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of these markets: winner-take-all and auction. Step 1: Decide What Capital Market You’re In. Step 2: Identify Your Capital Type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seek open gates—opportunities to build capital that are already open to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about skill acquisition like a freight train: Getting it started requires a huge application of effort, but changing its track once it’s moving is easy. In other words, it’s hard to start from scratch in a new field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3: Define good. Deliberate practice requires good goals.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 4: Stretch and Destroy. Doing things we know how to do well is enjoyable, and that’s exactly the opposite of what deliberate practice demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deliberate practice is often the opposite of enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term “stretch” describes what deliberate practice feels like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not uncomfortable, then you’re probably stuck at an “acceptable level.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embracing honest feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 5: Be Patient. Deliberate practice, an approach to work where you deliberately stretch your abilities beyond where you’re comfortable and then receive ruthless feedback on your performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Control over what you do, and how you do it, is one of the most powerful traits you can acquire when creating work you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;theory on how people end up loving what they do. I argued in Rule #1 that “follow your passion” is bad advice, as the vast majority of people don’t have pre-existing passions waiting to be discovered and matched to a job. In Rule #2, I then countered that people with compelling careers instead start by getting good at something rare and valuable—building what I called “career capital”—and then cashing in this capital for the traits that make great work great. In this understanding, finding the right work pales in importance to working right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving people more control over what they do and how they do it increases their happiness, engagement, and sense of fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to love what you do, your first step is to acquire career capital. Your next step is to invest this capital in the traits that define great work. Control is one of the most important targets you can choose for this investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Control that’s acquired without career capital is not sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enthusiasm alone is not rare and valuable and is therefore not worth much in terms of career capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have enough career capital to acquire more control in your working life, you have become valuable enough to your employer that they will fight your efforts to gain more autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When no one cares what you do with your working life, you probably don’t have enough career capital to do anything interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key, it seems, is to know when the time is right to become courageous in your career decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should only pursue a bid for more control if you have evidence that it’s something that people are willing to pay you for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what people are willing to pay for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to decisions affecting your core career, money remains an effective judge of value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When deciding whether to follow an appealing pursuit that will introduce more control into your work life, seek evidence of whether people are willing to pay for it. If you find this evidence, continue. If not, move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A unifying mission to your working life can be a source of great satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have a mission is to have a unifying focus for your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Missions are powerful because they focus your energy toward a useful goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systematically experiment with different proto-missions to seek out a direction worth pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mission chosen before you have relevant career capital is not likely to be sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next big ideas in any field are found right beyond the current cutting edge, in the adjacent space that contains the possible new combinations of existing ideas.&lt;br /&gt;
We like to think of innovation as striking us in a stunning eureka moment, where you all at once change the way people see the world, leaping far ahead of our current understanding. I’m arguing that in reality, innovation is more systematic. We grind away to expand the cutting edge, opening up new problems in the adjacent possible to tackle and therefore expand the cutting edge some more, opening up more new problems, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good career mission is similar to a scientific breakthrough—it’s an innovation waiting to be discovered in the adjacent possible of your field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to identify a mission for your working life, therefore, you must first get to the cutting edge—the only place where these missions become visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First master a promising niche—a task that may take years—and only then turning her attention to seeking a mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people who love their work got where they are by first building up career capital and then cashing it in for the types of traits that define great work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a mission, you need to first acquire capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advancing to the cutting edge in a field is an act of “small” thinking, requiring you to focus on a narrow collection of subjects for a potentially long time. Once you get to the cutting edge, however, and discover a mission in the adjacent possible, you must go after it with zeal: a “big” action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great missions are transformed into great successes as the result of using small and achievable projects—little bets—to explore the concrete possibilities surrounding a compelling idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have a trusted strategy for making this leap from idea to execution, then like me and so many others, you’ll probably avoid the leap altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than believing they have to start with a big idea or plan out a whole project in advance, [successful people] make a methodical series of little bets about what might be a good direction, learning critical information from lots of little failures and from small but significant wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great missions are transformed into great successes as the result of finding projects that satisfy the law of remarkability, which requires that an idea inspires people to remark about it, and is launched in a venue where such remarking is made easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a mission-driven project to succeed, it should be remarkable in two different ways. First, it must compel people who encounter it to remark about it to others. Second, it must be launched in a venue that supports such remarking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other People&#39;s Money</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/opm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/opm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/opm.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent journalistic work about the biggest real estate deal ever made. If follows the saga of Stuyvesant Town, the largest residential project in New York City, from it&amp;rsquo;s humble beginnings as a middle class bastion in the late 1940s, to object of desire of financiers and speculators in the cusp of the real estate bubble of the early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goes deep into the details of the deal itself and the personalities and egoes of the people involved. You will find this book thoroughly enjoyable if you are into real estate investing or politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left Goldman Sachs</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/goldman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/goldman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/GoldmanSachs.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating insider story about the culture of one of Wall Street&amp;rsquo;s most iconic institutions, through the eyes of somebody who went through all the motions until he decided it was time to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some critics have dismissed Smith&amp;rsquo;s account as oportunistic or naive, but the bottom line is that it sheds a powerful light on some of Wall Street&amp;rsquo;s worse practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Required reading for those who seek to understand corporate politics and how it can advance or hinder a business career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Made To Stick</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/mts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/mts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/mts.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many good ideas don&amp;rsquo;t get the attention they deserve simply because they are communicated poorly. In Made To Stick the Heath brothers research and discover that all good ideas share some key similarities, and that they are successful by design rather than by accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book will teach you how to make people care, pay attention, remember, and act on your ideas. Next time you stumble upon a great  communicator, you&amp;rsquo;ll recognize that they are applying  some or all of the techniques discussed in this book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work The System</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/wts.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ground breaking book about the importance of implementing systems in your business and personal life. Well written, entertaining, rooted in a deeply personal story, the book deals not only with the why but also with the how of developing systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1zpyqRi&#34;&gt;Work The System&lt;/a&gt; when it was highly recommended by two respected business thinkers that I follow online: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joshkaufman.net&#34;&gt;Josh Kaufman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sebastianmarshall.com&#34;&gt;Sebastian Marshall&lt;/a&gt;.  Also, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been very busy lately and a deep understanding of systems, standardization and automation will bring more control, less stress, and more time for value-adding activities like thinking, strategizing, and keeping healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint, and left me with plenty of actionable steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hereby summarize the main tenets of the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The systems of the world work perfectly 99.9% of the time:&lt;/strong&gt; Everyday systems like air travel or electricity delivery almost never fail. We&amp;rsquo;ve become so used to it that we have come to expect it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Businesses are machines:&lt;/strong&gt; Like their mechanical counterparts, businesses have moving parts that operate in a linear 1-2-3 fashion. If a business sub-system is not working properly, we can isolate it, fix it and put everything back together, just like we would with a physical machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Large corporations operate with systems.  Small businesses improvise:&lt;/strong&gt; The reason multi-billion dollar companies grow and expand is the relentless implementation of systems. For small business owners, though, systems implementation is low in the scale of priorities. Those who are able to take the leap and embrace systems thinking will be orders of magnitude more successful than those who don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are all project engineers. Our job is to create, fix and maintain systems:&lt;/strong&gt; This may come as a paradigm shift for most of us. By rethinking the way we work and redefining our role to project engineer (designing and repairing systems for a living) our productivity (and our sanity, I may add) will improve exponentially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;98% perfection:&lt;/strong&gt;  Borrowed from Pareto&amp;rsquo;s 80-20 rule, the author convincingly argues that 98% good is as well as perfect, since the remaining 2% would take too much time and effort for the benefit it would bring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Errors of omission:&lt;/strong&gt; Failures are not usually the consequence of overt mistakes but simply that somebody neglected or forgot something.  This is perhaps one of the most powerful arguments in favor of systems: if a process is thoroughly documented and followed, the chances of things going wrong will decrease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiet Courage:&lt;/strong&gt; Taking a cue from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stevenpressfield.com/&#34;&gt;Steven Pressfield&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s books, the author urges us to beat the resistance by sticking to the plan no matter what, even when we don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it.  He calls this quality &amp;ldquo;quiet courage&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Point of Sale Thinking:&lt;/strong&gt; An analogy to describe the  habit of doing things at once, by either doing them ourselves or delegating them. As in POS systems, where different business sub-systems are updated instantly the moment a sale is recorded, our habit of doing things at once will make a positive difference on our business in the long run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Singles and Doubles. Not Home Runs:&lt;/strong&gt; Superb results are not the consequence of genius or bursts of inspiration, but of small, deliberate and consistent incremental improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these concepts lead us to the most important part of the book: the introduction of the three essential documents. They are: the &lt;strong&gt;Strategic Objective&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Operating Principles&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Operating Procedures&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last of these three life changing tools, the Operating Procedures, are what make the day to day of a business go flawlessly. They&amp;rsquo;re the detailed written instructions on how the different tasks and activities are to be performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Strategic Objective states what you aim for (your vision and long term goals), while the Operating Principles serve as a guideline for decision making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help us internalize the concept, the author draws an interesting parallel between the three documents and the Declaration of Independence (the Strategic Objective), the Constitution (the Operating Principles) and the laws (the Operating Procedures).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes this book remarkable, aside from the usefulness of its content, is the deep personal connection between the author and the concepts he lays out. Sam Carpenter credits the systems mindset for rescuing him from near burnout and 80-hour workweeks, and leading him to a more relaxed, productive life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is also very well structured, half textbook/half biography, turning what would otherwise be a dry, tedious subject into an engaging read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rework</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/rework.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best business books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. The authors take every single piece of business conventional wisdom and shatters them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the books back cover says: ASAP is poison, underdo the competition, meetings are toxic, fire the workaholics, pick a fight, planning is guessing. All counterintuitive advice, but the authors will show you with facts that following it can lead to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some critics say that this book applies only to small businesses and start-ups, but I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in large companies almost all my life, and I find it&amp;rsquo;s tennets applicable no matter the size of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-highlights-and-notes:a3597fee00546c719f240d41842460c8&#34;&gt;My Highlights and Notes:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The real world isn&amp;rsquo;t a place, it&amp;rsquo;s an excuse. It&amp;rsquo;s a justification for not trying. It has nothing to do with you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Failure is not a prerequisite for success. Evolution doesn&amp;rsquo;t linger on past failures, it&amp;rsquo;s always building upon what worked. So should you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Writing a plan makes you feel in control of things you can&amp;rsquo;t actually control.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Working without a plan may seem scary. But blindly following a plan that has no relationship with reality is even scarier.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with finding the right size and staying there? Small is not just a stepping-stone. Small is a great destination. Anyone who runs a business that&amp;rsquo;s sustainable and profitable, whether it&amp;rsquo;s big or small, should be proud.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Workaholics] try to make up for intellectual laziness with brute force.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If all you do is work, you&amp;rsquo;re unlikely to have sound judgments.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your efforts need to feel valuable. You want your customers to say, &amp;ldquo;This makes my life better.&amp;rdquo; You want to feel that if you stopped doing what you do, people would notice. You should feel an urgency about this too. You don&amp;rsquo;t have forever. This is your life&amp;rsquo;s work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re going to do something, do something that matters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The easiest, most straightforward way to create a great product or service is to &lt;mark&gt;make something you want to use&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Best of all, this &amp;ldquo;solve your own problem&amp;rdquo; approach lets you fall in love with what you&amp;rsquo;re making.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What you do is what matters, not what you think or say or plan.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you&amp;rsquo;re new at something, you need to start creating. The most important thing is to begin.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;When you want something bad enough, you make the time regardless of your other obligations&lt;/mark&gt;. The truth is most people just don&amp;rsquo;t want it bad enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The perfect time never arrives. You&amp;rsquo;re always too young or old or busy or broke or something else. If you constantly fret about timing things perfectly, they&amp;rsquo;ll never happen.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Keep in mind why you&amp;rsquo;re doing what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. &lt;mark&gt;Great businesses have a point of view, not just a product or service&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you believe, everything becomes an argument. Everything is debatable. But &lt;mark&gt;when you stand for something, decisions are obvious&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a world of difference between truly standing for something and having a mission statement that says you stand for something. Standing for something isn&amp;rsquo;t just about writing it down. It&amp;rsquo;s about believing it and living it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No matter what kind of business you&amp;rsquo;re starting, take on as little outside cash as you can.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go the bigger, more expensive route, but not right now. Great companies start in garages all the time. Yours can too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The truth is every business, new or old, is governed by the same set of market forces and economic rules. Revenue in, expenses out. Turn a profit or wind up gone.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A business without a path to profit isn&amp;rsquo;t a business, it&amp;rsquo;s a hobby.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need a commitment strategy, not an exit strategy. You should be thinking about how to make your project grow and succeed, not how you&amp;rsquo;re going to jump ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embrace the idea of having less mass. Right now, you&amp;rsquo;re the smallest, the leanest, and the fastest you&amp;rsquo;ll ever be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough time/money/people/experience.&amp;rdquo; Stop whining. Less is a good thing. Constraints are advantages in disguise. Limited resources force you to make do with what you&amp;rsquo;ve got. There&amp;rsquo;s no room for waste. And that forces you to be creative.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re better off with a kick-ass half than a half-assed whole. Lots of things get better as they get shorter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Getting to great starts by cutting out stuff that&amp;rsquo;s merely good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So figure out your epicenter. Which part of your equation can&amp;rsquo;t be removed? If you can continue to get by without this thing or that thing, then those things aren&amp;rsquo;t the epicenter. When you find it, you&amp;rsquo;ll know. Then focus all your energy on making it the best it can be. Everything else you do depends on that foundation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ignore the details for a while. Nail the basics first and worry about the specifics later.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;henever you can, &lt;mark&gt;swap &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s think about it&amp;rdquo; for &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s decide on it.&lt;/mark&gt;&amp;rdquo; Commit to making decisions. Don&amp;rsquo;t wait for the perfect solution. Decide and move forward.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Decisions are progress. Each one you make is a brick in your foundation. You can&amp;rsquo;t build on top of &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll decide later,&amp;rdquo; but you can build on top of &amp;ldquo;Done.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Long projects zap morale. The longer it takes to develop, the less likely it is to launch.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the stuff you leave out that matters. So constantly look for things to remove, simplify, and streamline. Be a curator. Stick to what&amp;rsquo;s truly essential. Pare things down until you&amp;rsquo;re left with only the most important stuff. Then do it again.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When things aren&amp;rsquo;t working, the natural inclination is to throw more at the problem. More people, time, and money. All that ends up doing is making the problem bigger. The right way to go is the opposite direction: Cut back.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you start pushing back deadlines and increasing your budget, you&amp;rsquo;ll never stop.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The core of your business should be built around things that won&amp;rsquo;t change. Things that people are going to want today and ten years from now. Those are the things you should invest in.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You just don&amp;rsquo;t need the best gear in the world to be good. And you definitely don&amp;rsquo;t need it to get started. In business, too many people obsess over tools, software tricks, scaling issues, fancy office space, lavish furniture, and other frivolities instead of what really matters. And what really matters is how to actually get customers and make money.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you make something, you always make something else. You can&amp;rsquo;t make just one thing. Everything has a by-product. Observant and creative business minds spot these by-products and see opportunities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Think about it this way: If you had to launch your business in two weeks, what would you cut out? Funny how a question like that forces you to focus. You suddenly realize there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of stuff you don&amp;rsquo;t need. And what you do need seems obvious. Build the necessities now, worry about the luxuries later.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do everything you can to remove layers of abstraction.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sometimes abandoning what you&amp;rsquo;re working on is the right move, even if you&amp;rsquo;ve already put in a lot of effort. Don&amp;rsquo;t throw good time after bad work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Interruption is not collaboration, it&amp;rsquo;s just interruption. And when you&amp;rsquo;re interrupted, you&amp;rsquo;re not getting work done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Find a judo solution, one that delivers maximum efficiency with minimum effort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Problems can usually be solved with simple, mundane solutions. That means there&amp;rsquo;s no glamorous work. You don&amp;rsquo;t get to show off your amazing skills. You just build something that gets the job done and then move on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No one likes to be stuck on an endless project with no finish line in sight. To keep your momentum and motivation up, get in the habit of accomplishing small victories along the way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;The longer something takes, the less likely it is that you&amp;rsquo;re going to finish it&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Try to dedicate one day a week (or every two weeks) to small victories that generate enthusiasm. Small victories let you celebrate and release good news. And you want a steady stream of good news.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you already spent too much time on something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth it, walk away. You can&amp;rsquo;t get that time back. The worst thing you can do now is waste even more time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What distinguishes people who are ten times more effective than the norm is not that they work ten times as hard; it&amp;rsquo;s that they use their creativity to come up with solutions that require one-tenth of the effort.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Reality never sticks to best-case scenarios. Note: Hope for the best. Plan for the worst.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Estimates that stretch weeks, months, and years into the future are fantasies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The solution: Break the big thing into smaller things. The smaller it is, the easier it is to estimate. You&amp;rsquo;re probably still going to get it wrong, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be a lot less wrong than if you estimated a big project.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Long lists are guilt trips. The longer the list of unfinished items, the worse you feel about it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You have to understand why something works or why something is the way it is. When you just copy and paste, you miss that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How do you know if you&amp;rsquo;re copying someone? If someone else is doing the bulk of the work, you&amp;rsquo;re copying. Be influenced, but don&amp;rsquo;t steal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pour yourself into your product and everything around your product too: how you sell it, how you support it, how you explain it, and how you deliver it. &lt;mark&gt;Competitors can never copy the you in your product&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you think a competitor sucks, say so. When you do that, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that others who agree with you will rally to your side. Being the anti-______ is a great way to differentiate yourself and attract followers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do less than your competitors to beat them. Solve the simple problems and leave the hairy, difficult, nasty problems to the competition. Instead of one-upping, try one-downing. Instead of outdoing, try underdoing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t shy away from the fact that your product or service does less. Highlight it. Be proud of it. Sell it as aggressively as competitors sell their extensive feature lists.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to build &amp;ldquo;the iPod killer&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;the next Pokemon,&amp;rdquo; you&amp;rsquo;re already dead. You&amp;rsquo;re allowing the competition to set the parameters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start getting into the habit of saying no, even to many of your best ideas. Use the power of no to get your priorities straight. You rarely regret saying no. But you often wind up regretting saying yes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Making a few vocal customers happy isn&amp;rsquo;t worth it if it ruins the product for everyone else.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be a jerk about saying no, though. Just be honest. If you&amp;rsquo;re not willing to yield to a customer request, be polite and explain why. People are surprisingly understanding when you take the time to explain your point of view.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your goal is to make sure your product stays right for you. You&amp;rsquo;re the one who has to believe in it most. That way, you can say, &amp;ldquo;I think you&amp;rsquo;ll love it because I love it.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Scaring away new customers is worse than losing old customers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Companies need to be true to a type of customer more than a specific individual customer with changing needs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Have as many great ideas as you can. Get excited about them. Just don&amp;rsquo;t act in the heat of the moment. Write them down and park them for a few days. Then, evaluate their actual priority with a calm mind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Once you do get bigger and more popular, you&amp;rsquo;re inevitably going to take fewer risks. When you&amp;rsquo;re a success, the pressure to maintain predictability and consistency builds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Instead of trying to outspend, outsell, or outsponsor competitors, try to out-teach them. Teaching probably isn&amp;rsquo;t something your competitors are even thinking about.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Buying people&amp;rsquo;s attention with a magazine or online banner ad is one thing. Earning their loyalty by teaching them forms a whole different connection.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;People are curious about how things are made. It&amp;rsquo;s why they like factory tours or behind-the-scenes footage on DVDs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imperfections are real and people respond to real. It&amp;rsquo;s why we like real flowers that wilt, not perfect plastic ones that never change. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about how you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to sound and how you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to act. Show the world what you&amp;rsquo;re really like, warts and all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Call someone. Write a personal note. If you read a story about a similar company or product, contact the journalist who wrote it. Pitch her with some passion, some interest, some life. Do something meaningful. Be remarkable. Stand out. Be unforgettable. That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;ll get the best coverage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Accounting is a department. Marketing isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/mark&gt;. Marketing is something everyone in your company is doing 24/7/365.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Marketing isn&amp;rsquo;t just a few individual events. It&amp;rsquo;s the sum total of everything you do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never hire anyone to do a job until you&amp;rsquo;ve tried to do it yourself first. That way, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand the nature of the work. You&amp;rsquo;ll know what a job well done looks like. You&amp;rsquo;ll know how to write a realistic job description and which questions to ask in an interview.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t hire for pleasure; hire to kill pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The right time to hire is when there&amp;rsquo;s more work than you can handle for a sustained period of time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You want a specific candidate who cares specifically about your company, your products, your customers, and your job.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So how do you find these candidates? First step: Check the cover letter. In a cover letter, you get actual communication instead of a list of skills, verbs, and years of irrelevance.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Managers of one are people who come up with their own goals and execute them. They don&amp;rsquo;t need heavy direction. They don&amp;rsquo;t need daily check-ins. They do what a manager would do: set the tone, assign items, determine what needs to get done, etc., but they do it by themselves and for themselves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you are trying to decide among a few people to fill a position, hire the best writer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Clear writing is a sign of clear thinking&lt;/mark&gt;. Great writers know how to communicate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Writing is today&amp;rsquo;s currency for good ideas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When something goes wrong, someone is going to tell the story. You&amp;rsquo;ll be better off if it&amp;rsquo;s you. Own the story.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Getting back to people quickly is probably the most important thing you can do when it comes to customer service.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s never really a great way to say you&amp;rsquo;re sorry, but there are plenty of terrible ways. One of the worst ways is the non-apology apology, which sounds like an apology but doesn&amp;rsquo;t really accept any blame.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Keep in mind that you can&amp;rsquo;t apologize your way out of being an ass. Even the best apology won&amp;rsquo;t rescue you if you haven&amp;rsquo;t earned people&amp;rsquo;s trust.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t create a culture. It happens. This is why new companies don&amp;rsquo;t have a culture. &lt;mark&gt;Culture is the byproduct of consistent behavior&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cut the crap and you&amp;rsquo;ll find that people are waiting to do great work. They just need to be given the chance.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rockstar environments develop out of trust, autonomy, and responsibility.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When everything constantly needs approval, you create a culture of nonthinkers. You create a boss-versus-worker relationship that screams, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t trust you.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Policies are organizational scar tissue. They are codified overreactions to situations that are unlikely to happen again. They are collective punishment for the misdeeds of an individual. This is how bureaucracies are born.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who said writing needs to be formal? Who said you have to strip away your personality when putting words on paper? Forget rules. Communicate!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you&amp;rsquo;re writing, don&amp;rsquo;t think about all the people who may read your words. Think of one person. Then write for that one person.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;ASAP is inflationary. It devalues any request that doesn&amp;rsquo;t say ASAP. Before you know it, the only way to get anything done is by putting the ASAP sticker on it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Reserve your use of emergency language for true emergencies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We all have ideas. Ideas are immortal. They last forever. What doesn&amp;rsquo;t last forever is inspiration. Inspiration is like fresh fruit or milk: It has an expiration date. If you want to do something, you&amp;rsquo;ve got to do it now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Personal MBA</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/pmba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 17:47:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/pmba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/pmba.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outstanding. I was completely blown away by this book. It starts as a compelling case against spending a small fortune attending business school, and offering an alternative path: anybody can get a quality business education without mortgaging our lives by reading the right books and applying the concepts in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It then lays out a comprehensive overview of every single business fundamental, concept and function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To complement the book, the author has curated a list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://personalmba.com/best-business-books/&#34;&gt;99 must-read business books&lt;/a&gt; so the reader can delve deeper into the different business subjects. Make sure to check the book&amp;rsquo;s website, where you will find concise outlines of each of the chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikigai</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ikigai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 17:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/ikigai/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/ikigai.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Marshall is a bright, self-taught young strategist determined to leave his mark in the world. Drawing heavily from history and the careful study of classic and current business books, he offers insightful advice on strategy, productivity and business in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book was put together in a week (mostly from blog content) as a dare to an old-school publisher who had offered to publish it but had been dragging the project for months. As a result, some passages may sound repetitive and there are several grammatical and spelling errors, but don&amp;rsquo;t get fooled: there is gold on those pages if you just can see beyond the rough surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;highlights:898f2c2967af6916fd60f5a6d754f990&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Walk the center path with other people&amp;rsquo;s objectives.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want everyone who connects with me to be better off.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;90% of the people I draw up plans for, plans that would clearly work, don&amp;rsquo;t act on them. It&amp;rsquo;s like everyone fantasizes about &amp;lsquo;whatever&amp;rsquo; but once their fantasies start to become reality, they piss their pants and self-sabotage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;High quality paper is a super hack to come across as ultra-professional.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do a bunch of stuff that might work, and won&amp;rsquo;t hurt too bad if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Identify what makes people succeed at a massively high level. Do that. If that&amp;rsquo;s not working, go back to step and try again.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Listen to audiobooks and learning while doing other things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I must be neutral, study even successful people I don&amp;rsquo;t like. My mind should not become an echo chamber.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Greatness is not something you are, it&amp;rsquo;s something you do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Serve, build, inspire, connect, defend, protect, establish, write, experiment, teach, help&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start building skills, resources, experiences, and mobility.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Read the sequences on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lesswrong.com&#34;&gt;LessWrong&lt;/a&gt;, click sequences, read almost all of them. These will teach you how to think better.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Go to Wikipedia once a week, and put in a historical leader or era of history, and start reading.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s possible unless you study history.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re taking general university courses, take accounting. It&amp;rsquo;s really useful, but it&amp;rsquo;s too boring to self-study.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start learning general social skills. I recommend you read How to Win Friends and Influence People, but don&amp;rsquo;t read it cover to cover. Instead, read one chapter per week, and then practice the ideas from it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Learn how to negotiate. Read books on negotiation. I think Critical Conversations is probably the best one to start with.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never, ever, ever get into debt. Just don&amp;rsquo;t do it. If you have debt (student loans, credit cars, etc), pay them off as soon as you have any cash at all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Debt cripples a man&amp;rsquo;s ability to do what he wants with his life&lt;/mark&gt;. Stay away from it at all costs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Train yourself to do arithmetic fast. There&amp;rsquo;s more value in being able to add, subtract, divide, and do percents fast than in any other kind of math.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start filling up your dead time. Bring a book or audio with you when you&amp;rsquo;re running errands, commuting, things like that. Life is precious, either explicitly relax, or do something valuable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This one is big, start listening to audio if you don&amp;rsquo;t.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start building skills, credentials, money, contacts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So, what are your larger roles? It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to pick. It&amp;rsquo;s not like a minute exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s something you go to a cafe with a notebook and pen and sit there staring at the page with a coffee, thinking for an hour. Even one hour isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. You do the think-with-coffee thing dozens of times, hundreds of times if you need to, trying to discover what matters to you, what you can dedicate yourself to, what&amp;rsquo;s important, what works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s many ways to live a good and meaningful life, but I think one of the most important steps is to think on what a good and meaningful life would be to you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If/when you do know what matters most to you, then the rest of the points are just cost/benefit, expected value, planning, forecasting, things like that&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a world where marketing and advertising exists, you need to do it because that&amp;rsquo;s the equilibrium. If you fight against equilibriums, you lose.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;High happinesses: triumph, camaraderie, epiphany, wisdom. Those I think are worth pursuing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Depending on how much you&amp;rsquo;ve traveled and studied different eras of history, you probably have lots of views about &amp;ldquo;the way things are&amp;rdquo; that isn&amp;rsquo;t actually the way things are. Just your culture at this particular moment in history.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While you&amp;rsquo;re learning, start building. Eventually you&amp;rsquo;re going to find causes that matter to you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I chase meaning, the happiness and fun largely takes care of itself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Distribution and marketing are of core importance to business.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When someone eats, sleeps, breathes, walks, works, lives with one purpose, he will usually achieve that purpose.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Be grateful to the scientists and engineers and inventors and builders and artists that came before us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By doing an action repeatedly, eventually you become the kind of person who does that action. If you repeatedly ask, &amp;ldquo;What can I do to come across as helpful?&amp;rdquo; and execute on that, then you become a helpful person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Spread the good around, it&amp;rsquo;ll catch up with you sooner or later.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s virtuous and appropriate to build wealth and become powerful. Expect to be treated well. Be friendly, giving, and helpful and don&amp;rsquo;t expect anything in return. Yet, when you&amp;rsquo;ve got something of value, offer good deals and get compensated. Don&amp;rsquo;t define yourself by money and possessions. There&amp;rsquo;s an unlimited amount of wealth and power available, you can gain it by building, inventing, innovating, cooperating, trading, and doing other virtuous things. Don&amp;rsquo;t be stingy and scramble for the last penny, leave something on the table. But don&amp;rsquo;t be too shy either, build and receive a lot in return.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t define yourself by money and possessions. There&amp;rsquo;s an unlimited amount of wealth and power available, you can gain it by building, inventing, innovating, cooperating, trading, and doing other virtuous things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Expect to be treated well, and act accordingly. Have a calm expectancy that people will agree to do things your way. Don&amp;rsquo;t argue or get upset, but do calmly insist that things be done correctly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sell some things you produce, sell some of your skills, get paid. It&amp;rsquo;s cool to ask people for money as long as you know you can deliver x the value of what you&amp;rsquo;re being paid.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The victors: the ones who build the really enduring victories, they&amp;rsquo;re often not the most brilliant or charismatic or brave. They&amp;rsquo;re the ones who are most patient, who are most rational, who have the most self-control.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are seven emotions: joy, anger, anxiety, love, grief, fear, and hate, and if a man does not give way to these he can be called patient.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m scared sometimes of giving way to being joyful. It is a good thing to feel joyful, but not to let joy dull your edge.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Of the common virtues, the successful seem to have an immense amount of loyalty and reverence for the people that &amp;ldquo;got them there,&amp;rdquo; revering and celebrating them even as they bring more and more people to their banner. The people who break from their early friends and supporters usually end poorly, in an isolation of their own making.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The people who break from their early friends and supporters usually end poorly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By taking great care of the people who elevated you from the beginning, you build a stronger foundation that&amp;rsquo;s worthy of respect.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Two kinds of ways trade and interact and cooperate. The first way would be through &amp;ldquo;market norms&amp;rdquo;, this is where two people clearly agree to make an exchange, and deliver what they agreed to exchange, and the deal is concluded. The second way is through &amp;ldquo;social norms&amp;rdquo;, where you&amp;rsquo;re looking out for each other&amp;rsquo;s best interests.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Derek Sivers wrote a review of Predictably Irrational (&lt;a href=&#34;http://sivers.org/book/PredictablyIrrational&#34;&gt;http://sivers.org/book/PredictablyIrrational&lt;/a&gt;) that I highly recommend.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Market norms push out social norms. But I&amp;rsquo;ve started to wonder if this can be avoided by always leaving something on the table. This means getting away from haggling, grinding up/down to the absolute final price someone would pay, and hard selling. For my work, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be aiming to generate a x return on investment over the the next three years. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s %. I think that&amp;rsquo;s the first part, looking out for their interests and not grinding.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Good negotiation is about figuring out what you can offer that&amp;rsquo;s worth more to the other person than you, and what they can offer that&amp;rsquo;s worth more to you than them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re selling, the deal or product you offer should seem like a fantastically good value, like your service existing is a favor to the person doing business with you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you want to stay away from exchange-based feelings, be very enjoyable to work with. Figure out what your client or provider&amp;rsquo;s highest-level goals are, and help them get it. Pay well if you&amp;rsquo;re buying, over-deliver to a ridiculous extent so it&amp;rsquo;s clear you&amp;rsquo;re above and beyond the call if you&amp;rsquo;re selling. And make it enjoyable, really enjoyable, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You need to make everyone look good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Make people look good to the people they really care about.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Looking out for people outside of the scope of the deal can help make it about more than just the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I never liked spending money on comfort or luxury that doesn&amp;rsquo;t serve a higher purpose. I eat very simply, I sleep simply, I don&amp;rsquo;t need or want much.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to sacrifice and suffer and martyr myself when I help people. I ask for feedback.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Make connecting with people part of my entertainment time. You know, when most people are watching TV, I&amp;rsquo;m reading email, writing email, hopping on the phone with people, answering questions, helping other people do strategy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I added a note to my daily checklist for a while, &amp;ldquo;Reach out to someone&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Make connecting with people part of your entertainment time&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start by sending out short (the shorter the better) emails to people who you see saying or doing something cool. Even if they don&amp;rsquo;t write back, I guarantee they appreciate it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Embarrassment and errors are part of doing meaningful things. It&amp;rsquo;s not such a big deal, really.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Embarrassment? Dude, eternity stretches before and after us. Embarrassment is your neurochemistry in a mildly uncomfortable position. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter at all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Good Marketing Is Mostly Just Having People Want to Spend Time With You.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When someone spends their time with me, whatever the medium, that&amp;rsquo;s a tremendous honor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Good marketing goes, &amp;ldquo;This person could be anywhere else, let&amp;rsquo;s make it worth their while.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The rest of good marketing is offering people something worth many, many times more than what you&amp;rsquo;re charging.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tell people what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and let them decide if it&amp;rsquo;s right for them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;The first step to being a great marketer is respecting your own time&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The quintessential, alpha-omega principle of strategy, which is - Do things for reasons.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do not simply &amp;ldquo;do shit&amp;rdquo; for no reason.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The way to start doing that is to ask, &amp;ldquo;What is my objective here?&amp;rdquo; Then, &amp;ldquo;What course of action makes me most likely to reach that objective?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ask, &amp;ldquo;What is my objective here? What gives me the best chance of reaching it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe the biggest problem really intelligent people have is that they spend more time being clever than being effective.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Take a quick look, get an understanding, choose one. Change later if it becomes an issue.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Using words people don&amp;rsquo;t know maybe makes you seem clever, but makes you much less clear and less effective.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Proving someone wrong? Yeah, clever. Very ineffective, though.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Winning by a huge margin can make people stupid.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After victory, tighten the straps on your helmet.&amp;rdquo; Tokugawa Ieyasu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re writing a piece, you have to make sure the title, introduction, images, and formatting all fit the expectations and heuristics of the people who you care about.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People will skim your work. You need to take that into account, and make good transitions, sub-headlines, intelligently use bolding and links, and otherwise make sure the people of your target audience get the message. If they don&amp;rsquo;t get it, that means YOU didn&amp;rsquo;t get it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Keep learning marketing and buyer&amp;rsquo;s psychology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never ever ever ever say, &amp;ldquo;They don&amp;rsquo;t get it&amp;rdquo; if you care about the person who just made that decision. No, you don&amp;rsquo;t get it. You did it wrong. Learn. Figure out where the decision/reaction came from, and do it better next time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Most people don&amp;rsquo;t distinguish between observing and judging.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Strip your observations down to cause and effect. &amp;ldquo;X seems to have happened, what caused it? Perhaps Y, perhaps Z. Let&amp;rsquo;s observe some more.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(a) Ask ourselves what we&amp;rsquo;re trying to achieve;  (b) Ask ourselves how we could tell if we achieved it (&amp;ldquo;what does it look like to be a good comedian?&amp;rdquo;) and how we can track progress;  &amp;copy; Find ourselves strongly, intrinsically curious about information that would help us achieve our goal;  (d) Gather that information (e.g., by asking as how folks commonly achieve our goal, or similar goals, or by tallying which strategies have and haven&amp;rsquo;t worked for us in the past);  (e) Systematically test many different conjectures for how to achieve the goals, including methods that aren&amp;rsquo;t habitual for us, while tracking which ones do and don&amp;rsquo;t work;  (f) Focus most of the energy that &lt;em&gt;isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; going into systematic exploration, on the methods that work best; (g) Make sure that our &amp;ldquo;goal&amp;rdquo; is really our goal, that we coherently want it and are not constrained by fears or by uncertainty as to whether it is worth the effort, and that we have thought through any questions and decisions in advance so they won&amp;rsquo;t continually sap our energies; (h) Use environmental cues and social contexts to bolster our motivation, so we can keep working effectively in the face of intermittent frustrations, or temptations based in hyperbolic discounting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If you choose to make one thing your goal, then you&amp;rsquo;re choosing not to make something else your goal&lt;/mark&gt;. You have to prioritize, or you&amp;rsquo;ll be stuck serving multiple masters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You might need natural talent to win at a zero-sum game, or if you&amp;rsquo;re competing for limited pieces of pie. But you don&amp;rsquo;t need natural talent for positive sum games. Positive sum games make multiple winners and expand the pie more than what the person eats.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Constantly improve fundamentals Look for synergies in other fields Regularly complete attempts to do significant work (and ideally ship them). Just cross-reference two important disciplines that haven&amp;rsquo;t talked to each other enough yet, BAM, genius-quality work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d rank effectiveness, desire, and consistency/persistence all higher than intelligence for tangible success.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got to be working on your long term objectives almost daily, or at least weekly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you want to have a successful life, expose yourself to as much high-upside low-downside probability as you can.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Read books, reach out to people, try to get projects working, keep trying to write and build things, keep learning new skills, keep treating people well.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Want to write a great book? Free yourself to write a bad book first.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Something that is not done at that time at that place will remain unfinished for a lifetime.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Once you do start doing lots of interesting and engaging things, then it becomes a lot easier to meet and connect with people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll have mentors, colleagues, collaborators, people who want to hire you after you produce some good stuff, not before.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Spend time in nature, exercise, do some breathing, listen to good classical music or rock music, eat healthy, get enough sleep, take vitamins, maybe do some martial arts or yoga or something.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you hear someone speak at a conference, or tell you about their favorite project, or serve a beautiful dish in front of you, you&amp;rsquo;re seeing them at their peak. A lot of success sucks. You see the sprezzatura. You see the concert, not the setting up of the stage. Not the practicing until your hands hurt. Not the cleanup of the filthy area afterwards. Not the time touring in little nightclubs where nobody is actually watching you play, and nobody cares, and you&amp;rsquo;re kind of low and tired and strung out but gotta go play to a crowd of nine people anyways and make it good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The light easy breezy passion is kind of an illusion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The difference between a generalist and a dabbler is just saying &amp;ldquo;this is as done as it&amp;rsquo;s going to be&amp;rdquo; and shipping.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The dabbler moves on when things get tough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By shipping, you have a chance to win. If you don&amp;rsquo;t ship, you don&amp;rsquo;t win. You don&amp;rsquo;t even lose. You don&amp;rsquo;t get the lessons, the feedback, or connect with other people in the field. You don&amp;rsquo;t get the satisfaction and boost that comes from shipping.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People expect their passion to hit them in the head someday, then they&amp;rsquo;ll &amp;ldquo;get it&amp;rdquo;, and then they&amp;rsquo;re driven and motivated and ready to go.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is how you discover passions: Take a crack at it once and see if you like it at all. Then start studying and improving your craft, and see if you like that too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So that&amp;rsquo;s the first thing, I think, about passion: it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from sitting and thinking about it, it comes from diving in and getting dirty.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Passions are probably even harder to guess from just reading a book to know that you enjoy it, you do need to jump in, try some stuff, ship some stuff, and see what happens.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Produce and ship stuff. Even tiny tiny things. If you get into a new kind of music, write up your thoughts and first impressions on it either on a blog, or even just Amazon reviews. The mindset shift from being a consumer to being a producer is huge, even if what you produce doesn&amp;rsquo;t see all that much use at first.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you have a sincere interest, then why not try to write an analysis or critique or user guide or quick-start manual or observations or something? Producing, shipping, it&amp;rsquo;s cool.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not that getting your package  days from now instead of makes such a big difference in all cases. Much of the time, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But when it matters, it really matters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cognitive cost: if the man is thinking about the fence, he&amp;rsquo;s not thinking about something else.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If you want to make excellent stuff, you need to make a lot of crap&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In order to do high impact excellent work, you have to do a lot of work, which includes low impact not excellent work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I commit to doing it every day, every single day no matter what.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My audience is whoever likes it, the site is written for me. If someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t like it at this point in their life, they&amp;rsquo;re not my audience for now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you have a good idea, write it down. I have a &amp;ldquo;shorttermblog.txt&amp;rdquo; on the desktop of my laptop.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Every single day, write something. Even something small.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start noticing what people like, and tweaking your works.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tone is hard to get, but it comes with time. Every single day is the way. Something, even just a quote. You&amp;rsquo;ll find the theme later.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Quantity Always Trumps Quality&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no real risk to trying a high upside no downside endeavor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why don&amp;rsquo;t I make a habit of writing letters to people I respect and do it all the time?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Put up a basic webpage offering some sort of consulting at some bargain rate with an explanation of why it&amp;rsquo;s so cheap and then go hustle to get that work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shifting your time from watching random TV to trying to do something creative is almost a guaranteed win.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I could give you some tactical guidelines on this question: how do you become a faster decision maker? But that&amp;rsquo;s probably not the real question we&amp;rsquo;re grappling with. Is that the real question though? Make sure the underlying issue is not that you are afraid of failing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Define &amp;ldquo;adequately complete&amp;rdquo;&lt;/mark&gt;, then ask, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the fastest way to adequately complete?&amp;rdquo; Then do that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Slightly better&amp;rdquo; often takes twice as long, for very little gain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Consult, advise, or work for other people. It&amp;rsquo;s damn near impossible to evaluate your own projects correctly you get emotionally attached, you get stupid, you get blindsided. This still happens to me. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably do consulting forever, just so I&amp;rsquo;m working with other people and can be more clear-headed than when I&amp;rsquo;m doing my own thing. Whenever you give great advice to someone else about how much time to put into something or their decision making choices, write a note in your journal or diary and refer to it later when making the same decision.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve just got to become comfortable with failing more often.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start the day with 20 minutes planning the day and working for an hour on his most important thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To take better actions, you need to gradually establish better habits.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Environment matters. A lot. You can get pretty big pushes from moving your environment around to suit your goals and life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Go up to tons of people, a potential lover, a boss, a cashier, a traveler, a tourist, a friend you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen for years, etc. and accept any outcome. When you let go of your ego (wants, desires, your self identity, etc.) and accept the situation for what it is, then you&amp;rsquo;re able to take as many chances as you&amp;rsquo;d like.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Learn small talk, learn charm, learn confidence. The only way to learn those is by exposure!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I set goals every week. I aim for a 70% success rate. That means I fall short on 30% of my goals every week. I figure, if I succeeded at 100% my goals weren&amp;rsquo;t set high enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Something going wrong is an expensive lesson I already paid for. Might as well take it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of good time for details. But there&amp;rsquo;s one bad time: that&amp;rsquo;s when you&amp;rsquo;re paying attention to details instead of taking the big actions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Narrow it down to the bare minimum you need to do to get started. Do that&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Action first. Then details.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you decide to make a big change in your life, like starting a daily life tracking routine, your best chance of success is to start with a small change and slowly expand it into something bigger. If you disrupt the status quo too much too quickly, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t stick with it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After you&amp;rsquo;ve met your goal for a specific area, continue tracking it for a few weeks until you&amp;rsquo;re confident that you&amp;rsquo;ve made it a long term habit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you&amp;rsquo;re having a highly creative day, run it out as much as you can. Resist the temptation to say, &amp;ldquo;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s enough&amp;rdquo; and just go chill out or whatever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Normal life during normal times. &lt;mark&gt;Milk the cow as much as possible when things are unusually great. Fundamentals and trying to avoid being stupid when things are bad&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Trying to improve 30 things at once is a great formula for falling off a cliff and getting nothing done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Useful skills: Writing, negotiating, speaking, conflict resolution, do basic arithmetic fast, probability and statistics, project management.&lt;br /&gt;
Work hard on tangible stuff, document and claim credit for doing it, and notify people with what benefit the work provides.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prepare a BATNA (Best Alternative to Negotiated Agreement). If they say no, what will you do? You need to know this.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t work with idiots. You can&amp;rsquo;t appeal to their interest, because they&amp;rsquo;re too stupid to have interests.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everything is worth what its purchaser will pay for it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that kissing the ass of someone you don&amp;rsquo;t like and blindly hoping things are going to get better will result in a good life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Correspond with 100 new people per month, help them out at no cost, while simultaneously keeping up correspondence with 20 to 50 &amp;ldquo;core people&amp;rdquo; in my life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My entertainment is reading, writing, and connecting with smart people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pitch Anything&amp;rdquo; by Oren Klaff, &amp;ldquo;Winning Through Intimidation&amp;rdquo; by Robert Ringer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Think Big and Kick Ass in Business and Life&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;High variance strategy will produce huge wins or spectacular failures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thinking strategically. Very few people do this. This is saying, &amp;ldquo;What am I trying to accomplish?&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;What should I do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do I stand for?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone will value my time extremely highly, treat me very well, I&amp;rsquo;ll deliver the highest level of service and ability that I can to them, they&amp;rsquo;ll honor that and use it immediately, I&amp;rsquo;ll be treated with extreme respect and gratitude, I&amp;rsquo;ll be extremely grateful too, we&amp;rsquo;ll buy gifts for each other, I won&amp;rsquo;t accept any pay from someone that they don&amp;rsquo;t willingly excitedly give.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;Any simple deal can be written in one page&lt;/mark&gt;. If it&amp;rsquo;s under $100K, on a one-off job and there&amp;rsquo;s no regulations in play, then there&amp;rsquo;s no excuse for a bazillion pages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, I don&amp;rsquo;t understand contracts. I only sign one page contracts that are very simple.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not Thinking &amp;lt; Tactics &amp;lt; Strategy &amp;lt; Philosophy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Repeatedly stress that they&amp;rsquo;re making an investment into a durable and long-lasting asset. Costs get cut, assets get invested in.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Use some multiplication and bullshit charts. Whoever is paying you needs to justify it. Make some charts and graphs about how an expensive logo correlates with making a lot of money or high share price.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The haggling doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if we&amp;rsquo;ll never see each other again. But if we&amp;rsquo;re going to interact more? Then haggling is a no-go: it destroys goodwill, since it makes things transactional.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do everything you can to &lt;mark&gt;stay relational/social instead of market/transactional&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Be a trusted advisor. Over deliver on work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Transactional relationships are about paying as little as you can for as much as you can get. Social relationships are about giving as much as you can and far exceeding what you get.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You need to make people feel pain when they don&amp;rsquo;t pay you on time, or otherwise break their word.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Write things down. Take them out and show them. People are funny about remembering what&amp;rsquo;s most convenient for them. Paper doesn&amp;rsquo;t lie.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lay down a set of principles about what your time, your art, and your life are worth, and to explain them in advance.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Regularly update with the work you completed, and the benefit it provides. 2.) Decide what you want, and what you&amp;rsquo;ll do as Plan B if your current company won&amp;rsquo;t give it to you. 3.) Go stress that you&amp;rsquo;d be able to produce more value if you transition your role to a more highly paid and enjoyable one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t ask for money periodically, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to be underpaid&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s crucial to give whoever is paying you &amp;ldquo;the warm fuzzy feeling.&amp;rdquo; Part of that is letting them know what you&amp;rsquo;re working on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing work your boss doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand, how does he know how well you&amp;rsquo;re producing? Answer: He doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Unless you tell him. The person who describes what they&amp;rsquo;re doing and why it matters regularly will seem much, much more productive than the person who doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Every savvy businessperson loves revenues and hates costs. If you&amp;rsquo;re a cost, they want to reduce your work. If you&amp;rsquo;re bringing in revenues, they want to expand your work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t just stress benefits to the company, also show how you&amp;rsquo;re making the people you work with look good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You really want to be a profit center rather than a cost center. Profit centers get expanded. Cost centers get cut.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You need to know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to do if this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. BATNA, a backup plan, removes desperation. It also gives you a benchmark for how good an offer is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re always responsible for finance in any business you own, always, no matter what.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;mark&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a &amp;lsquo;what have you done for me lately&amp;rsquo; kind of world. It&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;lsquo;what are you going to do for me going forwards&amp;rsquo; kind of world&lt;/mark&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t expect loyalty or pay or compensation for things you did in the past. You get loyalty and pay and compensation for things you&amp;rsquo;re going to do going forwards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t mention what you&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past. People hate that. It makes people feel guilty and makes you sound entitled.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>