<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Mario Sanchez Carrion</title>
    <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Mario Sanchez Carrion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mariosanchez.org/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Other People&#39;s Money: Inside the Housing Crisis and the Demise of the Greatest Real Estate Deal Ever Made</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/opm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/opm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/opm.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent journalistic work about the biggest real estate deal ever made. If follows the saga of Stuyvesant Town, the largest residential project in New York City, from it&amp;rsquo;s humble beginnings as a middle class bastion in the late 1940s, to object of desire of financiers and speculators in the cusp of the real estate bubble of the early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goes deep into the details of the deal itself and the personalities and egoes of the people involved. You will find this book thoroughly enjoyable if you are into real estate investing or politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1lUYIpL&#34;&gt;Amazon Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Left Goldman Sachs</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/goldman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/goldman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/GoldmanSachs.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating insider story about the culture of one of Wall Street&amp;rsquo;s most iconic institutions, through the eyes of somebody who went through all the motions until he decided it was time to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some critics have dismissed Smith&amp;rsquo;s account as oportunistic or naive, but the bottom line is that it sheds a powerful light on some of Wall Street&amp;rsquo;s worse practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Required reading for those who seek to understand corporate politics and how it can advance or hinder a business career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Made To Stick</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/mts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/mts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/mts.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many good ideas don&amp;rsquo;t get the attention they deserve simply because they are communicated poorly. In Made To Stick the Heath brothers research and discover that all good ideas share some key similarities, and that they are successful by design rather than by accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book will teach you how to make people care, pay attention, remember, and act on your ideas. Next time you stumble upon a great  communicator, you&amp;rsquo;ll recognize that they are applying  some or all of the techniques discussed in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Chip and Dan Heath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/22gNCMi&#34;&gt;Amazon Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://heathbrothers.com/books/made-to-stick/&#34;&gt;Official Book Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rework</title>
      <link>http://www.mariosanchez.org/rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mariosanchez.org/rework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mariosanchez.org/images/rework.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best business books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. The authors take every single piece of business conventional wisdom and shatters them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the books back cover says: ASAP is poison, underdo the competition, meetings are toxic, fire the workaholics, pick a fight, planning is guessing. All counterintuitive advice, but the authors will show you with facts that following it can lead to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some critics say that this book applies only to small businesses and start-ups, but I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in large companies almost all my life, and I find it&amp;rsquo;s tennets applicable no matter the size of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OfzO06&#34;&gt;Amazon Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://37signals.com/rework/&#34;&gt;Official Book Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>